<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Utilities on tenbulls blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/utilities/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Utilities on tenbulls blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © {year} Mark Broadbent</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 20:07:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/utilities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Add metadata to your audio files</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/06/09/add-meta-to-your-audio-training-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 20:07:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/06/09/add-meta-to-your-audio-training-files/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my recent post &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/06/07/how-to-rip-audio-from-your-training-videos.md&#34;&gt;How to rip audio from your training videos&lt;/a&gt; I gave Linux a very big thumbs up for providing users with a very easy (free and fast) route to rip audio from our SQL Server training videos. Now as much as I like Linux, it is not the answer to every single problem. In fact it is undeniable that Microsoft has established Windows as a platform of choice for many very polished and useful third party applications -free or otherwise. Sometimes finding open source equivalents on Linux can be a real pain in the posterior since the reality is that every now and again the best application is a Windows application (take SQL Server as an example 🙂) and the application I will demonstrate today is exactly that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to rip audio from your training videos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/06/07/how-to-rip-audio-from-your-training-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 20:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/06/07/how-to-rip-audio-from-your-training-videos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; Although the following post is Linux related my dear SQL Server geek, you might just find what I am about to say useful in your pursuit of SQL Server greatness. If this possibility doesn’t interest you then I advise to stop reading right&amp;hellip; now!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don’t normally publish short blog posts and as a result, when I am really busy, it means nothing gets posted due to the large amount of time the bigger articles take. However from time to time I see something that I really want to shout about and this is one of those times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
