<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Installation on tenbulls blog</title>
    <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/installation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Installation on tenbulls blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © {year} Mark Broadbent</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 19:27:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/installation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Installing Docker on Linux Mint</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2018/02/installing-docker-on-linux-mint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 19:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2018/02/installing-docker-on-linux-mint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2018/docker-mint.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Mint&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ok, so first things first. This is not a ground shaking post of revelation, and ultimately all the information you need can be found directly from Docker, but like all good posts this is intended to address any confusion or ambiguity you may find when installing Docker on Linux Mint and join all the dots for you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A web search will almost certainly point you to lots of similar posts, mostly (if not) all of which start instructing you to add unofficial or unrecognized sources, keys etc. Therefore my intention with this post is not to replace official documentation, but to make the process as simple as possible, whilst still pointing to all the official documentation so that you can be confident you are not breaking security or other such things!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Samba on Linux Mint (the easy way)</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/04/18/samba_on_mint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 10:32:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/04/18/samba_on_mint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2017/hamster_share.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Server Message Block (SMB) Protocol is a network file sharing protocol introduced by Microsoft and can be incredibly useful when moving files across multiplatform machines (particularly if your primary machine is a Windows desktop). Samba is a file and print sharing suite of utilities in Linux which uses and provides integration with other machines using the SMB transport.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-this-quick-guide-covers&#34;&gt;What this quick guide covers&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you only want to provide basic folder sharing capabilities from your Linux distribution of choice, configuration and setup of Samba is (in my humble opinion) over complicated at best and a little bit messy at worst.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resolving Windows Cluster creation problems in Powershell</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/04/03/problems-creating-windows-cluster-through-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 16:09:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/04/03/problems-creating-windows-cluster-through-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating a Windows Cluster is surprisingly easy, but every now and again you run into small problems which irritate and are not really helped by the error messages – a problem which is exacerbated by the do all in one go power of PowerShell.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One such problem is when you use the New-Cluster command to add all your nodes in one go.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34; data-lang=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;New-Cluster -Name magrathea -node server5,server6,server7&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;-staticaddress &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;192.168&lt;/span&gt;.1.70&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simple right? Well no. In this instance I ran into the following error:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.2 for YUM without a Redhat Subscription</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/10/11/rhelyum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 11:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/10/11/rhelyum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a very long time since I have installed a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redhat.com/en/resources/whats-new-red-hat-enterprise-linux-7&#34;&gt;Redhat Enterprise Linux&lt;/a&gt; distribution having tended to prefer Ubuntu based distributions (such as Linux Mint) or CentOS if I really wanted a Redhat derivative (although for Oracle Database installations on Linux, I would always tend to use Oracle Enterprise Linux for simplicity). With the development and impending arrival of SQL Server on Linux, I thought it was about time that I returned back to the playground with a vanilla copy of Redhat EL so that I could test it with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-gb/cloud-platform/sql-server-on-linux&#34;&gt;SQL Server&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com/&#34;&gt;Docker Linux Containers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://spark.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Spark&lt;/a&gt; and lots of other sexy things that have been avoiding my immediate attention for a little too long.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle Unbreakable Linux installation fails on Hyper-V Generation 2 Virtual Machine</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/10/16/oracle-unbreakable-linux-installation-fails-on-hyper-v-generation-2-virtual-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 14:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/10/16/oracle-unbreakable-linux-installation-fails-on-hyper-v-generation-2-virtual-machine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you been attempting (and failing) to install &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oracle.com/us/technologies/linux/overview/index.html&#34;&gt;Oracle Unbreakable Linux&lt;/a&gt; as a Virtual Machine under Hyper-V and cannot figure out what is wrong?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-problem&#34;&gt;The problem&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are receiving the following message:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34; data-lang=&#34;text&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Boot Failed. EFI SCSI Device.&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Boot Failed. EFI SCSI Device.&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Boot Failed. EFI SCSI Device. Failed Secure Boot Verification.&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;PXE Network Boot using IPv4&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;......&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;PXE-E18: Server response timeout.&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Boot Failed. EFI Network.&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;No Operating System was Loaded.&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Press a key to retry the boot sequence...&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2015/secure-boot-verification.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Secure Boot verification&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to install SharePoint 2013 on Windows 2012R2</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/03/30/how-to-install-sharepoint-2013-on-windows-2012r2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 07:52:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/03/30/how-to-install-sharepoint-2013-on-windows-2012r2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you want to jump straight to the condensed solution, then please feel free to go to the &lt;a href=&#34;#condensed-installation&#34;&gt;Condensed Installation instructions&lt;/a&gt; below. If you find this post useful or have any feedback then please leave me a comment so that I know my efforts were not wasted!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Installing Microsoft Backoffice products on Microsoft Operating Systems has over the years become a much easier proposition and is largely the reason why SQL Server got the reputation of being &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo;. Except it isn&amp;rsquo;t. Ask any idiot to install a SQL Server instance and create a database and there is a good chance that they will succeed, but ask them to install SQL Server correctly and configured to best practice, suddenly the knowledge gap becomes a little more obvious.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Flash in Chrome/ Chromium on Linux</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/01/06/flash-not-working-in-chrome-chromium/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 14:33:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/01/06/flash-not-working-in-chrome-chromium/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2015/parliament_not_working.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Flash not working&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Linux works it works well, and when it doesn&amp;rsquo;t it can be a real pain in the backside. Usually though, the failings are not necessarily the fault of the OS, but more the fault of the way in which packages, snap-ins, extensions and other third party code is deployed. Granted, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really help that there are numerous methods and &lt;em&gt;Package Managers&lt;/em&gt; available to install applications, codecs and their ilk, but often the fault lies partially with the Third-party vendors for not making the process as easy and transparent as possible (especially for the less technical savvy amongst us).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using the SQL Server Installation Wizard on Server Core!</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2012/09/19/using-the-sql-server-installation-wizard-on-server-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 18:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2012/09/19/using-the-sql-server-installation-wizard-on-server-core/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever heard the phrase &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;just because you can, doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you should?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. Yep me too -many times, and what I am about to say comes with that caveat in mind although as I shall explain, I see absolutely no reason why you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t -certainly not in a development environment OR using this technique to produce a configuration installation file. But I&amp;rsquo;m getting ahead of myself, first let me describe our scenario.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing the Citrix client on Linux</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2010/05/12/installing-citrix-client-on-linuxcertify-your-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 20:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2010/05/12/installing-citrix-client-on-linuxcertify-your-client/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first step of installing Citrix client on your Linux machine is to first obtain the package. From Citrix&amp;rsquo;s website download the tarball of the Citrix Receiver.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2010/citrix1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Citrix clients&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Extract the tarball&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2010/citrix2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Extract&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;and run the setupwfc executable. Select the first menu item to start the installer, and keep defaults. Once the installer has completed, exit the installer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2010/citrix3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Run setup&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once complete you should try launching a published Citrix Application. At this stage you will probably encounter a client error message &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;You have not chosen to trust &amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo;, the issuer of the server&amp;rsquo;s security certificate (SSL error 61).&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
