<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker on tenbulls blog</title>
    <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker on tenbulls blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © {year} Mark Broadbent</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 19:27:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Installing Docker on Linux Mint</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2018/02/installing-docker-on-linux-mint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 19:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2018/02/installing-docker-on-linux-mint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2018/docker-mint.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Docker Mint&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ok, so first things first. This is not a ground shaking post of revelation, and ultimately all the information you need can be found directly from Docker, but like all good posts this is intended to address any confusion or ambiguity you may find when installing Docker on Linux Mint and join all the dots for you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A web search will almost certainly point you to lots of similar posts, mostly (if not) all of which start instructing you to add unofficial or unrecognized sources, keys etc. Therefore my intention with this post is not to replace official documentation, but to make the process as simple as possible, whilst still pointing to all the official documentation so that you can be confident you are not breaking security or other such things!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Days of Dockercon – Day 4</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/10/19/4-days-of-dockercon-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 19:12:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/10/19/4-days-of-dockercon-day-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2017/entsummit.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Enterprise Summit&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After doing some more work in the evening for Microsoft and watching my Football match, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to sleep until midnight, so I woke with my usual conference groggy feeling. At my age, I really need more hours in bed! Thankfully I had done most of my packing the night before so didn&amp;rsquo;t have an awful lot to do. However given the fact that I had skipped dinner/ supper the night before I was determined to grab a big breakfast. I&amp;rsquo;d skipped my evening meal since I really couldn&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to wander down to the Shopping Mall and waste 40 minutes on a round trip in doing so, nor did I fancy a meal in the hotel restaurant wasting 2 hours of messing around.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Days of Dockercon – Day 3</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/10/19/4-days-of-dockercon-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 08:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/10/19/4-days-of-dockercon-day-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2017/handsonlabs.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hands on labs&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The second and final day of general sessions arrives and I manage to leave my room with a little more time to spare than yesterday. Again, I grab a bite to eat in the exhibitor room and then find myself a good seat for the keynote day 2. This time it was lead by Scott Johnson (COO of Docker) and focused again on Docker Enterprise Edition but with a strong focus on the MTA program and migrating legacy apps to Docker. The atmosphere was slightly more subdued today -probably because people were nursing hangovers from last nights party, but I was intrigued by a few things. For instance, when they talked about migrating a legacy .NET app and modernizing it to Docker, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t really clear to me whether doing so was also irradicating dependencies on older .NET frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Days of Dockercon – Day 2</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/10/17/4-days-of-dockercon-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 22:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/10/17/4-days-of-dockercon-day-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2017/keynote.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Keynote&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why is it that at every conference I always seem to be rushing around in the morning trying to get to the keynote sessions in time. No matter how early I wake, I always seem to run out of time. Today was the first main day of sessions and I was determined to grab a bite to eat before heading to the keynote, so I headed across to the sponsor hall and grabbed my required bacon supplement for the day and managed to have a very interesting chat with a Docker insider (who is apparently contributing to the keynote the next day – I&amp;rsquo;ll insert name if that is correct). We discussed the future of containers in a potentially Serverless world and it was really interesting (and reassuring) to note that Docker has their eyes and ears firmly planted in all the right places (can&amp;rsquo;t say any more right now!).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Days of Dockercon – Day 1</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/10/17/4-days-of-dockercon-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 06:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/10/17/4-days-of-dockercon-day-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2017/dockercon.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dockercon&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s those little things in life that you come to be grateful for when you are staying in a different country and significantly helps make your trip more relaxing and enjoyable. A quick visit to Starbucks in the morning or being able to grab a half decent lunch in a nearby restaurant during the conference or simply popping into a nearby newsagent to grab a newspaper to read in your room in the evening just make the days away from home a little more bearable&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Days of Dockercon – Day 0</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/10/15/4-days-of-dockercon-day-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 19:37:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/10/15/4-days-of-dockercon-day-0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2017/food.webp&#34; alt=&#34;BASALT&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s around this time of year that I&amp;rsquo;d usually begin blogging my traditional 5,6 or 7 days of PASS (another conference about another technology) and I have been doing this for at least 3-4 years (primarily as a speaker). This year, due to a multitude of reasons, I decided to pull my sessions just prior to selection after deciding that it really was time for me to do something different. Those people who know me quite well will know that I have harbored a very strong interest in Microservices and container technologies (long before they started getting &amp;ldquo;hip&amp;rdquo; in the world of Microsoft) and have had a bucket list desire to attend Dockercon since it&amp;rsquo;s inception.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
