<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General Tips on tenbulls blog</title>
    <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/general-tips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General Tips on tenbulls blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © {year} Mark Broadbent</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/general-tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reading very BIG text files using PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2018/03/14/reading-big-text-files-using-ps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2018/03/14/reading-big-text-files-using-ps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2018/big.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Big&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I frequently have to troubleshoot a variety of data feeds (populated from very very large files) which are regularly ingested into SQL Server for reporting and data validation purposes. From time to time, these feeds break due to malformed or invalid data provided by the third parties, and often due to the size of the files and limitations of third-party text file applications, loading them into a text file viewer is not possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving lost applications back into your Desktop on Windows</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/04/07/moving-lost-applications-back-into-your-desktop-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 12:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/04/07/moving-lost-applications-back-into-your-desktop-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ok, I confess that this post is about as far removed as I can probably get from my blogging &lt;em&gt;focus&lt;/em&gt;, but as of late I have been running into this problem more and more frequently on my Windows 10 tablet and it is starting to annoy me. So to use my blogging platform for the original purpose (as a reference for me in the first instance), I have decided to make a little note of what actions I take to get these dastardly disappearing applications back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
