<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Training on tenbulls blog</title>
    <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/training/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Training on tenbulls blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © {year} Mark Broadbent</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 14:31:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/training/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bring-A-Boss to SQLSaturday Training day promotion</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/08/20/announcing-our-sqlsaturday-cambridge-bring-a-boss-training-day-promotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 14:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/08/20/announcing-our-sqlsaturday-cambridge-bring-a-boss-training-day-promotion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2015/david_brent_111.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;David Brent&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft are delivering a dedicated full day pre-conference training day session at &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlcambs.org.uk/&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Cambridge&lt;/a&gt; aimed towards Data Professional Leaders and Executives, delivered by industry leading technology movers and shakers. &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlcambs.org.uk/precon7/&#34;&gt;Building a Data Driven Strategy&lt;/a&gt; will help your boss understand how they invest in Data Driven Data Analytics and how they can implement them. They will learn all about Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s future data vision and understand what theirs should be. It is something they will not want to miss.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Business Intelligence Seminar 2011</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/enlightenment/presentation-notepad/microsoft-bi-seminar-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/enlightenment/presentation-notepad/microsoft-bi-seminar-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The seminar was given on the Microsoft Campus at Reading UK on the 3rd March 2011. The presentation was split into four sections and the end of each section represents a real world intermission. You would be advised to download the slides (download link in notes) and follow the notes as you step through the slides. I personally think there is some excellent information embedded in these notes, your job now oh dear Business Analyst is start “data mining” for what is important and what is not! Within these notes you will also find a video link to last years presentation. Unfortunately due to the &lt;em&gt;NDA&lt;/em&gt; nature of some of the information talked about this years session, it was not recorded.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A visit to the Microsoft Business Intelligence Seminar 2011</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2011/03/09/business_intelligence_seminar_2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 12:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2011/03/09/business_intelligence_seminar_2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I visited Microsoft for the Microsoft Business Intelligence Seminar presentation given by  Rafal Lukawiecki (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rafaldotnet&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://rafal.net/&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;). I must say that I found this one of the most valuable full day presentations that I have watched in a VERY long time for many different reasons. It is probably fair to say that I have probably not engaged BI as much as I probably should have over the last few years, since I have been focused on many other things. However it was plain to see that much of Rafal&amp;rsquo;s vision for the future of BI in IT was a very real possibility and as such is a compelling reason for me to re-engage. Certainly since the introduction of SQL 2000 Analysis Services, I am impressed by the pace in which the technology has matured.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SELECT MediaType, SUM(Content) FROM #Sources GROUP BY MediaType</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2011/03/08/t-sql_tuesday_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2011 00:06:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2011/03/08/t-sql_tuesday_16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/shared/tsql2sday150x15032.webp&#34; alt=&#34;TSQL Tuesday&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes people, for a change I have written my T-SQL Tuesday contribution several days in advance, ready for that very satisfying &lt;em&gt;Publish&lt;/em&gt; button to be pressed. But why you might ask? (OK well you didn&amp;rsquo;t ask but I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you anyway). 🙂&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reason that I decided to make that extra special bit of effort to write something in advance of Tuesday was precisely because I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a Scooby Doo (clue) of what exactly I was going to write about! This was thanks to the chosen subject of the month &lt;em&gt;Aggregation&lt;/em&gt; by the most excellent grrlgeek – Jes Borland (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/grrl_geek&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.lessthandot.com/index.php/All/?author=420&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
