<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal Development on tenbulls blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/personal-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal Development on tenbulls blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © {year} Mark Broadbent</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 02:06:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/personal-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SQLRally and Beyond</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/01/25/sqlrally-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 02:06:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/01/25/sqlrally-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am almost ashamed to say that I have let over a month pass since my last post and truth be told I have come close a few times without never actually pressing that submit button.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I shan&amp;rsquo;t bore you with my excuses or reasons for my inactivity but what matters is I&amp;rsquo;m back!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been seeing an increasing amount of noise about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sqlpass.org/sqlrally/2012/dallas/&#34;&gt;SQLRally Dallas&lt;/a&gt; and I felt that I wanted to share my own personal experience with you about this rather unique event (in Orlando) -for it quite literary changed my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everybody wants to be important</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/03/25/everybody-wants-to-be-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 12:49:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/03/25/everybody-wants-to-be-important/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a very big fan of &amp;ldquo;self-development&amp;rdquo; materials whether they be books, audio, presentations or simply just ramblings on the Internet and last year during the &amp;ldquo;Meet an MVP&amp;rdquo; lunch time at the SQL PASS 2010 Summit this was the hotly debated subject on our table. I know these materials generally get a bad press and I always remember a line from one of our comedians here in the UK who was criticising them and said &amp;ldquo;the clue is in the name….self!….so why are you listening to someone else!&amp;rdquo;. However in all seriousness, for me I personally believe that the &amp;ldquo;self&amp;rdquo; actually means that we always need to examine ourselves and our behaviour in order to grow into something better. One thing that I know for sure is that I have a lot of work ahead of me to become the person that I want to be and I know it is within my power to do so.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SELECT MediaType, SUM(Content) FROM #Sources GROUP BY MediaType</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/03/08/t-sql_tuesday_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2011 00:06:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/03/08/t-sql_tuesday_16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2011/tsql2sday150x15032.webp&#34; alt=&#34;TSQL Tuesday&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes people, for a change I have written my T-SQL Tuesday contribution several days in advance, ready for that very satisfying Publish button to be pressed. But why you might ask? (OK well you didn&amp;rsquo;t ask but I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you anyway). 🙂&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reason that I decided to make that extra special bit of effort to write something in advance of Tuesday was precisely because I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a Scooby Doo (clue) of what exactly I was going to write about! This was thanks to the chosen subject of the month &amp;ldquo;Aggregation&amp;rdquo; by the most excellent grrlgeek – Jes Borland (Twitter | Blog)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLRally is live!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/02/25/sqlrally-area-is-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 16:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/02/25/sqlrally-area-is-live/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the coming weeks and months leading up to SQLRally, I will be adding information, news and more detail about my presentation. For now though the root area is live which is effectively the &amp;ldquo;press release&amp;rdquo; provided to the selected speakers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2011/sqlrally_banner_240x120_1.webp&#34; alt=&#34;SQLRally Orlando&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Click picture for more&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget, if you do see me wandering around in Orlando, to say hello. It&amp;rsquo;s always great to meet new people and I am always humbled by the high level of skill in the SQL community. Also (and most importantly) expanding our IT Professional Support Network will ensure that we always will have an ear to bend when we have technical problems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLBits 7 the forgotten photos part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/02/12/sqlbits-7-forgotten-photos-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 19:48:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/02/12/sqlbits-7-forgotten-photos-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlbits.com/default.aspx&#34;&gt;SQLBits&lt;/a&gt; 8 voting has now ended so perhaps it is a good time to publish the second and final post of the series. I wonder if any of my sessions will get selected this time? One of my submitted sessions is the same one that has made it to the reserve list for the first ever &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/sqlrally/2011/&#34;&gt;SQLRally&lt;/a&gt; in Orlando and although slightly disappointed at just making the reserve list I was very proud that out of all the reserve sessions I came joint top (I took 38% of the vote in my category). The winner of that category is the well known Edwin Sarmiento (&lt;a href=&#34;https://bassplayerdoc.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bassplayerdoc&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;) and he is an absolutely smashing chap so I&amp;rsquo;m nothing but pleased for him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automate now to save time later</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/02/08/t-sql-tuesday-015-spend-time-now-to-save-time-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 12:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/02/08/t-sql-tuesday-015-spend-time-now-to-save-time-later/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2011/tsql2sday150x15032.webp&#34; alt=&#34;TSQL Tuesday&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s T-SQL Tuesday time again and this month I&amp;rsquo;m a little late off the starting block. This time it is being hosted by Pat Wright &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlasylum.wordpress.com&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/SqlAsylum&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; and the subject of the month is all about &amp;ldquo;Automation in SQL Server&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So what is my favourite automation script or technique that I use in SQL Server? I had to have a think about this and my problem is that I have quite a few. I believe that the accessibility and usability of the Windows and SQL GUI (and related tools) means that SQL DBAs in particular have a tendency to automate much more than other IT Professionals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My submitted SQLRally sessions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/01/27/sqlrally-just-proud-to-be-in-there-with-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 10:41:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/01/27/sqlrally-just-proud-to-be-in-there-with-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2011/sqlrally1.png&#34; alt=&#34;SQLRally logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several months ago, I submitted two sessions to SQLRally with great enthusiasm as detailed in this post. The first &amp;ldquo;The Great High Availability Hustle&amp;rdquo; I had been thinking about for a very long time and is hopefully going to fill a void that has existed for too long. As a DBA, if you are not already using Clustering I guarantee that you will be, sooner or later. SQL 2008 finally gave us true HA product for the Enterprise and I believe SQL High Availability is going to start gaining traction and market share over the coming months and years. But there is a problem with this. I believe that probably nearly every DBA that has become competent with SQL Clustering will at one point have had a baptism of fire with the technology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye SQL 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/01/16/countdown-to-extinction-goodbye-sql-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2011 20:06:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/01/16/countdown-to-extinction-goodbye-sql-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I cannot let the week go by without a special goodbye to an old friend. If you hadn&amp;rsquo;t already heard, &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.msdn.com/b/sqlreleaseservices/archive/2010/09/29/end-of-support-for-sql-server-7-0.aspx?wa=wsignin1.0&#34;&gt;SQL 7.0 support officially ended on the 11th January&lt;/a&gt; of this week. This means that as of now, legacy installations of SQL Server 7 are threatened with extinction and is only a matter of time before they become as scarce as SQL 6.5 installs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in how I got started with SQL Server and you haven&amp;rsquo;t done so already, you might want to take a quick peek at my &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/about&#34;&gt;about&lt;/a&gt; page. Here I mention how I quite insightfully (read luckily) took a training opportunity and put myself on a SQL 7 beta course rather than the one my company was expecting – one for SQL 6.5. That decision had a very big effect on my future IT career. Whilst at the training centre I remember that there was a guy there who claimed that he had been one of the first 100 people in the world to certify as an MCSE+i and his efforts to do so had been made a little easier because of the fact that he had apparently been based in Saudi Arabia for six months in a company that had not only a testing centre but all course materials available to him. He said of being out there &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;well what else can you do for 6 months in Saudi? I thought I might as well do something productive!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Start as you mean to go on</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/01/11/t-sql-tuesday-014-start-as-you-mean-to-go-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2011 02:03:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/01/11/t-sql-tuesday-014-start-as-you-mean-to-go-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2011/tsql2sday150x15032.webp&#34; alt=&#34;TSQL Tuesday&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I cant believe T-SQL Tuesday has come around so soon again, and luckily I have just seen a tweet for someone else&amp;rsquo;s contribution just before I was about to turn into bed (it has just gone 01:17 a.m here in the UK).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So people, be grateful that I&amp;rsquo;m sacrificing those precious extra minutes counting sheep just to spout nonsense to you all! Actually you&amp;rsquo;d probably prefer that I just went to bed right? Well tough, I&amp;rsquo;m writing this even if it takes me all night (which I can assure you it won&amp;rsquo;t!).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2010 in reflection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/01/01/a-year-in-provence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 23:59:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/01/01/a-year-in-provence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Firstly let me wish you all a very happy New Year and secondly a big thank you to all of you who have been dropping by my blog and I sincerely hope you continue to do so. I&amp;rsquo;ve been seeing at least a 10% month on month growth in traffic since the start of the year and its the prospect that I might be producing something (however remote) of interest to someone makes my efforts even more rewarding. I would also like to pay my respects to all those other Bloggers in the Blogosphere who provide great content for me to consume – more on this in the next few days. Also lets not forget the Tweeps, and if you do both then a huge big-up to you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at SQLRally 2011!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/12/16/excited-about-sqlrally-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2010 13:42:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/12/16/excited-about-sqlrally-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am very pleased/ proud to announce that I have submitted 2 abstracts for presentations to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/sqlrally/2011/&#34;&gt;SQLRally&lt;/a&gt; and should I be chosen they will be given in Orlando, Florida between May 11th to May 13th. For those of you not already aware, SQLRally is a little bit like a mini SQL PASS Summit and enables people from the East Coast of America to visit an event closer to them should they have not been able to attend the PASS Summit due to the distance and cost restrictions. It has been devised to fill the gap between SQL Saturday events and more can be found by visiting this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/sqlrally/2011/About.aspx&#34;&gt;url&lt;/a&gt;. I believe it is going to be a great success. Should I be chosen to present at SQLRally, which will be a tall order given the very strong competition it will be only my second time going to a SQL Event in the States (PASS 2010 was my first) it will be my very first visit to the East Coast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLBits 7 the forgotten photos part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/12/01/sqlbits-7-forgotten-photos-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 15:05:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/12/01/sqlbits-7-forgotten-photos-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Several weeks back I attached my Blackberry to my PC to clear down all the photos in preparation for SQL Pass and I stumbled across these grainy old photos taken during those rainy few days in York. It all seems like a lifetime ago now and much has happened to me since &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlbits.com&#34;&gt;SQL Bits&lt;/a&gt; 7, but this was my story of an interesting and enjoyable but all too brief few days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLBits Speaker Training Day</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/09/19/speaker-training-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2010 18:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/09/19/speaker-training-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago, I (like many others) rolled into Reading to attend the Speaker Training day held at Microsoft HQ in the UK. This event was organized to help people prepare for speaking at SQLBits 7 (if your submission was successful) or to prepare for a future successful submission (if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t). Upon arriving at Microsoft it was quite funny because the receptionist seemed to recognize me, but since I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been to that building for around 3 years I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how she could have done …still it&amp;rsquo;s always nice to be &amp;ldquo;recognized&amp;rdquo; 🙂&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
