<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Concurrency on tenbulls blog</title>
    <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/concurrency/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Concurrency on tenbulls blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © {year} Mark Broadbent</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 22:29:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/concurrency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lock Compatibility Matrix 1.2</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2011/11/17/compatibility-matrix-1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 22:29:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2011/11/17/compatibility-matrix-1-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of months back I published my version of SQL Server’s Lock Compatibility Matrix under the post &lt;a href=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2011/09/27/fancy-a-decent-compatibility-matrix&#34;&gt;Fancy a decent Compatibility Matrix?&lt;/a&gt; since the one provided by MSDN is really very poorly designed and difficult for the average Joe to understand.This is one reason I believe that lock compatibility is a very misunderstood subject.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One thing that has bothered me about my version from the very beginning was the use of green and red to respectively indicate compatible or incompatible locks. The reason this has bothered me from the offset is because I was aware that those two colours could be a very big problem for colour blind DBAs. However, for me they really DID look great together and &lt;em&gt;told the story&lt;/em&gt; of the compatibility between the locks without even needing words -every (non colour blind) person understands the concept of GREEN -&amp;gt; GO (i.e. lock grant), RED -&amp;gt; STOP (i.e. lock wait). BUT that doesn&amp;rsquo;t help colour blind people very much does it!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NOLOCK hits Mythbusters!</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2011/10/14/nolock-hits-mythbusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 15:59:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2011/10/14/nolock-hits-mythbusters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Exactly one month to this very day I wrote the article &lt;a href=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2011/09/14/when-should-you-use-nolock&#34;&gt;When should you use NOLOCK?&lt;/a&gt; which explained exactly when the use of the &lt;code&gt;READUNCOMMITTED&lt;/code&gt; isolation level was acceptable and when it wasn’t. I also revealed that it not only takes out a &lt;em&gt;Schema Stability (Sch-S)&lt;/em&gt; lock on the object (which is documented in Books Online for the hint) but also took out a special &lt;em&gt;Shared (S) Bulk Operation&lt;/em&gt; lock when used on heaps. This latter behaviour is not even mentioned in Books Online for the hint and as far as I know, has never been documented or mentioned anywhere else before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fancy a decent Compatibility Matrix?</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2011/09/27/fancy-a-decent-compatibility-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 21:12:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2011/09/27/fancy-a-decent-compatibility-matrix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever taken a look at Microsoft’s published &lt;a href=&#34;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms186396.aspx&#34;&gt;compatibility matrix&lt;/a&gt; for SQL Server lock compatibility? If you have, then I don’t need to tell you that it sucks in a very big way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have no fear, I have painstakingly redrawn at better one (via PowerPoint no less!) and am making available to you totally free of charge as a lovely PDF slide found via &lt;a href=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/documents/readpastfuriouslockcompatibilitymatrix.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip; Why you ask? Because I love you all!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When should you use NOLOCK?</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2011/09/14/when-should-you-use-nolock/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 12:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2011/09/14/when-should-you-use-nolock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well the quick answer to that question is never. And there you have it, the quickest blog post in history (perhaps!).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;…Except that I should really have said &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;When should you use &lt;code&gt;READUNCOMMITTED&lt;/code&gt; isolation or hint?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; and then the question takes a little more of a surprising turn. Let me first start and explain why I have categorically ruled against the use of &lt;code&gt;NOLOCK&lt;/code&gt;. The reason, is that at some point in the dim and distant future Microsoft may decide to remove this hint from the product. If they could do it today, they probably would; the only thing that is really stopping them is the numerous lines of external T-SQL code that dirtys the floors of many Development teams around the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
