<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tenbulls blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on tenbulls blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © {year} Mark Broadbent</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:06:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate Training Resources Page</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/enlightenment/training-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:06:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/enlightenment/training-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update (27th January 2026):&lt;/em&gt; Currently the Ultimate Training Resources Page section of the new website has not been migrated. I&amp;rsquo;ll seek to build this back up over time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Restart of blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/04/06/blog-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 18:51:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/04/06/blog-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2025/restart-plane-ai-600.png&#34; alt=&#34;Restarting&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve finally made the shift to my new statically generated blog and am slowly migrating the content over. This operation is probably going to take me quite some time since I will need to go all the way back to 2009 and decide what posts and content I want to come across. There is possibly over a hundred posts (or more) to bring across! I&amp;rsquo;ll also be quite keen on bringing over some of my more useful resources (although they may need a huge revamp/ update) such as my Ultimate Resources Training Page and others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 13:48:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/shared/me-fin.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Me in Finland&#34; style=&#34;margin:50px;float:right&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;Hi there and thank you for dropping by my pages!&#xD;&#xA;My name is Mark Broadbent and I am a Microsoft Certified Master in SQL Server (there are approximately 28 of us in the UK and 220 worldwide, although this certification has now been grandfathered) and a former 7 time Microsoft Data Platform MVP focusing on Microsoft Azure, Azure DevOps, SQL Server, Administration, Development, Business Intelligence, Docker, Data Factory, and Cosmos DB. I also have strong expertise in concurrency, performance, high availability, disaster recovery, virtualization, Windows and Linux, C# and dotNET.&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--this is needed due to markdown not converting line space with picture--&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am the Technical Editor to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Microsoft-SQL-Server-2017-Linux-ebook/dp/B07DCH314W/&#34;&gt;SQL Server on Linux &lt;/a&gt; (published 2018, McGraw-Hill), and Technical Reviewer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/High-Performance-SQL-Server-Mission-Critical-ebook/dp/B08TQR3NMF&#34;&gt;High Performance SQL Server: Consistent Response for Mission-Critical Applications 2nd Edition&lt;/a&gt; (published 2021, Apress), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/SQL-Server-Query-Tuning-Optimization/dp/1803242620&#34;&gt;SQL Server Query Tuning and Optimization: Optimize Microsoft SQL Server 2022 queries and applications&lt;/a&gt; (published 2022, Apress), and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Expert-Server-Transactions-Locking-Practitioners-ebook/dp/B07FXCW836&#34;&gt;Expert SQL Server Transactions and Locking Concurrency Internals for SQL Server Practitioners&lt;/a&gt; (published 2018, Apress).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Future Changes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/02/01/future-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 20:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/02/01/future-changes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick note to give an update on the future changes for this blog. Many long time readers out there might realise that what you are reading today no longer exists under its original domain and currently lives under its default WordPress domain namespace. Given that this blog has existed since 2009 and been linked to from a variety of popular sources and published materials, this is a big shift.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automating Pause of Synapse Dedicated Pool Part I</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/06/18/automating-pause-of-synapse-dedicated-pool-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 20:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/06/18/automating-pause-of-synapse-dedicated-pool-part-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Synapse Analytics is an enterprise analytics engine that offers multiple (compute) Pool types that you can use for varying data processing and analytics requirements. Each Pool type has a slightly different cost model based upon its architecture, capabilities, and consumption patterns, but if we over simplify things, we can break these cost considerations down to compute costs and (in some cases) storage costs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest benefits with modern data lakehouse architectures is that with the separation of compute and storage comes the ability to reduce costs when compute is not needed, and most importantly, not running.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Is My Azure Solution Running Slow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/01/31/why-is-my-azure-solution-running-slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 15:36:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023/01/31/why-is-my-azure-solution-running-slow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an Azure data professional, one of the most common questions you are most likely to hear from users is &amp;ldquo;why do cloud solutions often appear to have performance issues post-deployment&amp;rdquo;. This perception is particularly common for Azure migration projects moving on-premises into the cloud, but do these observations really match reality or are they misguided?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this introductory article, we will take a look into some of the reasons why Azure cloud-based solutions are often seen to be problematic, or in some cases, are problematic, and provide some ideas to avoid these negative perceptions in your cloud environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encouraging Diversity in Leadership Roles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/09/01/encouraging-diversity-in-leadership-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 21:19:27 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/09/01/encouraging-diversity-in-leadership-roles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over 33 years ago I started my journey working in Information Technology (I.T.), and it is probably fair to say that I have worked my way slowly up from the absolute bottom of the pile to the modest heights of today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-problem-with-it&#34;&gt;The problem with I.T.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I look back over the years I cannot help but feel a sense of disappointment that during my long and arduous journey to the &amp;ldquo;top&amp;rdquo; I never really found someone of seniority (or power) who went out of their way to selflessly help me climb the greasy ladder of success in any of the organisations I worked at. I don&amp;rsquo;t think my experiences are particularly unique either.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Introduction to Azure Purview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/07/29/a-quick-introduction-to-azure-purview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 07:15:27 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2022/07/29/a-quick-introduction-to-azure-purview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2022/catalogue-of-data-ai-600.png&#34; alt=&#34;Data Catalog&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Azure Purview is Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s next-generation data catalog service in Azure which is a direct replacement for the first-generation service known as Azure Data Catalog. While some people refer to Purview as Azure Data Catalog v2, It is important to note that Purview is more of a re-write of Azure Data Catalog rather than an upgrade, and as such, no migration path between both services currently exists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Azure Purview can be used to inventory, classify, map, and govern your on-premises, multi-cloud, and SaaS data estate, providing a holistic up-to-date map of your data with automatic data discovery, data classification, and end-to-end data lineage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSIS Data Flow Performance Tuning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/08/11/ssis-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 15:18:01 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/08/11/ssis-performance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yes before you say it, I know SQL Server Integration Services is &amp;ldquo;old technology&amp;rdquo; but a lot of people are still using it, and in many cases are either still developing against it, or are looking to integrate/ migrate with other burgeoning technologies such as Azure Data Factory. In other words, if you are not currently using SSIS then this post is probably not for you -otherwise read on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are still one of the lucky ones to still be using SSIS, I thought it would be worth publishing these comprehensive notes taken from a session titled &amp;ldquo;SSIS Data Flow Performance Tuning&amp;rdquo; delivered at SQLBits 8 (Brighton) by the then &amp;ldquo;SSIS guru&amp;rdquo; Jamie Thomson. Notes have timings (in mins and seconds) against them, which correlate directly with the presentation times. The video is still available and can be downloaded from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlbits.com/Sessions/Event8/SSIS_Dataflow_Performance_tuning&#34;&gt;SQLBits website&lt;/a&gt; so you can watch it (if required) and use the timings to follow along.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Querying Azure Vm State With Powershell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/05/12/querying-azure-vm-state-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 15:16:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/05/12/querying-azure-vm-state-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently given the task of identifying the state of an Azure VM so that an automation script using the &lt;code&gt;az vm run-command invoke&lt;/code&gt; would not fail if the VM was down or under a reboot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I initially thought the task would be really easy and a simple query of the VM state using &lt;code&gt;Get-AzVM&lt;/code&gt; would provide us with a running state property of the VM, but as it happens the state is a little abstracted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Removing and Maintaining Azure Resource Group Deployments Based Upon Deployment Count</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/05/06/removing-and-maintaining-azure-resource-group-deployments-based-upon-deployment-count/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 11:37:47 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/05/06/removing-and-maintaining-azure-resource-group-deployments-based-upon-deployment-count/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whenever you create or update an Azure resource, a new &lt;em&gt;deployment&lt;/em&gt; is created under the resources&amp;rsquo; configured resource group. This deployment history is retained ad-infinitum until you eventually hit the hard limit of &lt;em&gt;800 deployments (per resource group)&lt;/em&gt;. You may think this figure is more than enough to accommodate all the possible resource changes that could ever be made in a resource group, but if you are running CICD pipelines to push out your Infrastructure as Code (IaC) (or create lots of resources per resource group) then it is very likely you will exhaust this figure very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inconsistent result sets and another case against pessimistic isolation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/04/27/inconsistent-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 12:05:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/04/27/inconsistent-results/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of demonstrating when transaction processing goes bad in Database Management Systems because it is a reminder to us all to ensure that we know exactly what we are doing when we write our code. Not only should you test and execute your code multiple times in serial (for instance running in sequence in isolation), but you should also execute in parallel with itself or other potentially dependent transactions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Restore Azure Devops Repository</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/04/14/restore-azure-devops-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 12:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/04/14/restore-azure-devops-repository/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are using &lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-gb/services/devops/&#34;&gt;Azure DevOps&lt;/a&gt;, you might be comforted that your &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; repo is &amp;ldquo;in the Cloud&amp;rdquo; and automatically has availability and disaster guarantees. However you (or someone else) still have the ability to accidentally (or maliciously) delete repos from Azure DevOps Repos. Surprisingly, at the time of writing, there is no GUI based option to restore your repo. This might initially instill a sense of panic as you frantically search for the latest local clone to replace your remote – but there is a better way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cannot delete old build definitions in Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/03/25/delete-old-build-definitions-in-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 19:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/03/25/delete-old-build-definitions-in-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been experiencing a problem for quite a while now in my current environment, in that some of our old builds cannot be deleted. When you attempt to do so it results in the following error:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2020/cannotdel.webp&#34; alt=&#34;build error&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One or more builds associated with the requested pipeline(s) are retained by a release. The pipeline(s) and builds will not be deleted.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many of our pipelines have undergone a lot of change over time to the degree it is not even obvious anymore why (or indeed where) these builds are being prevented from being dropped. The only thing that is clear is that until they can be, the old build definitions will remain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Querying Azure Devops Rest Api With Powershell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/03/11/querying-azure-devops-rest-api-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 13:13:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/03/11/querying-azure-devops-rest-api-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2020/saddog.png&#34; alt=&#34;sad dog&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In previous posts we have talked about trying to use and consume Azure DevOps using PowerShell and utilizing the Azure CLI. In particular, my post titled Use &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/02/17/use-powershell-to-consume-your-azure-cli-devops-result-set.md&#34;&gt;PowerShell to consume your Azure CLI DevOps result&lt;/a&gt; set painted a rather frustrating picture when trying to manipulate the tabular dataset from the Azure CLI. Furthermore, our functionality is restricted to only those commands implemented by the Azure CLI Azure DevOps add-in -as will become increasingly obvious, this is limited to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dropbox Appears Stuck Synchronizing Files</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/02/25/dropbox-appears-stuck-synchronizing-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 10:28:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/02/25/dropbox-appears-stuck-synchronizing-files/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Normally I don&amp;rsquo;t like off-topic style posts, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com&#34;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; is certainly not within my key areas of interest, however, I am an avid user and every now and then I run into a problem that is frustrating and worrying -given a large number of important files I store on that platform. This post is my placeholder to help myself – and hopefully you!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently ran into an issue where my Dropbox icon just kept spinning and spinning and believed it was related to some weird conflict resolution problem across different machines that I had run into by accident.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use Powershell to Consume Your Azure Cli Devops Result Set</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/02/17/use-powershell-to-consume-your-azure-cli-devops-result-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 13:43:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/02/17/use-powershell-to-consume-your-azure-cli-devops-result-set/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Use PowerShell to consume your Azure CLI DevOps result set&#xA;Before we get going it is probably first worth me pointing out (in case you are wondering) that the whole premise of this post stems from a lack of native Azure DevOps PowerShell Module. Yes there are a few solutions out there, but at the time of writing there is no official Microsoft PowerShell DevOps module, so we are stuck with using the CLI if you want to avoid using these other solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rewrite Your Powershell Azurerm to Az for Azure Devops Deployments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/02/13/rewrite-your-powershell-azurerm-to-az-for-azure-devops-deployments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 14:58:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/02/13/rewrite-your-powershell-azurerm-to-az-for-azure-devops-deployments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to get a quick post out on specific problem that I have just encountered from one of our Azure DevOps release pipelines in which one of the release stage tasks started failing for no reason (despite no obvious changes having been made). Hopefully this post will help others if you are also experiencing this problem and don&amp;rsquo;t know what to do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The error message was as follows for our task &lt;code&gt;Enable Firewall on Data Lake&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Azure Cli to Query Azure Devops</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/01/06/using-azure-cli-to-query-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 20:41:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020/01/06/using-azure-cli-to-query-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In previous posts, I have touched upon the use of Azure Cloud Shell for generic querying of Azure resources and I thought it would be useful to quickly document its use for something a little more specific such as querying or manipulating &lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/devops/&#34;&gt;Azure DevOps&lt;/a&gt; through the command line.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For my example, I will focus on something as mundane and straight-forward as querying the Azure DevOps repository meta-data (so that I can look at and compare branch settings against each other) but I hope you get the idea that this is just scratching the tip of the iceberg and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/cli/azure/get-started-with-azure-cli?view=azure-cli-latest&#34;&gt;Azure CLI&lt;/a&gt; is a powerful tool to add to your arsenal of scripting languages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encouraging diversity at technical events – volunteers and organisers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019/08/29/diversity-at-technical-events-volunteers-and-organisers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 19:28:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019/08/29/diversity-at-technical-events-volunteers-and-organisers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the third and final post of this three-part series, I will be exploring a few thoughts and ideas regarding how we can encourage diversity of &lt;em&gt;volunteers and organisers&lt;/em&gt; at technical events. I have been organising events as far back as 2010 so I have (no doubt) been responsible for many failures (and hopefully a few successes) in promoting and hosting events to the community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before we start talking about diversity, I think it is first important to define what I mean by this term. According to the Merriam-Webster definition, diversity is &amp;ldquo;the condition of having or being composed of differing elements&amp;rdquo; and especially &amp;ldquo;the inclusion of different types of people (such as people of different races or cultures) in a group or organization&amp;rdquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t quite think this extends far enough, and I see personally see diversity as the inclusion of all people regardless of their gender, sexual orientation, ability, physical appearance, age, size, race, or religion. Our aim, therefore, should be to provide a harassment-free conference experience in which everyone can enjoy this in equal measure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encouraging diversity at technical events – speakers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019/07/25/diversity-at-technical-events-speakers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 21:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019/07/25/diversity-at-technical-events-speakers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the second of this three-part series, I will be exploring a few thoughts and ideas regarding how we can encourage diversity of speakers at technical events. I have been organising events as far back as 2010 so I have (no doubt) been responsible for many failures (and hopefully a few successes) in promoting and hosting events to the community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before we start talking about diversity, I think it is first important to define what I mean by this term. According to the Merriam-Webster definition, diversity is &amp;ldquo;the condition of having or being composed of differing elements&amp;rdquo; and especially &amp;ldquo;the inclusion of different types of people (such as people of different races or cultures) in a group or organization&amp;rdquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t quite think this extends far enough, and I see personally see diversity as the inclusion of all people regardless of their gender, sexual orientation, ability, physical appearance, age, size, race, or religion. Our aim, therefore, should be to provide a harassment-free conference experience in which everyone can enjoy this in equal measure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encouraging diversity at technical events – attendees</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019/06/17/diversity-at-technical-events-attendees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 19:36:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019/06/17/diversity-at-technical-events-attendees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the first of this three-part series, I will be exploring a few thoughts and ideas regarding how we can encourage diversity of &lt;em&gt;attendees&lt;/em&gt; at technical events. I have been organising events as far back as 2010 so I have (no doubt) been responsible for many failures (and hopefully a few successes) in promoting and hosting events to the community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before we start talking about diversity, I think it is first important to define what &lt;em&gt;I mean&lt;/em&gt; by this term. According to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/diversity&#34;&gt;Merriam-Webster&lt;/a&gt; definition, diversity is &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;the condition of having or being composed of differing elements&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; and especially &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;the inclusion of different types of people (such as people of different races or cultures) in a group or organization&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t quite think this extends far enough, and I see personally see diversity as the inclusion of all people regardless of their gender, sexual orientation, ability, physical appearance, age, size, race, or religion. Our aim, therefore, should be to provide a harassment-free conference experience in which everyone can enjoy this in equal measure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azure subscription is not registered to use Cosmos DB namespace</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019/05/31/azure-subscription-is-not-registered/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 20:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019/05/31/azure-subscription-is-not-registered/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is usually the simplest things that often leave me feeling like I am a complete dummy. One such issue I ran into fairly recently when trying to deploy Cosmos DB into an Azure subscription.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From Azure DevOps I received the following error:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2019-05-31T16:28:55.4288261Z ##[error]MissingSubscriptionRegistration : The subscription is not registered to use namespace &amp;lsquo;Microsoft.DocumentDB&amp;rsquo;. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/rps-not-found&#34;&gt;https://aka.ms/rps-not-found&lt;/a&gt; for how to register subscriptions.&#xA;2019-05-31T16:28:55.5005526Z ##[section]Finishing: Deploy Cosmos Account and Database with Shared Capacity&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Azure Cloud Shell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019/04/25/introduction-to-azure-cloud-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 17:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019/04/25/introduction-to-azure-cloud-shell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2019/cloudshell.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;On the beach&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my last couple of posts, I have described the remote management of Azure through the command line from what was essentially a fat (or thick) client. This gives you an awful lot of scripting and automation control over the platform by using either the Azure CLI or PowerShell through the PowerShell Az Module. This is perfect for most cases, but what if you are using an unsupported Operating System or you only have access to the browser (perhaps via a thin client)?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AzureRM, Azure CLI and the PowerShell Az Module</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019/02/01/azurerm-azure-cli-and-the-powershell-az-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 13:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019/02/01/azurerm-azure-cli-and-the-powershell-az-module/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2019/azurecli.png&#34; alt=&#34;Azure CLI&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is now a variety of Microsoft provided command line tools available to connect to (and manage) Azure Resources and the situation is quite confusing to new-comers or those individuals who have not kept up to date with new developments. This post is designed to rectify this situation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is probably also worth me mentioning that I am focusing on the usage and deployment of these tools with Linux in mind, however, the following explanation is also applicable to Windows and macOS environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing Azure CLI on Linux Mint</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018/12/01/installing-azure-cli-on-linux-mint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 21:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018/12/01/installing-azure-cli-on-linux-mint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Azure CLI (or Azure Command Line Interface) allows provides an easy way to create and manage your Azure resources on macOS, Linux, and Windows. If you (like me) are using Linux and wish to use and control &lt;a href=&#34;https://portal.azure.com&#34;&gt;Microsoft Azure&lt;/a&gt; easily through the command line, then it is probably something you should have.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wanted to write a very quick post in order to explain the very simple steps you must follow to get the Azure CLI working for you if are using an &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category:Ubuntu_derivatives&#34;&gt;Ubuntu derivative distribution&lt;/a&gt; such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://linuxmint.com/&#34;&gt;Linux Mint&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft’s basic installation guide &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/cli/azure/install-azure-cli-apt?view=azure-cli-latest&#34;&gt;Install Azure CLI with apt&lt;/a&gt; has one specific problem for those distros, so let’s take a look at the Ubuntu section of that guide:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create multiple dashboards in the Azure Portal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018/11/01/create-multiple-dashboards-in-the-azure-portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 10:12:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018/11/01/create-multiple-dashboards-in-the-azure-portal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Several years ago I wrote a very quick post on the Azure Portal user-experience called &lt;a href=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/2016/02/29/using-the-new-azure-dashboard-favourites-and-tiles/&#34;&gt;Using the new Azure Dashboard favourites and tiles&lt;/a&gt; which demonstrated how Microsoft is improving the usability of the Azure Portal. As such, It is probably worth a very quick mention that I recently noticed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://portal.azure.com&#34;&gt;Microsoft Azure Portal&lt;/a&gt; now supports multiple dashboards, and according to my Google-Bing-Fu seems to have done so for a couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning to say NO</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2017/08/08/learning-to-say-no/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 20:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2017/08/08/learning-to-say-no/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thank you to Kendra Little who is hosting this month&amp;rsquo;s T-SQL Tuesday topic on &amp;ldquo;Interviewing Patterns and Anti-Patterns&amp;rdquo; - and what advice I might have for someone preparing for an interview. But instead of regurgitating the obvious advice you can find in other places, I&amp;rsquo;d rather talk about my own personal experiences, in-particular about a specific dark period in my professional career and how I avoided jumping into yet another bad experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dear #sqlfamily</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/12/16/dear-sqlfamily/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 15:32:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/12/16/dear-sqlfamily/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2015/rare_smile1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rare smile&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;This was the first time Lucy (and her brother smiled) after the first few days of treatment (in which she was constantly vomiting). A charity had come into the hospital to let the kids play with their video editing software. It was the first time that Mummy and Daddy felt hopefull&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would first like to apologise for the time it has taken for me to write this open letter to #sqlfamily in response to the rather incredible and slightly bewildering response to Steve Jones’s first #sqlwish initiative.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitesize SSIS - Passing SSIS variables into script components</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/11/30/bitesize-ssis-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 01:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/11/30/bitesize-ssis-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hate SSIS. It seems to me that it is full of certain nuances and unless you are regularly developing SSIS packages, they are easy to forget or it is easy to miss specific important steps. I first started using SSIS back in 2005 when it was directly introduced to replace DTS, but even today I am constantly going around in circles whenever I have to return to write certain functionality.Therefore I have decided to put together a “Bitesize” series of posts that encapsulate simple operations in order to help not just you, but more importantly remind me! Hopefully this will save me time in the long run&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/11/04/7-days-of-pass-day-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 15:28:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/11/04/7-days-of-pass-day-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2015/conf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Conference Center&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wake at 3 a.m. to find my plan of preparing my sessions into the late evening in tatters having completely crashed and burned after the huge meal the night before. My main session is scheduled to be delivered at 8 a.m so that means I have approximately &lt;em&gt;four hours&lt;/em&gt; to try and nail it. First I get showered at dressed, and then start running through my slide deck and correct error after error. Once I am happy with the deck, I read through my notes and study each slide until I am happy that I &lt;em&gt;understand&lt;/em&gt; each one. I run through the demos and complete main session preparation before returning back to the lightning talk. After working four solid hours I head to the Convention Centre so that I can grab a quick bite to eat and setup in my room with enough lead time before the session starts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 6</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/11/03/7-days-of-pass-day-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 16:14:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/11/03/7-days-of-pass-day-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2015/nikocrazy.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Crazy Niko&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s my 2nd and final day on the Blogger Table and also the 2nd day of the Summit proper. This time I am seated at the opposite end of the table to the day before and soon after sitting down I am greeted by Chris Yates (&lt;a href=&#34;https://chrisyatessql.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/yatessql&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;) who turns out to be a really nice guy and a pleasure to sit with. This time the keynote focuses more on the logistics of PASS growth and their finances more than anything else. After an all too long discussion on those points we finally get to the ever brilliant Dr David DeWitt and Dr Rimma Nehme who talk about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_of_Things&#34;&gt;IoT&lt;/a&gt;. I’ll be honest and say that I didn’t find much (personal) value in this discussion but that is probably because I am more interested in technical nitty gritty rather than more generalised discussion, but there is no doubting those two are not only brilliant individuals but are an incredible team together. Sad then that the real stand out announcement of the entire Summit Keynote sessions for me was their shock news that they would not be working together after this Summit due to David retiring and Rimma moving onto other things. The result was a couple of tears in my eyes and a standing ovation from all those present. I’ve been watching these guys present (especially David) since my very first Summit, and this feels like an end of an era to all concerned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/10/29/7-days-of-pass-day-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 23:58:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/10/29/7-days-of-pass-day-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2015/meandrob.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mark Broadbent and Rob Farley on Blogger table&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today is the first day proper of the Summit and I am scheduled to be on the Blogger table again which means an early start for me. I need some breakfast but am running out of time so for the first time ever (out of 6 years of Summit) I decide to drop by the Conference Center and check-out the breakfast offerings. The only thing that I really care about is Bacon and I am pleased to report that the dining hall has a bountiful supply! I grab some Egg, fruit and (of course) Bacon and wonder why I have never done this before??? Could have saved myself hundreds of Bucks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/10/28/7-days-of-pass-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/10/28/7-days-of-pass-day-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2015/pike.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pike&amp;rsquo;s Place&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another day, another dawn, but somebody forgot to tell my body that what has gone has gone. I feel pretty bad from yesterday’s alcoholic Molotov concoctions and have been up since 2.30 a.m. unable to sleep with jet-lag and over exuberance. By the morning I have become an expert on Seattle Weather reports and American News but I’m feeling a little better and am grateful for those few bottles of water in my room. I decide to get in-touch with last nights partners in crime and we arrange to meetup at &lt;a href=&#34;https://eatatlowells.com/&#34;&gt;Lowells&lt;/a&gt; to have some breakfast. This is good for me because I have wanted to try breakfast at Lowells for a long time having only ever eaten there for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/10/28/7-days-of-pass-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/10/28/7-days-of-pass-day-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2015/ill.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ill&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is unbelievable to think that it is already Monday although it feels like I’ve now been in Seattle for a week. Today is the first day of SQLPASS pre-conference sessions although this year is the first time ever in 6 years that I will not be attending them. Instead I’ve decided to leave the days open to do other things and hopefully catch up on some work, so this is what I try to do for the next few hours until my hunger cannot take it any more. I head over to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dailygrill.com/locations/daily-grill-seattle-washington/&#34;&gt;Daily Grill&lt;/a&gt; again for a quick breakfast and coffee and then head across the road to register at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wscc.com/&#34;&gt;Convention Center&lt;/a&gt; to pick up the standard fare and obligatory conference bag.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/10/28/7-days-of-pass-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/10/28/7-days-of-pass-day-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2015/soccer.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sounders&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is Sunday 8 a.m. and I’ve managed to sleep well after yesterday’s exuberance. My body aches, but I’m soaking my bones in a nice hot bath and starting to feel ready for the day. As I glance outside I can see that the darkened streets are glistening from the light rain that is gently falling. The Sun is not completely up and it is cloudy to boot. Welcome to Seattle weather.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/10/25/7-days-of-pass-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/10/25/7-days-of-pass-day-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2015/carnival.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Carnival of Souls&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having decided to avoid missing yet another day of work, rather than travel on my more traditional Friday slot, instead I managed to catch the early morning Saturday flight to Seattle from London Heathrow. Knowing that I had lots of work to do on the plane, I decided that an upgrade to Business Class was in order so upon boarding settled back for that more pampered experience. The flight itself was fairly uneventful and despite spending a couple of hours trying to go through presentation content, I could not resist the lure of the in-flight film system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle Unbreakable Linux installation fails on Hyper-V Generation 2 Virtual Machine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/10/16/oracle-unbreakable-linux-installation-fails-on-hyper-v-generation-2-virtual-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 14:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/10/16/oracle-unbreakable-linux-installation-fails-on-hyper-v-generation-2-virtual-machine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you been attempting (and failing) to install &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oracle.com/us/technologies/linux/overview/index.html&#34;&gt;Oracle Unbreakable Linux&lt;/a&gt; as a Virtual Machine under Hyper-V and cannot figure out what is wrong?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-problem&#34;&gt;The problem&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are receiving the following message:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34; data-lang=&#34;text&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Boot Failed. EFI SCSI Device.&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Boot Failed. EFI SCSI Device.&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Boot Failed. EFI SCSI Device. Failed Secure Boot Verification.&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;PXE Network Boot using IPv4&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;......&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;PXE-E18: Server response timeout.&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Boot Failed. EFI Network.&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;No Operating System was Loaded.&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Press a key to retry the boot sequence...&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2015/secure-boot-verification.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Secure Boot verification&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bring-A-Boss to SQLSaturday Training day promotion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/08/20/announcing-our-sqlsaturday-cambridge-bring-a-boss-training-day-promotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 14:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/08/20/announcing-our-sqlsaturday-cambridge-bring-a-boss-training-day-promotion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2015/david_brent_111.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;David Brent&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft are delivering a dedicated full day pre-conference training day session at &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlcambs.org.uk/&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Cambridge&lt;/a&gt; aimed towards Data Professional Leaders and Executives, delivered by industry leading technology movers and shakers. &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlcambs.org.uk/precon7/&#34;&gt;Building a Data Driven Strategy&lt;/a&gt; will help your boss understand how they invest in Data Driven Data Analytics and how they can implement them. They will learn all about Microsoft’s future data vision and understand what theirs should be. It is something they will not want to miss.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So you havent been selected for the PASS Summit?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/06/26/not-accepted-for-the-pass-summit-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 19:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/06/26/not-accepted-for-the-pass-summit-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I guess it could be easy to become complacent about being selected to speak at conferences and you could certainly argue that I have been tremendously lucky with the selection process since I first broke into the speaking circuit in 2010. In 2011 I delivered my first lightning talk at the Summit and this was already off the back of me being the only European speaker (AFAIK) at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/sqlrally/2011/orlando/Home.aspx&#34;&gt;SQLRally Orlando&lt;/a&gt;. Every year since then I have been fortunate enough to be selected to deliver one (or more) full session abstracts at the Summit and when combined with a nice collection of speaking gigs at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlsaturday.com/&#34;&gt;SQLSaturdays&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/Events/24HoursofPASS.aspx&#34;&gt;24HOP&lt;/a&gt; and other events you could be forgiven for thinking that I must have the &lt;em&gt;magic touch&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing SharePoint Saturday Cambridge 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/06/25/twotribes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 10:43:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/06/25/twotribes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2013, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlsaturday.com/228/eventhome.aspx&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Cambridge&lt;/a&gt; became the first ever SQLSaturday in the World to host a dedicated SharePoint track and the event was a great success. It struck me at the time how well we managed to get a SharePoint audience at an event that was largely about SQL Server so with the support of our dedicated SharePoint sponsors (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.combined-knowledge.com/&#34;&gt;Combined Knowledge&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.k2.com/&#34;&gt;K2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.axioworks.com/&#34;&gt;AxioWorks&lt;/a&gt;), a fantastic addition of SharePoint speakers and with the expert help from the SharePoint community through Peter Baddeley (&lt;a href=&#34;https:https://about.me/baddaz&#34;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/baddaz&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;) I think we managed to light the touch paper for my future plans for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlsaturday.com/411/EventHome.aspx&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Cambridge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday London 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/06/05/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturday-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 10:43:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/06/05/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturday-london/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2015/evoconf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Evoconf&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don’t think it is any great secret that I have had my eyes on the SharePoint Community for quite some time. With the introduction of a dedicated SharePoint track (and precon) in 2013 at &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlcambs.org.uk/category/sqlsaturday/&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Cambridge&lt;/a&gt; (a World 1st, I believe) and most recently my attendance of the three day annual &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sharepointevolutionconference.com/&#34;&gt;SharePoint Evolution Conference&lt;/a&gt; in London, it has been clear to me for years that the SQL and SharePoint Communities and technologies are more closely related and integrated than I think most professionals would realize. They are simply just different perspectives on what is essentially the end goal of presenting data to the end-user.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choose your own agenda - from SQLSaturday to the PASS Summit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/05/26/progcomm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 11:44:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/05/26/progcomm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2015/buck-needs-you.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Buck needs you!&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;OK so sadly Buck can’t be with us this year, but if he could, he would tell you to join our Programme Committee!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This year, SQLSaturday Cambridge is pioneering the first ever Global Programme Committee for a SQLSaturday and we want you to be part of it!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After being personally involved in the PASS Programme Committee for many many years and playing a small part in reviewing abstracts, speakers and anything else that needs an opinion, it might be natural that I would want to take my experiences of this process and attempt to improve things -or at very least try a different approach.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at SQLSaturday New York 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/04/09/speaking-at-sqlsaturday-380-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 15:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/04/09/speaking-at-sqlsaturday-380-new-york/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in August 2012 I had the honour of speaking at the last (but one) SQLSaturday to be held in New York City which marked a particular milestone in my SQL Server journey. While I had (by then) already spoken at the two American SQLRally events (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/sqlrally/2011/orlando/Home.aspx&#34;&gt;Orlando&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/sqlrally/2012/dallas/Home.aspx&#34;&gt;Dallas&lt;/a&gt;) and delivered a lightning talk at the 2011 PASS Summit, SQLSaturday New York was my first ever SQLSaturday in the U.S.A and because of that it was already special before I had even arrived.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to install SharePoint 2013 on Windows 2012R2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/03/30/how-to-install-sharepoint-2013-on-windows-2012r2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 07:52:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/03/30/how-to-install-sharepoint-2013-on-windows-2012r2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you want to jump straight to the condensed solution, then please feel free to go to the &lt;a href=&#34;#condensed-installation&#34;&gt;Condensed Installation instructions&lt;/a&gt; below. If you find this post useful or have any feedback then please leave me a comment so that I know my efforts were not wasted!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Installing Microsoft Backoffice products on Microsoft Operating Systems has over the years become a much easier proposition and is largely the reason why SQL Server got the reputation of being “easy”. Except it isn’t. Ask any idiot to install a SQL Server instance and create a database and there is a good chance that they will succeed, but ask them to install SQL Server correctly and configured to best practice, suddenly the knowledge gap becomes a little more obvious.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changing the boot order of generation 2 Virtual Machines in Systems Center VMM and Hyper-V</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/02/24/scvmm_boot_order/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 14:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/02/24/scvmm_boot_order/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Windows 2012 R2 hosts, Hyper-V introduced the concept of generation 2 Virtual Machines, which provide various &lt;a href=&#34;https://technet.microsoft.com/library/dn282285.aspx&#34;&gt;benefits and a set of restrictions&lt;/a&gt; to those VMs configured in this way. In most cases the performance improvements and functionality they provide make it desirable to create new Virtual Machines as generation 2 -assuming that you will run them on generation 2 capable hosts which at this time of writing is Windows 2012 R2 Servers! Furthermore you will also be restricted by your guest operating system because Windows Server 2008 R2 and Windows 7 are not supported by generation 2. There are also further considerations to take into account with regards to Linux support by Hyper-V and we shall look at that topic another time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at SQLBits XIV (after all!)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/02/20/speaking-at-sqlbits-xiv-after-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 13:36:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/02/20/speaking-at-sqlbits-xiv-after-all/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t think it is a particularly big secret that I am a fan of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlbits.com/&#34;&gt;SQLBits&lt;/a&gt; (more posts about SQLBits can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tags/sqlbits/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). I remember being at the PASS Summit in 2010 and enthusiastically talking about the SQLBits conference to those that cared to listen and was rather taken aback by the lack of awareness outside of Europe during my time there, so I like to think that my enthusiastic ramblings over the years have contributed in some very small way to promoting the conference to a wider global audience. SQLBits gave me my first speaking break, which allowed me soon after to speak at SQLRally in Orlando, so I am always grateful to them for offering me that opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at SQLSaturday Lisbon 2015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/02/17/speaking-at-sqlsaturday-lisbon-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 09:14:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/02/17/speaking-at-sqlsaturday-lisbon-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2015/sqlportremington2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Remington&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;I liked the event so much, I bought the community&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you ever asked an experienced speaker what is the best formula to follow when starting out on your road to presenting, they would most likely tell you to start &lt;em&gt;small&lt;/em&gt; and work your way up to bigger events. First present to your work colleagues, next move onto User-Groups, then onto bigger events such as SQLSaturdays and then finally (when you are ready) talk at the biggest events in the World such as the PASS Summit (in the U.S.A) or SQLBits (in the U.K).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Flash in Chrome/ Chromium on Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/01/06/flash-not-working-in-chrome-chromium/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 14:33:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015/01/06/flash-not-working-in-chrome-chromium/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2015/parliament_not_working.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Flash not working&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Linux works it works well, and when it doesn’t it can be a real pain in the backside. Usually though, the failings are not necessarily the fault of the OS, but more the fault of the way in which packages, snap-ins, extensions and other third party code is deployed. Granted, it doesn’t really help that there are numerous methods and &lt;em&gt;Package Managers&lt;/em&gt; available to install applications, codecs and their ilk, but often the fault lies partially with the Third-party vendors for not making the process as easy and transparent as possible (especially for the less technical savvy amongst us).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Days of PASSDay - 5</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/11/08/5-days-of-pass-day-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 14:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/11/08/5-days-of-pass-day-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2014/enterthedragon.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Enter the Dragon&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wake up to the faint sound of early morning traffic starting to roll slowly through the empty streets of Downtown Seattle as the occasional bark from a dog can be heard from somewhere in the distance. Nearby, just a few blocks away, the now empty Convention Center stands as a shell compared to the hive of activity that it was over the last week.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The last day of the Summit has been and gone and I feel just a hint of sadness that my time here in Seattle and the U.S.A is almost over but can at least start to think about the end of 2014 and look forward to good things in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Days of PASSDay - 4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/11/07/5-days-of-pass-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 14:56:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/11/07/5-days-of-pass-day-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2014/beingbuck.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Being Buck Woody&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I write, the penultimate day of the PASS Summit has been and gone. It was again an overloaded rollercoster of a ride filled with appointments, chance meetings of old friends and most significantly the day I gave my Community Session called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/summit/2014/Sessions.aspx#sid7377&#34;&gt;Being Buck Woody&lt;/a&gt; alongside the ever fabulous Buck Woody. I spent the early hours of the morning in deep concentration preparing for this session and even while eating breakfast I had my head down gathering thoughts and listening to some recorded notes. Later on, myself and Buck got together in the speaker room and did a final run through of the deck and both of us were fairly happy with the content and flow of the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Days of PASS - Day 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/11/06/5-days-of-pass-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2014 00:38:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/11/06/5-days-of-pass-day-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well just when you thought things could not get any busier, along comes Day 3 of the PASS Summit. I started the day on the PASS Blogger Table for the opening Keynote speech of the Summit introduced by Thomas LaRock (the current PASS president). There was a distinct shortage of Australian representatives on the table, which was soon rectified by the arrival of the one an only Rob Farley (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rob_farley&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlblog.com/blogs/rob_farley/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;), who is always amusing to listen to. To my left was one of my favourite German SQL Server experts, the ever happy Oliver Engels who was furiously typing away and in front of me Brent Ozar appeared to be switching backwards and forwards across different media platforms and applications and was no doubt constructing some interesting posts for our consumption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 days of PASS - Blogger table</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/11/05/blogger-table-day-1-thomas-larock/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 16:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/11/05/blogger-table-day-1-thomas-larock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The key note has just begun and the number of first timers standing up is quite incredible and very large. Thomas LaRock has begun the keynote speech and runs through the board of Directors and then makes a plea for people to stop by the Community Zone and connect.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some of the numbers quoted regarding the number of Chapters, SQLSaturdays and Virtual Chapters is quite staggering and demonstrates the growth of PASS today. The discussion moves to looking back at how our personal careers have grown in the last 5 years, which is interesting  because 5 years ago just pre-dates my first ever Summit, how things have changed for me back then in that time frame.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Days of PASS – Day 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/11/05/5-days-of-pass-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 13:42:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/11/05/5-days-of-pass-day-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome folks to the second enthralling instalment of 5 days of PASS! As I am sure is about to become very clear, I type with the knowledge that I have a very busy day ahead with various pieces of preparation to complete. The biggest thing that bothers me is that by the time my PASS related workload ends, so will most of the conference. This is perhaps the biggest downside to being involved in events as something more than just an attendee, since you don’t quite get to relax and do as much with your time that you would normally do and your time doesn’t really feel like your own, however if I didn’t enjoy contributing I wouldn’t do it right?!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Days of PASS – Day 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/11/04/5-days-of-pass-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 15:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/11/04/5-days-of-pass-day-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2014/taphouse_beer.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Taphouse Beer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is now the morning after the night before, having completed the official first day of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/summit/2014/Home.aspx&#34;&gt;PASS Summit 2014&lt;/a&gt;. It is nice to be back in Seattle and America after not being able to travel last year so it has been particularly great to catch up with a couple of old friends and ex-colleagues. I actually arrived in the States on Saturday evening (two days ago) where I met up with my good friend &lt;a href=&#34;https://theblobfarm.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Régis Baccaro&lt;/a&gt; at the Airport, and then later we had a nice meal and drinks with the most excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.solidq.com/rpertusa/home.aspx&#34;&gt;Ruben Pertusa Lopez&lt;/a&gt; and a bunch of other &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.solidq.com/&#34;&gt;SolidQ&lt;/a&gt; guys (at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://http://www.taphousegrill.com/&#34;&gt;Taphouse&lt;/a&gt; -of course).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Messy Meta-Described Views</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/06/18/view-pugh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 15:36:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/06/18/view-pugh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It never ceases to amaze me that there is always that little bit of SQL Server functionality that you didn’t know about. Some of it good and some of it bad, some of it just meh&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The other day I was stumbling around a new environment, when I decided to use the GUI to script out an existing set of views when I saw something that had me scratching my head. Underneath the actual view definition was the following (some names removed to protect the innocent).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who is watching the Watchmen?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/06/03/who-is-watching-the-watchmen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 17:06:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/06/03/who-is-watching-the-watchmen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2014/smiley.png&#34; alt=&#34;Watchmen&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is funny, but when I first decided to put myself forward for the Nominations Committee this year, I didn’t realize that the whole process would turn into a Campaign for Election. It really goes against much of what I stand for and is not really what I believe the Community is truly about. My involvement with community efforts, whether they be PASS related or not, are done so because I believe that my input (if required) would be beneficial to the cause that  I am offering to invest my time, efforts and possibly finances into. I am not seeking publicity, nor am I interested in promoting any personal ventures, Companies or other self-serving interests into those efforts. What I &lt;strong&gt;am&lt;/strong&gt; interested in, is that this ‘thing’ we all are part of benefits from my investment, whatever that may be. That is surely the whole purpose of being a volunteer? I volunteer my time and effort to you, so that you can benefit -not me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PASS NomCom is announced</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/05/28/your-country-needs-you-pass-nomcom-is-announced/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 21:06:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/05/28/your-country-needs-you-pass-nomcom-is-announced/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Please also check out my latest post on the NomCom election found &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/06/03/who-is-watching-the-watchmen&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t already heard, the official slate for the 2014  NomCom committee has been finalized and published by the Professional Association for SQL Server (that’s PASS to you and me) and can be found on their website via this &lt;a href=&#34;https://bit.ly/SfTpBD&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;. You can check out the list of 11 candidates (and how to vote) in which I am very pleased to announce I am one of them having decided to put myself forward this year for reasons that will become clearer in future posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 reasons why I HA-te you!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/04/25/10-reasons-why-i-hate-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 08:33:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/04/25/10-reasons-why-i-hate-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Designing, planning, deploying, administrating and recovering (known from now on as &lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;e&lt;strong&gt;P&lt;/strong&gt;lan&lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;e&lt;strong&gt;AR&lt;/strong&gt; – and pronounced in the tone of a Caribbean Grandma 🙂 ) a SQL Server High Availability and Disaster Recovery (HADR) solution is really not an easy thing to implement and maintain. There are many reasons for this and whilst (ultimately) our business is only interested in an almost permanent unbroken connectivity to the Database Engine for its Applications or Middleware Clients, the reality is that our databases/s play just a very small part of the whole availability story when maintaining one of these solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside SQLSaturday: Lisbon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/04/07/inside-sqlsaturday-niko-neugebauer-sqlsaturday-lisbon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 13:32:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/04/07/inside-sqlsaturday-niko-neugebauer-sqlsaturday-lisbon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2014/sintra.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Sintra&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;The beautiful Sintra&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Inside SQLSaturday, and today I am joined by Portugal’s very own Niko Neugebauer (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nikoport.com/&#34;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/NikoNeugebauer&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Niko is the event lead to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlsaturday.com/267/eventhome.aspx&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Lisbon&lt;/a&gt; which holds the honour of being the first SQLSaturday &lt;strong&gt;ever&lt;/strong&gt; to be held outside of the United States and the launch pad for so many other great events to follow around the world. Along with his team, they run a selection of Community events and innovative initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ROLLBACK damn you!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/03/05/rollback-damn-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 09:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/03/05/rollback-damn-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A good question was asked on #SQLHELP the other day regarding the use of &lt;code&gt;XACT_ABORT ON&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have a &lt;code&gt;BEGIN TRAN COMMIT TRAN&lt;/code&gt; in a stored procedure, will SET XACT_ABORT ON do anything?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My immediate reply to this was:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes it makes the transaction atomic. See my blog post &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/10/23/baby-baby-baby-where-did-our-love-data-go&#34;&gt;Baby baby baby, where did our ROLLBACK go?&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In response to this, the follow-up question was raised:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;wouldn’t executing the stored procedure by itself be atomic?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLBits 12 Announced!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/03/04/twelve-is-a-magic-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 09:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/03/04/twelve-is-a-magic-number/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2014/coltsfoot_rock_small.png&#34; alt=&#34;Coltsfoot Rock&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A massive congratulations to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlbits.com/&#34;&gt;SQLBits&lt;/a&gt; team for announcing what will become the 12th iteration of the UKs finest and largest SQL Server conference. Putting on events at this scale by such a small core team demands huge respect and I sincerely thank them for doing so. I have personally learnt a ton of information and grown as a person and as a SQL Professional because of their efforts and I know many others in the industry feel the same way too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Read your old CHM files from network storage on Windows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/02/11/read-your-old-chm-files-from-network-storage-on-windows-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 12:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014/02/11/read-your-old-chm-files-from-network-storage-on-windows-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was just recently going through my old SQL Server documents and reference material and attempting to organize and tidy things up, when I re-discovered a huge collection of literature that even now is incredibly useful. The only problem is that many of these old electronic books and files are stored in &lt;em&gt;CHM&lt;/em&gt; format. Those old timers of you will remember that this was how SQL Server Books online was deployed up to and including SQL Server 2000.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLSaturday Cambridge raises £££ for charity!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013/09/29/sqlsaturday-cambridge-raises-for-charity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 20:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013/09/29/sqlsaturday-cambridge-raises-for-charity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are very pleased to announce that the final figures of the SQLSaturday Cambridge fundraising has been counted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some of you will know that we were collecting for Children’s Cancer Charity &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.younglivesvscancer.org.uk/&#34;&gt;CLIC Sargent&lt;/a&gt; and the reasons why we were doing this can be understood by reading my previous post &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/2013/09/25/change-your-event-and-make-a-difference&#34;&gt;Change (your event) and make a difference!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The amount collected at the event through various different means amounts to &lt;strong&gt;£490.03&lt;/strong&gt;!!!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SQLSaturday Cambridge are therefore honoring our commitment to match this figure, which means that &lt;mark&gt;we are therfore donating a grand total of £980.06 to charity&lt;/mark&gt;. I’m hoping to write a bit more about this further in due course.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Change (your event) and make a difference!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013/09/25/change-your-event-and-make-a-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 22:52:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013/09/25/change-your-event-and-make-a-difference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Regular readers may remember a post I wrote many moons ago in which I described just how exactly &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/05/04/change-and-make-a-difference&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Cambridge started&lt;/a&gt; and hopefully gave a lesson in why we should all attempt to grow as much as possible as individuals and embrace (unforeseen) opportunities, as and when they appear. These days I suppose you could describe me as a seasoned presenter (note: seasoning doesn’t necessarily equal good 🙂) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlsaturday.com/228/eventhome.aspx&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Cambridge&lt;/a&gt; is soon to celebrate its second birthday and outing this coming Friday and Saturday. I know I have only just scratched the surface of what I could become and what I would like to be and that I only have myself and genetic limitations to get in the way of my &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;enlightenment&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why don’t you go and LOCK OFF!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013/07/17/why-dont-you-go-and-lock-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 13:44:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013/07/17/why-dont-you-go-and-lock-off/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No this is not a Hekaton post 🙂 -perhaps I should have saved this title for another rainy day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SQL Server concurrency is a particularly difficult subject to master and understanding the result of your actions can be confounded by some of SQL Server’s special behaviors and quirks that I so often like to talk and write about.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As some of my &lt;del&gt;followers&lt;/del&gt; stalkers out there may remember, one of my favorite demonstrations I like to give is during my&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/summit/2012/Sessions/SessionDetails.aspx?sid=2816&#34;&gt;READPAST &amp;amp; Furious: Transactions, Locking, and Isolation&lt;/a&gt; session -last performed at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/summit/2012/&#34;&gt;SQLPASS 2012 Summit&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlsaturday.com/viewsession.aspx?sat=229&amp;amp;sessionid=14975&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday #229 Dublin&lt;/a&gt; where in a little piece of code I discuss whether a transaction is really Atomic (or not). For anyone reading this paragraph who has immediately answered “ALWAYS” -then my friend you are in serious trouble with your code-base. And I am not even talking about the use of lower levels of isolation to perform dirty reads within your transaction here, isolation does not effect a transaction’s atomicity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Countdown to SQLSaturday Edinburgh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013/06/06/countdown-to-sqlsaturday-edinburgh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 10:25:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013/06/06/countdown-to-sqlsaturday-edinburgh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2013/xeventjonathan2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jonathan Kehayias&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;A pre-conference good enough for Super heros&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In exactly 2 days time the United Kingdom’s 3rd SQLSaturday will be in full swing, showcasing a group of SQL Server MVPs, MCMs and Community experts. This will be the very first time that SQLSaturday has happened in Scotland and it is going to be fantastic to bolster the PASS membership and exposure in that area which can only good news for all concerned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selected again for the PASS Summit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013/05/22/see-you-in-charlotte/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 15:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013/05/22/see-you-in-charlotte/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well it is that time of year again where the results of the PASS Summit 2013 session selections become public. This year was of course a very difficult one to get selected since (I believe) a record number of submissions were received -but thankfully I still managed to knock one session (out of four) into the back of the net. I would also like to take this opportunity to congratulate all the other selected Speakers (especially if this is your first time at the Summit) and commiserations to all those who were not successful on this occasion. I know the usual inquests and finger pointing will naturally ensue by a small handful of people who feel personally aggrieved that they weren’t successful, but believe me when I say that the process is as fair as I could expect, but not without room for improvement (more on this very soon in a follow up post).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I love SQLBits</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013/04/09/t-sql-tuesday-41-i--sqlbits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 21:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013/04/09/t-sql-tuesday-41-i--sqlbits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/shared/tsql2sday150x15032.webp&#34; alt=&#34;TSQL Tuesday&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long time since I last wrote a T-SQL Tuesday post but the combination of a great topic along with a spare 5 minutes of downtime has resulted in my contribution to the mix this month.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This time around T-SQL Tuesday is hosted by Bob Pusateri (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bobpusateri.com/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SQLBob&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;) and his chosen topic is &lt;strong&gt;how did you come to love presenting?&lt;/strong&gt;. So here goes…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2010 I had traveled to my very first conference as a presenter. So there I was, stood on the stage in front of a motley collection of SQL professionals, realizing the enormity of what was about to happen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to run SQL Server 2012 on the Kindle Fire HD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013/04/01/how-to-run-sql-server-2012-on-the-kindle-fire-hd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 12:44:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013/04/01/how-to-run-sql-server-2012-on-the-kindle-fire-hd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;Warning! Please do not attempt to perform any of the following steps on production systems. This information is provided purely for reference and any attempt to replicate these actions on your own hardware will be purely at your own risk!&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest benefits to the latest release of SQL Server (and reasons to upgrade) is that Windows Server Core is now a supported option. For those of you who are not yet familiar with Server Core, it could be best described as a reduced GUI version of Microsoft Windows. In other words, if you like the command line then you are in for a very big treat! Regular visitors to these pages will most likely be very aware of my passion for Windows Server Core and more to the point running SQL Server on it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upload files to your Azure VM instance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013/03/20/upload-files-to-your-azure-vm-instance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 17:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013/03/20/upload-files-to-your-azure-vm-instance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes some of the simplest tips are the best, and recently I was trying to figure out just how to upload SQL Server 2012 Enterprise/ Developer Edition installation files to my Windows Azure Virtual Machine since my pre-provisioned copy of SQL Server (Evaluation Edition) had expired.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As it turned out I realized pretty quickly that I didn’t need to bother since the VM also comes with a copy of SQL Server 2012 Evaluation Edition media pre-loaded at the root of the &lt;em&gt;C:\&lt;/em&gt; drive. All I had to do therefore was to grab an existing Developer Edition license key and run the Evaluation Edition media setup and step through the Edition Upgrade to &lt;em&gt;convert&lt;/em&gt; my existing instance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My recent achievements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/12/23/santa-comes-early/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2012 09:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/12/23/santa-comes-early/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2012/kumar_christmas_smaller.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kumar Christmas&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With days to go before Santa boards his sleigh and pulls back on the reigns tethering his trusty magical flying reindeer to perform what is probably the most incredible feat of logistical planning and execution the world has ever seen, I can look back on the last few months with surprise, satisfaction and appreciation and thank those people who have helped to make my run up to Christmas an extremely rewarding and happy affair.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baby baby baby, where did our ROLLBACK go?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/10/23/baby-baby-baby-where-did-our-love-data-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2012 22:51:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/10/23/baby-baby-baby-where-did-our-love-data-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2012/frankiesays.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Frankie Says Relax&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Possibly one of the very first things we learn as fledgling DBA’s is that transactions are used to provide &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;all or nothing&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; operations. If you ever go for a SQL Server job interview, you are almost guaranteed to be asked exactly what constitutes the ACID properties (&lt;strong&gt;groan&lt;/strong&gt;). The A in ACID is of course Atomicity and basically represents the fact that a given set of operations within a transaction either succeeds as an atomic unit OR it doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Curious Case of the Non-Escalating transaction locks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/10/17/the-curious-case-of-the-non-escalating-transaction-locks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 13:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/10/17/the-curious-case-of-the-non-escalating-transaction-locks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SQL Server has many facets and behaviors that are often misunderstood and do not always work quite as we may have expected. At first you may believe that you understand the mechanics, only to realize after a little bit of delving deeper that your comprehension was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SQL Server Lock Escalation is one of these commonly misunderstood topics, and most recently after doing a little investigation into a few subjects related to escalation I was shocked and surprised in equal measure to find that things were not working quite as I expected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memoirs of SQLSaturday Cambridge #162 - Speaker Dinner</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/10/01/memoirs-of-sqlsaturday-162-part-ii-speaker-dinner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 18:11:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/10/01/memoirs-of-sqlsaturday-162-part-ii-speaker-dinner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Probably one of the most over-looked parts of any big or small SQL Event can sometimes be the speaker dinner -which essentially boils down to one thing… the organisers way of showing their appreciation to the speakers who have traveled far and wide usually at their own expense to present expert technical content at no cost to the attendees.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a fairly regular speaker myself, I have experienced many events who have either made very little effort with the dinner, poorly handled its organization (meaning many speakers aren’t even informed that it is happening) or simply don’t bother arranging one at all. And whilst I don’t want to suggest that by organizing an event you absolutely &lt;em&gt;MUST&lt;/em&gt; provide a speaker dinner in order for the event to be regarded as a success, I do personally feel that the speaker meal helps define your event and give it a &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; or your &lt;em&gt;stamp of identity&lt;/em&gt; -and hopefully one along the lines that you were aiming for.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using the SQL Server Installation Wizard on Server Core!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/09/19/using-the-sql-server-installation-wizard-on-server-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 18:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/09/19/using-the-sql-server-installation-wizard-on-server-core/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever heard the phrase &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;just because you can, doesn’t mean you should?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. Yep me too -many times, and what I am about to say comes with that caveat in mind although as I shall explain, I see absolutely no reason why you shouldn’t -certainly not in a development environment OR using this technique to produce a configuration installation file. But I’m getting ahead of myself, first let me describe our scenario.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memoirs of SQLSaturday Cambridge #162 - Precons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/09/12/memoirs-of-sqlsaturday-162-part-i-pre-cons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 11:26:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/09/12/memoirs-of-sqlsaturday-162-part-i-pre-cons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Days have passed since we closed the first ever SQLSaturday to hit the shores of the UK and I write with an element of sadness that it is over, relief that my time can start to be more of my own again for other projects, and optimism of what may come.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I first set out on the path of recording what I view as very much a mixture of personal and technical journal in the pages of this blog (and hopefully at times a good resource for others), I always intended to write at least one post per month. I always viewed it as a cardinal sin to let things slip, but unfortunately I truly underestimated the enormity of the work involved in planning, implementing and executing a major IT event. Now it is almost over (there are still many small administrative issues to complete) I think it is fair to say that Team &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlsaturday.com/162/eventhome.aspx&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday #162 Cambridge&lt;/a&gt; are able to take a deep breath and be proud of what we did.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Change and make a difference</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/05/04/change-and-make-a-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 18:03:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/05/04/change-and-make-a-difference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let me tell you a story&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2012/sqlsat162_print_small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SQLSaturday #162 Cambridge&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is a drizzly night in November and I am sat with a bunch of people I have never met before. They are all eating and I am not (one too many Whiskys the night before). They all appear to know each other and are vigorously moving from subject to subject with enthusiasm and I am listening intently to the conversation but not really saying too much.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remember your OS when upgrading to SQL 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/04/24/remember-your-os-when-upgrading-to-sql-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2012 19:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/04/24/remember-your-os-when-upgrading-to-sql-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Probably as far back as the end of last year when I first started putting material together for my Enter the Dragon and Moves like Jagger presentations and giving very early mash up presentations of them combined together, I started emphasising one very important upgrade consideration which is very often ignored. It is also a fact that is quite nicely touched upon by Glenn Berry (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/glennalanberry&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlserverperformance.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;) in his excellent book SQL Server Hardware and if you have yet to discover its unique delights then I strongly advise you to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>whoisactive on SQL 2000</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/04/17/whos-active-on-sql-2000/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2012 18:38:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/04/17/whos-active-on-sql-2000/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yes yes yes I &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; we are currently on SQL 2012 but just hear me out for a second…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think I am probably one of the only people on the planet who has not (yet) used Adam Machanic’s (&lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlblog.com/blogs/adam_machanic/default.aspx&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlblog.com/blogs/adam_machanic/archive/2011/04/27/who-is-active-v11-00-a-month-of-activity-monitoring-part-27-of-30.aspx&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;) whoisactive Stored Procedure. One of the reasons for this is that going right back to the days of SQL Server 2000 I had rolled my own stored procedure which worked very nicely and did everything that I ever needed it to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schedule so far</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/04/13/schedule-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 19:24:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/04/13/schedule-so-far/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I have been starting to get a little stressed about whether or not I have a speaking engagement coming up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whilst I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/calendar&#34;&gt;Google Calendar&lt;/a&gt; and most recently have set up a premium &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rememberthemilk.com/&#34;&gt;Remember the Milk&lt;/a&gt; account to organise my life a little better, I thought it was probably a good idea to see where I am with my past and forth coming presentations for the first half of this year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weight doesnt ALWAYS have to be AlwaysOn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/04/05/weight-doesnt-always-have-to-be-alwayson/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 15:56:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/04/05/weight-doesnt-always-have-to-be-alwayson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One thing I keep hearing myself mentioning more and more in conversation (and most recently in a discussion group at &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlbits.com/&#34;&gt;SQLBits&lt;/a&gt; a few days ago) is the ability to configure your Windows Cluster Quorum for situations where each cluster node may not be of equal importance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/sqlserver/en/us/default.aspx&#34;&gt;SQL Server 2012&lt;/a&gt; we have various high availability enhancements and improvements and most of these are branded under the term &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/sqlserver/en/us/solutions-technologies/mission-critical-operations/SQL-Server-2012-high-availability.aspx&#34;&gt;AlwaysOn&lt;/a&gt;. In particular we have enhancements to AlwaysOn SQL Failover Clustering and a new technology known as AlwaysOn Availability Groups. Whilst I won’t bore you with any specific details about what these are or how to use them -since that is no doubt something for another day, you may probably be already aware that for both, each require the existence of a Windows Cluster in order to use them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presenting Moves Like Jagger – my 24HOP baptism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/03/26/moves-like-jagger-my-24hop-baptism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 15:07:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/03/26/moves-like-jagger-my-24hop-baptism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is now nearly one week since my début on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/24hours/spring2012/Home.aspx&#34;&gt;24 Hours Of PASS&lt;/a&gt; and I thought it would be useful for people considering presenting on 24HOP themselves that I write my thoughts on the whole experience. I have also taken the liberty to publish in advance my &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/documents/24hoursofpassppt_moves_like_jagger.pdf&#34;&gt;slide deck&lt;/a&gt;) whilst I have managed to catch a rare quiet period.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have been very lucky over the last couple of years to have presented many times to a selection of large and small events around the world and yet as nearly all presenters will tell you, we are always still learning the craft. Every event is a new experience, every delivery is different and perfection is always a distant and impossible dream. So although the prospect of talking to an audience was in itself not a particular problem, the difference in delivery medium, scale and truly International audience meant that the whole ball-game had totally changed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to remove your VirtualBox machines BLOAT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/03/14/how-to-remove-you-virtual-machines-bloat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2012 12:43:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/03/14/how-to-remove-you-virtual-machines-bloat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well I guess its been a long time since I have offered you a useful nugget of information or help, so I have decided to haul myself to the keyboard and provide a useful tip that I have been saving for a rainy day. Regular readers to this blog will certainly be no stranger to my positively strong feelings towards Oracle’s VirtualBox and I have been a user of this product for more years than I can remember. The tip I am about to describe will use VirtualBox in the examples but it should be transferable to any virtualisation product that has the ability to shrink back virtual disks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Hours Of PASS goes multi-lingual</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/02/16/i-can-speak-english-i-learn-it-from-a-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2012 21:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/02/16/i-can-speak-english-i-learn-it-from-a-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many many years ago when I was still in short trousers I started to take an interest in Movies. My parents had completely different sleeping patterns and my Father was an irritatingly early riser -a fact that would irritate me right into my adolescence and beyond. My mother was the opposite and (like me) very much a night owl. This resulted in there being a period of around 3 to 4 hours before my Mother went to bed, where the Television would be switched to whatever channel she wanted to watch -in other words &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; Sport.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What are the impersonation rights for my database users?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/01/30/what-are-the-impersonation-rights-for-my-database-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 14:29:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/01/30/what-are-the-impersonation-rights-for-my-database-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From time to time I get thrown the odd request to provide various bits of information from the SQL Server environment and most recently I was asked about a group of databases that required migrating to another instance. For some reason there had been a little bit of a panic about the impersonation rights in each of the databases and their configuration. The request was &lt;em&gt;*ahem*&lt;/em&gt; kindly passed to me. The number of database users was huge in each database and performing a manual lookup through the SSMS GUI got rather tiresome very quickly (after about the second user).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLRally and Beyond</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/01/25/sqlrally-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 02:06:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2012/01/25/sqlrally-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am almost ashamed to say that I have let over a month pass since my last post and truth be told I have come close a few times without never actually pressing that submit button.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I shan&amp;rsquo;t bore you with my excuses or reasons for my inactivity but what matters is I&amp;rsquo;m back!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been seeing an increasing amount of noise about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sqlpass.org/sqlrally/2012/dallas/&#34;&gt;SQLRally Dallas&lt;/a&gt; and I felt that I wanted to share my own personal experience with you about this rather unique event (in Orlando) -for it quite literary changed my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visualising disk space usage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/12/13/t-sql-tuesday-25-the-best-tool-youve-never-used/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 22:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/12/13/t-sql-tuesday-25-the-best-tool-youve-never-used/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/shared/tsql2sday150x15032.webp&#34; alt=&#34;T-SQL Tuesday&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wow, it&amp;rsquo;s been a long time since my last T-SQL Tuesday post and I have disappointingly missed it 5 times for one reason or another. Still, the important thing is that I am back people!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This month&amp;rsquo;s T-SQL Tuesday is brought to you by Allen White (&lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlblog.com/blogs/allen_white/default.aspx&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SQLRunr&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;) who many of you will know for his PowerShell, SMO and SQL Server expertise.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ironically for this post (or the subject at least) I was saving up towards a larger Data Visualisation article that I was putting together, but when I read the subject of this months T-SQL Tuesday I just knew it was time to spill the beans.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keep your Availability Group listener name short</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/11/25/lets-keep-it-short-problem-creating-availability-group-listeners/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2011 00:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/11/25/lets-keep-it-short-problem-creating-availability-group-listeners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Someone once said to me that he thought I should work as a GUI tester since I always seemed to find problems in the UI -after I had highlighted a problem to him that I&amp;rsquo;d found in Linux Gnome which he had never seen before &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;after all his years working with the product&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. I guess there is an element of truth to that statement since I really do like clicking around and trying different things. However I suspect that my latest discovery won&amp;rsquo;t necessarily be one of those obscure problems that no-one else comes across since it is such an obvious problem and fairly easy to run into.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lock Compatibility Matrix 1.2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/11/17/compatibility-matrix-1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 22:29:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/11/17/compatibility-matrix-1-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of months back I published my version of SQL Server&amp;rsquo;s Lock Compatibility Matrix under the post &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/09/27/fancy-a-decent-compatibility-matrix&#34;&gt;Fancy a decent Compatibility Matrix?&lt;/a&gt; since the one provided by MSDN is really very poorly designed and difficult for the average Joe to understand.This is one reason I believe that lock compatibility is a very misunderstood subject.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One thing that has bothered me about my version from the very beginning was the use of green and red to respectively indicate compatible or incompatible locks. The reason this has bothered me from the offset is because I was aware that those two colours could be a very big problem for colour blind DBAs. However, for me they really DID look great together and &lt;em&gt;told the story&lt;/em&gt; of the compatibility between the locks without even needing words -every (non colour blind) person understands the concept of GREEN -&amp;gt; GO (i.e. lock grant), RED -&amp;gt; STOP (i.e. lock wait). BUT that doesn&amp;rsquo;t help colour blind people very much does it!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cambridgeshire SQL Server User Group joins PASS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/10/24/pass-the-dutchie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 11:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/10/24/pass-the-dutchie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anyone old enough to remember this song from the eighties will remember the catchy lyrics and tune:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pass the Duchie pon the left hand side pass the Duchie pon the left hand side&amp;hellip; It gonna burn&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;Ah yes, I&amp;rsquo;ve now got my foot tapping away remembering the good old days of my youth :). The song (as some of you will be aware) is about passing a cooking pot around and sharing food with each other, but the more astute of you will know that it was based upon a track titled &lt;em&gt;Pass the Kouchie&lt;/em&gt; -a ditty about smoking cannabis! &lt;sub&gt;*1&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NOLOCK hits Mythbusters!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/10/14/nolock-hits-mythbusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 15:59:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/10/14/nolock-hits-mythbusters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Exactly one month to this very day I wrote the article &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/09/14/when-should-you-use-nolock&#34;&gt;When should you use NOLOCK?&lt;/a&gt; which explained exactly when the use of the &lt;code&gt;READUNCOMMITTED&lt;/code&gt; isolation level was acceptable and when it wasn&amp;rsquo;t. I also revealed that it not only takes out a &lt;em&gt;Schema Stability (Sch-S)&lt;/em&gt; lock on the object (which is documented in Books Online for the hint) but also took out a special &lt;em&gt;Shared (S) Bulk Operation&lt;/em&gt; lock when used on heaps. This latter behaviour is not even mentioned in Books Online for the hint and as far as I know, has never been documented or mentioned anywhere else before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At the Bloggers Table - Post 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/10/12/community-is-driving-sql-to-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 08:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/10/12/community-is-driving-sql-to-success/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well the keynote speech has begun, Ted Kummert is on stage and the focus at the beginning has been very much on the Community and SQL Azure. It is clear to me that Microsoft recognize the value of our amazing community -and they should because together we are helping to shape that future of this product into something that is becoming truly amazing. There was a time when Oracle DBA&amp;rsquo;s used to look down on SQL Server, but now they are worried and are desperately trying to get up to speed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At the Bloggers Table - Post 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/10/12/my-alarm-clock-worked/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 07:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/10/12/my-alarm-clock-worked/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well the good news is my alarm clock worked!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So the time is around 7:30 am and I managed to get out of bed for my second official appointment of the PASS Summit 2011 and things are getting warmed up. I&amp;rsquo;m sat here on the front row of the Blogger table whilst to my left I have Brent Ozar, Aaron Bertrand and to my right Wes Brown and the Midnight DBA&amp;rsquo;s. If that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough in front of me I have Stacia Misner and behind me I have Wendy Dance and Glen Berry! I don&amp;rsquo;t know how I managed this gig but it feels really good and it is an absolute pleasure to be part of it all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Im gonna be on the Bloggers Table!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/10/09/im-gonna-be-on-the-bloggers-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2011 20:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/10/09/im-gonna-be-on-the-bloggers-table/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m currently sat here in the lounge of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.marriott.com/en-us/hotels/seasi-sheraton-grand-seattle/overview/&#34;&gt;Seattle Sheraton&lt;/a&gt; and finally have time to reflect upon my week ahead here at this years &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/summit/2011/&#34;&gt;SQLPASS Summit&lt;/a&gt;. At this point in time it is very hard to say exactly how busy I am going to be this week but I suspect that my time here will be slightly more focused than last time since I have a few more responsibilities than before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLBits 9 Slidedeck for READPAST &amp; Furious</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/10/03/sqlbits-9-slidedeck-for-readpast-furious/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 16:13:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/10/03/sqlbits-9-slidedeck-for-readpast-furious/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am very pleased to publish the slide-deck for my Friday presentation &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlbits.com/Sessions/Event9/READPAST__Furious_Transactions_Locking_and_Isolation&#34;&gt;READPAST &amp;amp; Furious: Transactions, Locking and Isolation&lt;/a&gt;. Just click &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/documents/readpastfurious.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to obtain the slide-deck in PDF format.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had an absolutely fantastic time giving the presentation and really enjoyed the audience participation (though it took some of you guys a bit of time to warm up 🙂). No seriously, the thing that makes all those weeks/ months of preparation and collation of material worthwhile is the possibility that I have managed to communicate something of value to you all -and &lt;em&gt;hopefully&lt;/em&gt; I managed to do that. I learnt a massive amount of stuff myself in the process of preparing for this session and I cannot wait for the next time (whenever this may be).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fancy a decent Compatibility Matrix?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/09/27/fancy-a-decent-compatibility-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 21:12:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/09/27/fancy-a-decent-compatibility-matrix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever taken a look at Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s published &lt;a href=&#34;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms186396.aspx&#34;&gt;compatibility matrix&lt;/a&gt; for SQL Server lock compatibility? If you have, then I don&amp;rsquo;t need to tell you that it sucks in a very big way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have no fear, I have painstakingly redrawn at better one (via PowerPoint no less!) and am making available to you totally free of charge as a lovely PDF slide found via &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/documents/readpastfuriouslockcompatibilitymatrix.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip; Why you ask? Because I love you all!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When should you use NOLOCK?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/09/14/when-should-you-use-nolock/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 12:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/09/14/when-should-you-use-nolock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well the quick answer to that question is never. And there you have it, the quickest blog post in history (perhaps!).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;Except that I should really have said &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;When should you use &lt;code&gt;READUNCOMMITTED&lt;/code&gt; isolation or hint?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; and then the question takes a little more of a surprising turn. Let me first start and explain why I have categorically ruled against the use of &lt;code&gt;NOLOCK&lt;/code&gt;. The reason, is that at some point in the dim and distant future Microsoft may decide to remove this hint from the product. If they could do it today, they probably would; the only thing that is really stopping them is the numerous lines of external T-SQL code that dirtys the floors of many Development teams around the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to increase your OS Virtual Processors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/08/30/how-to-increase-your-virtual-processors-in-the-os/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2011 22:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/08/30/how-to-increase-your-virtual-processors-in-the-os/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There usually comes a time in your Virtual Machine life-cycle that you think&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;I wish I&amp;rsquo;d given that baby more processors for me to play with!&lt;/em&gt; This is especially true if the Virtual Machine in question is your little plaything that you use to test out funky stuff using parallelism and allows you to play with various SQL Server settings and functionality such as &lt;em&gt;Processor Affinity&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;MAXDOP&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So there was a time in the dark and distant past when wanting to increase your processor count for your OS would mean a reinstall. Thankfully, this is no longer necessary and once you have performed this operation once you will never forget. So here goes&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of Inside the SQL Server Query Optimizer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/08/19/inside-the-sql-server-query-optimizer-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2011 14:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/08/19/inside-the-sql-server-query-optimizer-book-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Inside-SQL-Server-Query-Optimizer/dp/1906434603&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2011/insidequerysmall.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Inside the SQL Server Query Optimizer&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are only a handful of people that when they talk about something you should sit up and take notice, and for me Benjamin Nevarez (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.benjaminnevarez.com/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/BenjaminNevarez&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;) is one of those. As someone I&amp;rsquo;ve been following technically for several years, when I saw that his book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Inside-SQL-Server-Query-Optimizer/dp/1906434603&#34;&gt;Inside the SQL Server Query Optimizer&lt;/a&gt; had been released to the Kindle format, I immediately clicked the purchase button and I haven&amp;rsquo;t been disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Standing upon the shoulders of Giants</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/08/01/standing-upon-the-shoulders-of-giants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 13:42:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/08/01/standing-upon-the-shoulders-of-giants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the very late nineties and early naughties I used to co-habit the Microsoft Newsgroups (which was then located at &lt;em&gt;news.microsoft.com&lt;/em&gt; over the NNTP protocol), and in particular I posted primarily on the SQL Server forums to help others where I could. A by product of my helping out was of course learning lots of hints, tips and best practices from other users and there is a lesson in that for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sun isnt shining for the Solstice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/07/31/the-sun-isnt-shining-for-the-solstice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 20:36:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/07/31/the-sun-isnt-shining-for-the-solstice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So today I was surprised (slightly) to pick up a tweet by the excellent Grant Fritchey (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scarydba.com/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/gfritchey&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;) regarding the fact that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlsolstice.com/&#34;&gt;SQL Solstice&lt;/a&gt; had been cancelled due to a lack of interest. I say that I was only slightly surprised for a few reasons. The first is that the event was a new initiative and just by that very fact, was never going to be a certainty. Secondly, the United States is no stranger to SQL events. Not only do they host the largest SQL Server convention in the world (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/summit/2011/&#34;&gt;SQL PASS Summit&lt;/a&gt;), but have also a new initiative called SQLRally, in which I was lucky enough to speak at the inaugural event in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/sqlrally/2011/orlando/&#34;&gt;Orlando&lt;/a&gt; this May just past. I believe the intention for SQLRally is for it to rotate bi-yearly between the States and Europe and the success of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/sqlrally/2011/nordic/&#34;&gt;SQLRally Nordic&lt;/a&gt; will (I believe) be the making or death of that initiative. I personally believe SQLRally is work in progress and will become a great success over time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Database corruption - Your mistake, my problem!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/06/14/t-sql-tuesday-19-your-mistake-my-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2011 08:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/06/14/t-sql-tuesday-19-your-mistake-my-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/shared/tsql2sday150x15032.webp&#34; alt=&#34;TSQL Tuesday&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This month&amp;rsquo;s T-SQL Tuesday is brought to you by Allen Kinsel (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.allenkinsel.com&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sqlinsaneo&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;) who contributes a great amount of his time to the SQL Community and so we can only say a huge thank you for your efforts and keep up the good work! I&amp;rsquo;ve not been able to participate in T-SQL Tuesday for a while so it is good to catch this one which is made easier by keeping a close eye on what Rob Farley (&lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlblog.com/blogs/rob_farley/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rob_farley&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;) is up to because he is always on time every time! Here&amp;rsquo;s my entry&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Add metadata to your audio files</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/06/09/add-meta-to-your-audio-training-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 20:07:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/06/09/add-meta-to-your-audio-training-files/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my recent post &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/06/07/how-to-rip-audio-from-your-training-videos.md&#34;&gt;How to rip audio from your training videos&lt;/a&gt; I gave Linux a very big thumbs up for providing users with a very easy (free and fast) route to rip audio from our SQL Server training videos. Now as much as I like Linux, it is not the answer to every single problem. In fact it is undeniable that Microsoft has established Windows as a platform of choice for many very polished and useful third party applications -free or otherwise. Sometimes finding open source equivalents on Linux can be a real pain in the posterior since the reality is that every now and again the best application is a Windows application (take SQL Server as an example 🙂) and the application I will demonstrate today is exactly that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to rip audio from your training videos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/06/07/how-to-rip-audio-from-your-training-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 20:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/06/07/how-to-rip-audio-from-your-training-videos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; Although the following post is Linux related my dear SQL Server geek, you might just find what I am about to say useful in your pursuit of SQL Server greatness. If this possibility doesn&amp;rsquo;t interest you then I advise to stop reading right&amp;hellip; now!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t normally publish short blog posts and as a result, when I am really busy, it means nothing gets posted due to the large amount of time the bigger articles take. However from time to time I see something that I really want to shout about and this is one of those times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using SQL Server Scalable Shared Database</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/05/25/sqlrally-scalable-shared-database-demo-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 23:24:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/05/25/sqlrally-scalable-shared-database-demo-redux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2011/orders.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation slide&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several weeks ago now I had the honour of presenting at the very first ever SQLRally event in Orlando Florida and I gave a presentation around the very large (no pun intended) subject of scaling out your SQL Server data. At the end of one of my demos it unfortunately crashed and burned and the annoying thing was, that up to then it had worked flawlessly!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem that I hit in the demo was (I believe) related to a virtual machine crash that had happened the previous evening and I don&amp;rsquo;t think I allowed the database to run through recovery the following day. I am presuming that my iSCSI targets were not connected to my SQL Server on startup which meant that the database in question which was located on my shared drive still needed to run through recovery and couldn&amp;rsquo;t because I had (as part of the demo) changed the attribute of the drive to read-only in order to prepare it for the next stage. The error was suggesting that there was a version compatibility problem between the two instances and I had several members of the audience suggesting that this was the problem when I knew the versions were identical. Disappointingly, we were so short of time that I needed to move on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The real value of attending SQLRally</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/05/18/the-real-value-of-attending-sqlrally/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 18:43:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/05/18/the-real-value-of-attending-sqlrally/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(This post was written primarily whilst travelling back from SQLRally and subsequently edited, amended and added to where necessary before publishing)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently sat here at Orlando Airport and I am able to reflect a little bit whilst waiting to board my plane back to the U.K. after having spent the last 5 days of preparation, learning and socialising at SQLRally and I need to ask myself &lt;em&gt;was it worth the expense?&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m not too sure how many attendees or indeed speakers were from Europe but I am pretty sure I was one of a very small number and therefore the cost to myself was indeed far more than it would have cost for the majority of the attendees. It is therefore important that I look at the return on investment of not just my attending the event, but also of me speaking. One key thing to remember about going to conferences, is that the knowledge &lt;em&gt;retained&lt;/em&gt; is usually very little of what you have actually heard but hopefully with the efforts of the presenters, the materials provided will help to reinforce the important parts of this knowledge. It is true that I went to some excellent presentations but was sadly unable to attend many of them due to the amount of work I felt I needed to do on the preparation of my own session since I was really not quite happy where I was at. This particular point is a key take home for me, and I &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; now ensure that I am far more prepared going forward. Unfortunately due to working commitments, family and other events it is sometimes easier said than done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLBits 8 - a presenters review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/20/sqlbits-8-finis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 15:42:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/20/sqlbits-8-finis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly two weeks has passed after another SQLBits and what another fabulous event. After an incredibly early morning train journey down to Brighton for the excellent Thursday training session with Thomas Kejser and an enjoyable time presenting my &lt;em&gt;SQL Server Clustering for Dummies&lt;/em&gt; session I am well and truly back down to earth with a thump.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Personal highs for me were:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally getting to meet Allan Hirt and not only that but I had a Geo-Cluster debate with him in the speaker room.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meeting a few of the new first time SQLBits speakers -in particular Atul Thakor (blog|twitter) who I had a very long chat with in the speaker room and on the morning before his presentation. He had run into lots of problems with his laptop and demos prior to his session -which can strike the best of us, but managed to keep his wits about him an plow onto success when he finally came to present. What a top guy, and look forward to meeting him again in a User Group or another conference.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Recognizing some audience members in my Clustering for Dummies session from my SQLBits 7 session. I ran into a couple of them later on and said a big thanks for the support, gave them my personal email and very much hope they do drop me a mail sometime to say hello.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bumping into some old faces&amp;hellip;people I&amp;rsquo;ve met in Seattle, previous UK conferences and User Groups and old colleagues. A special big-up to Judith Kinsella who made the effort to come to my presentation (which threw me when I saw her in the audience), although she keeps telling me that I remind her of John Peel and just can&amp;rsquo;t take me seriously 🙂🙂🙂&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Being able to enjoy the experience a little more, due to familiarity of proceedings. Anyone who presents at a major conference for the first time will tell you that it is all a bit of a daze, stressful and is a big unknown what you have let yourself in for. This time I knew what to expect, what I was doing and what I needed to do.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Seeing some great presentations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Excellent weather!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2011/introduction.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mark Broadbent Introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;In full flow!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to run SQL Server on Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/01/how-to-run-sql-server-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 14:51:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/01/how-to-run-sql-server-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE 2011-04-10: PLEASE NOTE THIS WAS AN APRILS FOOL JOKE 🙂&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well I have finally cracked it, after years of trying (and a little help from the R2 release) to get SQL Server to install and run happily on the Linux Platform. I could hardly believe it when it all came together, but I&amp;rsquo;m very pleased that it has. What is even more exciting is that the performance of the SQL Engine is going through the roof.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Business Intelligence Seminar 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/enlightenment/presentation-notepad/microsoft-bi-seminar-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/enlightenment/presentation-notepad/microsoft-bi-seminar-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The seminar was given on the Microsoft Campus at Reading UK on the 3rd March 2011. The presentation was split into four sections and the end of each section represents a real world intermission. You would be advised to download the slides (download link in notes) and follow the notes as you step through the slides. I personally think there is some excellent information embedded in these notes, your job now oh dear Business Analyst is start “data mining” for what is important and what is not! Within these notes you will also find a video link to last years presentation. Unfortunately due to the &lt;em&gt;NDA&lt;/em&gt; nature of some of the information talked about this years session, it was not recorded.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everybody wants to be important</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/03/25/everybody-wants-to-be-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 12:49:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/03/25/everybody-wants-to-be-important/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a very big fan of &lt;em&gt;self-development&lt;/em&gt; materials whether they be books, audio, presentations or simply just ramblings on the Internet and last year during the *Meet an MVP lunch time at the SQL PASS 2010 Summit this was the hotly debated subject on our table.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I know these materials generally get a bad press and I always remember a line from one of our comedians here in the UK who was criticising self-improvement training and said &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;the clue is in the name&amp;hellip;.self! &amp;hellip;so why are you listening to someone else!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. For myself I believe that the &amp;ldquo;self&amp;rdquo; in the name self-improvement actually means that we always need to examine ourselves (and our behaviour) in order to grow into something better. One thing that I know for sure is that I have a lot of work ahead of me to become the person that I want to be and I know it is within my power to do so.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VirtualBox random behaviour</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/03/21/virtualbox-randomness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 13:23:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/03/21/virtualbox-randomness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; If you want to learn something then stop reading this post now&amp;hellip; however if you (like me) take enjoyment in the weird, unusual, and unexplained, then please continue reading on.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Regular readers of my ramblings will by now appreciate that I love VirtualBox and I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it for a considerable amount of time -long before those Oracle boys muscled in on Sun, and just recently I saw something that I found a little puzzling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A visit to the Microsoft Business Intelligence Seminar 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/03/09/business_intelligence_seminar_2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2011 12:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/03/09/business_intelligence_seminar_2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I visited Microsoft for the Microsoft Business Intelligence Seminar presentation given by  Rafal Lukawiecki (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rafaldotnet&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://rafal.net/&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;). I must say that I found this one of the most valuable full day presentations that I have watched in a VERY long time for many different reasons. It is probably fair to say that I have probably not engaged BI as much as I probably should have over the last few years, since I have been focused on many other things. However it was plain to see that much of Rafal&amp;rsquo;s vision for the future of BI in IT was a very real possibility and as such is a compelling reason for me to re-engage. Certainly since the introduction of SQL 2000 Analysis Services, I am impressed by the pace in which the technology has matured.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SELECT MediaType, SUM(Content) FROM #Sources GROUP BY MediaType</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/03/08/t-sql_tuesday_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2011 00:06:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/03/08/t-sql_tuesday_16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/shared/tsql2sday150x15032.webp&#34; alt=&#34;TSQL Tuesday&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes people, for a change I have written my T-SQL Tuesday contribution several days in advance, ready for that very satisfying &lt;em&gt;Publish&lt;/em&gt; button to be pressed. But why you might ask? (OK well you didn&amp;rsquo;t ask but I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you anyway). 🙂&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reason that I decided to make that extra special bit of effort to write something in advance of Tuesday was precisely because I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a Scooby Doo (clue) of what exactly I was going to write about! This was thanks to the chosen subject of the month &lt;em&gt;Aggregation&lt;/em&gt; by the most excellent grrlgeek – Jes Borland (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/grrl_geek&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.lessthandot.com/index.php/All/?author=420&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Categorise your SQL Agent jobs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/03/04/job-category/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 16:12:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/03/04/job-category/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you are one of those people who&amp;rsquo;s house is immaculate? The lid is firmly placed back on the toothpaste, shoes left in a neat pile, coat in the cupboard. You know the sort of thing? Well I&amp;rsquo;m not quite like that but I try to be. Organized effort is a good thing and although it might not be obvious at the time can make life so much more easier further down the line.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLRally is live!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/02/25/sqlrally-area-is-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 16:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/02/25/sqlrally-area-is-live/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the coming weeks and months leading up to SQLRally, I will be adding information, news and more detail about my presentation. For now though the root area is live which is effectively the &amp;ldquo;press release&amp;rdquo; provided to the selected speakers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tags/sqlrally&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2011/sqlrally_banner_240x120_1.webp&#34; alt=&#34;SQLRally Orlando&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget, if you do see me wandering around in Orlando, to say hello. It&amp;rsquo;s always great to meet new people and I am always humbled by the high level of skill in the SQL community. Also (and most importantly) expanding our IT Professional Support Network will ensure that we always will have an ear to bend when we have technical problems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clustering nodes on different subnets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/02/17/clusterin-nodes-on-different-subnets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 19:38:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/02/17/clusterin-nodes-on-different-subnets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s rather ironic that the answer to a question that came my way recently, had been sitting in my feed-reader for the last month. Apart from the length of time that the item/s had been sitting there, I had opened them on numerous occasions and re-marked as &lt;em&gt;unread&lt;/em&gt; because I believed they needed more than just a quick skim.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I consider myself very experienced with SQL Clustering but one cannot know everything about everything. I&amp;rsquo;m endeavouring to fill any gaps in order to be not just very good, but hopefully at some point a leading (or how about &lt;em&gt;the leading&lt;/em&gt; expert in this field. Right now there are only a few people that I am aware of that I consider to be authorities in SQL Clustering -at least people I can learn from, I&amp;rsquo;ve even been using it as long as some of them. There will of course be more experts who I am unaware of but the ones I follow are Geoff Hiten, Allan Hirt and Symon Perriman of course! Whether I achieve my own personal aims will depend upon how many other areas of specialism I lend my eye to, but one can only try and right now I think I&amp;rsquo;ve been heading in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automating your SQL snapshots</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/02/15/automating-your-snapshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 16:49:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/02/15/automating-your-snapshots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A little while ago I was talking to someone about possibilities of reporting from SQL Server to avoid impacting the production server and the very first thing that sprang to mind was for them to use snapshotting from a mirror. They had already considered this option but it was not really viable because an almost real-time reporting solution was required. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until later that I wondered whether I had not really been precise enough in my explanation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLBits 7 the forgotten photos part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/02/12/sqlbits-7-forgotten-photos-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 19:48:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/02/12/sqlbits-7-forgotten-photos-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlbits.com/default.aspx&#34;&gt;SQLBits&lt;/a&gt; 8 voting has now ended so perhaps it is a good time to publish the second and final post of the series. I wonder if any of my sessions will get selected this time? One of my submitted sessions is the same one that has made it to the reserve list for the first ever &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/sqlrally/2011/&#34;&gt;SQLRally&lt;/a&gt; in Orlando and although slightly disappointed at just making the reserve list I was very proud that out of all the reserve sessions I came joint top (I took 38% of the vote in my category). The winner of that category is the well known Edwin Sarmiento (&lt;a href=&#34;https://bassplayerdoc.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bassplayerdoc&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;) and he is an absolutely smashing chap so I&amp;rsquo;m nothing but pleased for him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where to go for WAIT stat information</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/02/08/where-to-go-for-your-wait-stat-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 21:07:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/02/08/where-to-go-for-your-wait-stat-information/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fairly recently I was talking with a rather talented SQL Specialist internally at Microsoft and was asked the question by him as to where I get my Wait Stat information from. Query tuning isn&amp;rsquo;t really something I currently am required to do on a regular basis so I tend to get my information as and when I need it (even though I have a couple of articles and urls bookmarked I couldn&amp;rsquo;t particularly reference them in a conversation so perhaps I could go one better and officially post them). My answer then was that I Bing for my Wait Stat references (actually replace that with another search engine – but I was on the MS site!).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automate now to save time later</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/02/08/t-sql-tuesday-015-spend-time-now-to-save-time-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 12:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/02/08/t-sql-tuesday-015-spend-time-now-to-save-time-later/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/shared/tsql2sday150x15032.webp&#34; alt=&#34;TSQL Tuesday&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s T-SQL Tuesday time again and this month I&amp;rsquo;m a little late off the starting block. This time it is being hosted by Pat Wright &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlasylum.wordpress.com&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/SqlAsylum&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; and the subject of the month is all about &amp;ldquo;Automation in SQL Server&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So what is my favourite automation script or technique that I use in SQL Server? I had to have a think about this and my problem is that I have quite a few. I believe that the accessibility and usability of the Windows and SQL GUI (and related tools) means that SQL DBAs in particular have a tendency to automate much more than other IT Professionals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Disaster Recovery?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/02/01/what-is-dr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 19:39:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/02/01/what-is-dr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently asked &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;What is DR?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; when talking about SQL Clustering, Mirroring and the like to someone. The question was asked not because they didn&amp;rsquo;t know but because they were interested in what I thought. The answer is quite simple right?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After a moments pause I answered, &lt;em&gt;Disaster Recovery is the ability to restore a companies IT infrastructure to a minimum level required in order for that company to continue operating&lt;/em&gt;. OK so that wasn&amp;rsquo;t a really great response and of course DR means different things to different people, so it is probably important that we can be as explicit as possible. When the business asks &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Have you got a DR strategy in place&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;, I personally believe that we should already have established with the Business what they would class as &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Recovery&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My submitted SQLRally sessions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/01/27/sqlrally-just-proud-to-be-in-there-with-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 10:41:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/01/27/sqlrally-just-proud-to-be-in-there-with-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2011/sqlrally1.png&#34; alt=&#34;SQLRally logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several months ago, I submitted two sessions to SQLRally with great enthusiasm as detailed in this post. The first &amp;ldquo;The Great High Availability Hustle&amp;rdquo; I had been thinking about for a very long time and is hopefully going to fill a void that has existed for too long. As a DBA, if you are not already using Clustering I guarantee that you will be, sooner or later. SQL 2008 finally gave us true HA product for the Enterprise and I believe SQL High Availability is going to start gaining traction and market share over the coming months and years. But there is a problem with this. I believe that probably nearly every DBA that has become competent with SQL Clustering will at one point have had a baptism of fire with the technology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Gnome to Flux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/01/25/from-gnome-to-flux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2011 07:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/01/25/from-gnome-to-flux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In between the time I am looking into all things SQL and all things Microsoft I am usually tinkering in Linux, and this usually consists of tweaking my user desktop environment so that I may have a more productive and enjoyable experience – you might recall the post &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/08/03/my-big-fat-greek-desktop&#34;&gt;My Big Fat Greek Desktop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2011/my_menu.png&#34; alt=&#34;Flux Menu&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I knew the time would come when I would finally move on from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnome.org/&#34;&gt;Gnome&lt;/a&gt; desktop on my trusty Linux boxes, and I had toyed with that idea several times without the jump. Over the last few weeks and months I have been trialling &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.linuxmint.com/?p=1523&#34;&gt;Linux Mint Fluxbox&lt;/a&gt; edition and to be honest I really didn&amp;rsquo;t like it at first. One of the things that struck me was the simplicity of it, but then that was the whole point for the move. Simplicity equals speed and speed equals productivity as long as I could navigate my way around. One of the things that I first hated about this desktop that I now love, was the right-click behaviour on the taskbar. For instance if you right-click any running application on the taskbar, a close signal is sent to the application. At this stage you might be thinking that this would drive you mad and believe me for a small amount of time it did -until I started to realise actually how many times I right-click applications in Gnome or Windows and then do something with the context menu -which is usually always to close anyway. This action has now been reduced to a one-click operation, and I find that I am not constantly minimizing or maximizing windows all the time because I can close applications very quickly and tend to do just that. The other part of the equation (opening applications) can also be performed very quickly by moving the mouse to any part of the blank desktop, some of which can always be found at the bottom left and bottom right of the taskbar and right-clicking. This initially was a real pain until I discovered that the Fluxbox menus can be easily edited and customized to your requirements via a simple text edit of the menu files under the .fluxbox directory in your home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye SQL 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/01/16/countdown-to-extinction-goodbye-sql-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2011 20:06:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/01/16/countdown-to-extinction-goodbye-sql-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I cannot let the week go by without a special goodbye to an old friend. If you hadn&amp;rsquo;t already heard, &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.msdn.com/b/sqlreleaseservices/archive/2010/09/29/end-of-support-for-sql-server-7-0.aspx?wa=wsignin1.0&#34;&gt;SQL 7.0 support officially ended on the 11th January&lt;/a&gt; of this week. This means that as of now, legacy installations of SQL Server 7 are threatened with extinction and is only a matter of time before they become as scarce as SQL 6.5 installs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in how I got started with SQL Server and you haven&amp;rsquo;t done so already, you might want to take a quick peek at my &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/about&#34;&gt;about&lt;/a&gt; page. Here I mention how I quite insightfully (read luckily) took a training opportunity and put myself on a SQL 7 beta course rather than the one my company was expecting – one for SQL 6.5. That decision had a very big effect on my future IT career. Whilst at the training centre I remember that there was a guy there who claimed that he had been one of the first 100 people in the world to certify as an MCSE+i and his efforts to do so had been made a little easier because of the fact that he had apparently been based in Saudi Arabia for six months in a company that had not only a testing centre but all course materials available to him. He said of being out there &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;well what else can you do for 6 months in Saudi? I thought I might as well do something productive!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Start as you mean to go on</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/01/11/t-sql-tuesday-014-start-as-you-mean-to-go-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2011 02:03:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/01/11/t-sql-tuesday-014-start-as-you-mean-to-go-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/shared/tsql2sday150x15032.webp&#34; alt=&#34;TSQL Tuesday&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I cant believe T-SQL Tuesday has come around so soon again, and luckily I have just seen a tweet for someone else&amp;rsquo;s contribution just before I was about to turn into bed (it has just gone 01:17 a.m here in the UK).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So people, be grateful that I&amp;rsquo;m sacrificing those precious extra minutes counting sheep just to spout nonsense to you all! Actually you&amp;rsquo;d probably prefer that I just went to bed right? Well tough, I&amp;rsquo;m writing this even if it takes me all night (which I can assure you it won&amp;rsquo;t!).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review image hex data before storing it in a database</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/01/10/checking-your-images-in-adhoc-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2011 13:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/01/10/checking-your-images-in-adhoc-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really had to laugh (and not in a good way) when a request recently dropped into my lap to update a production database server with the script like the one that you will see shortly below. It is my firm belief that NO DML should ever be applied directly to production (Yes you read that right&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;NO DML&lt;/em&gt;). You might be thinking to yourself, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;well that&amp;rsquo;s a bit weird, what&amp;rsquo;s the point of having the database then if you can&amp;rsquo;t even query it?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; and that is a valid point. The key words in my original statement are &lt;em&gt;applied directly&lt;/em&gt; and by that I mean querying or updating the Database via the native SQL application tools such as &lt;code&gt;sqlcmd&lt;/code&gt; or more likely SSMS. If you are having to do so then I am betting there are usually one of the two following problems with your production system:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2010 in reflection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/01/01/a-year-in-provence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 23:59:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/01/01/a-year-in-provence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Firstly let me wish you all a very happy New Year and secondly a big thank you to all of you who have been dropping by my blog and I sincerely hope you continue to do so. I&amp;rsquo;ve been seeing at least a 10% month on month growth in traffic since the start of the year and its the prospect that I might be producing something (however remote) of interest to someone makes my efforts even more rewarding. I would also like to pay my respects to all those other Bloggers in the Blogosphere who provide great content for me to consume – more on this in the next few days. Also lets not forget the Tweeps, and if you do both then a huge big-up to you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshoot SQL Service connectivity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/12/23/dynamic-ports-are-dangerous/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 13:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/12/23/dynamic-ports-are-dangerous/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We had a fairly interesting incident recently where there had been some significant network issues which even once they had been resolved had left various connectivity problems to several of our SQL Instances. I thought it would be useful to take a few screen shots and demonstrate my thought process when this sort of reported incident occurs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first thing I am aware of is that our development support team has stated that an application is having problems connecting to the SQL Server. OK well the first thing I think is &lt;em&gt;lets try it for ourselves under my own system administrator security context&lt;/em&gt;. The security angle is important since the problem may be related to access rights. The result of my attempt is that we at least prove that something is not quite working as it should and the instance cannot be connected to for whatever reason.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at SQLRally 2011!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/12/16/excited-about-sqlrally-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2010 13:42:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/12/16/excited-about-sqlrally-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am very pleased/ proud to announce that I have submitted 2 abstracts for presentations to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/sqlrally/2011/&#34;&gt;SQLRally&lt;/a&gt; and should I be chosen they will be given in Orlando, Florida between May 11th to May 13th. For those of you not already aware, SQLRally is a little bit like a mini SQL PASS Summit and enables people from the East Coast of America to visit an event closer to them should they have not been able to attend the PASS Summit due to the distance and cost restrictions. It has been devised to fill the gap between SQL Saturday events and more can be found by visiting this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/sqlrally/2011/About.aspx&#34;&gt;url&lt;/a&gt;. I believe it is going to be a great success. Should I be chosen to present at SQLRally, which will be a tall order given the very strong competition it will be only my second time going to a SQL Event in the States (PASS 2010 was my first) it will be my very first visit to the East Coast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What the Business says is not what the Business wants</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/12/14/t-sql-tuesday-13-what-the-business-says-is-not-what-the-business-wants/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 00:07:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/12/14/t-sql-tuesday-13-what-the-business-says-is-not-what-the-business-wants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/shared/tsql2sday150x15032.webp&#34; alt=&#34;TSQL Tuesday&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Steve Jones, editor at large of SQL Server Central is this month hosting the latest &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlservercentral.com/blogs/steve_jones/archive/2010/12/07/t_2D00_sql-tuesday-_2300_13-_2D00_-what-the-business-says-is-not-what-the-business-wants.aspx&#34;&gt;T-SQL Tuesday&lt;/a&gt; and luckily I have managed to be organized enough to make a note in my Calendar so that I may finally contribute. A big thank you also goes to Steve who gave plenty of notice for this iteration of T-SQL Tuesday. If you don&amp;rsquo;t already know, the idea behind T-SQL Tuesday was created by Adam Machanic to improve the sharing of ideas and co-operation between SQL Server Professionals and if you would like to know more then you should check out Adam&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlblog.com/blogs/adam_machanic/archive/2009/11/30/invitation-to-participate-in-t-sql-tuesday-001-date-time-tricks.aspx&#34;&gt;first ever post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mr. Fumble Fingers - a case against clustering</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/12/09/mr-fumble-fingers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 14:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/12/09/mr-fumble-fingers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are not perfect (and I am guessing you are not!) you will have been in that situation where you have clicked your mouse button (substitute with your own horror story) and then almost immediately thought &lt;em&gt;what have I done!&lt;/em&gt; followed by an intense feeling of self loathing, self pity and general hopelessness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Actually as DBA&amp;rsquo;s, being fallible is not really an option and is why our positions of risk are usually rewarded on many various levels -of which higher salaries only play a small part of it. In the early days of my long IT career I recall two scenarios that I remember that feeling of despair (stories which I&amp;rsquo;ll save for another rainy day) but on both of those occasions they were ironically Cluster related and on both occasions I could argue the mistakes had been entirely preventable -and not just by myself. One issue was related to hardware and the other to the software setup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to rename a SQL Failover Cluster </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/12/06/more-cluster-group-network-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 13:39:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/12/06/more-cluster-group-network-names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most recently I came across a couple of tweets on the #sqlhelp hash tag regarding changing a Cluster Group network name. Helpfully a knowledge base article was offered up to the person asking the original question. The article &lt;a href=&#34;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms178083.aspx&#34;&gt;How to: Rename a SQL Server Failover Cluster Instance&lt;/a&gt; gave some very easy steps and advice to perform this action. However a comment was made regarding what exactly the Cluster Group Network name was. It was stated that &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is merely a DNS name&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; and this is not correct and may get you into hot water if you take that comment at face value.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLBits 7 the forgotten photos part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/12/01/sqlbits-7-forgotten-photos-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 15:05:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/12/01/sqlbits-7-forgotten-photos-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Several weeks back I attached my Blackberry to my PC to clear down all the photos in preparation for SQL Pass and I stumbled across these grainy old photos taken during those rainy few days in York. It all seems like a lifetime ago now and much has happened to me since &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlbits.com&#34;&gt;SQL Bits&lt;/a&gt; 7, but this was my story of an interesting and enjoyable but all too brief few days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The fantastically forgetful IP stack</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/11/30/the-fantastically-forgetful-ip-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 10:56:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/11/30/the-fantastically-forgetful-ip-stack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So the first thing you are probably wondering is&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;does this post have anything to do with SQL Server?&lt;/em&gt; Well if you have ever listened to my views on specialization and generalization you may be aware of the fact that I strongly believe that we all should be running our own sand-boxed virtualized environment distinctly separate from our corporate virtual environment and you (the humble DBA) will be your own Domain and Server admin -master of your own educational destiny. I am of course talking about one of the my key concepts that I like to practice myself, namely trying to be what I term a DBA 2.5. More on this though another time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dastardly database hiding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/11/26/dastardly-database-and-password-hiding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 13:44:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/11/26/dastardly-database-and-password-hiding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been recently going through the first part of one of Redgate&amp;rsquo;s excellent free ebooks &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.simple-talk.com/books/sql-books/the-red-gate-guide-to-sql-server-team-based-development/&#34;&gt;The Red Gate Guide to SQL Server Team-based Development&lt;/a&gt; and was rather amused when I came across the section talking about creating what they term &lt;em&gt;shape&lt;/em&gt; tables. Essentially what this means is to use the shape ascii codes in order to name a table. I remember a very very long time ago when I was still (almost) in short trousers reading an article suggesting that user passwords should incorporate various invisible ascii codes (such as escape codes) in their respective passwords, since this would render dictionary password cracking tools pretty much useless. It would also help if someone was looking over your shoulder – yes they have just observed you type &lt;em&gt;MyP@ssw0rd&lt;/em&gt; but they didn&amp;rsquo;t quite catch that ascii code you also typed did they?!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Different differential backup behaviour between SQL versions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/11/24/differential-backup-behaviour-between-sql-versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 13:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/11/24/differential-backup-behaviour-between-sql-versions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The other day I ran into a rather unique problem with a database when attempting to maintain it&amp;rsquo;s transaction log. As it turned out my particular issue was related to old replication code -which I hope to post about at a later date, but essentially I needed to clear down some of the logfile&amp;rsquo;s VLFs which I was struggling to perform. Anything I attempted to maintain it failed, however if I performed Transactional log backups, they would also fail due to the fact that there was no Full database backup in existence. Since the database was huge, and a full backup would have taken up to 12 hours to perform, it raised quite an interesting question namely &lt;em&gt;was there a way to force a Transactional log backup&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding disk partition alignment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/11/23/disk-partition-alignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 14:29:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/11/23/disk-partition-alignment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure by now most of you will have heard about Disk Partition Alignment and why it is so important (and not just for use with SQL Server IO Subsystems). I&amp;rsquo;m really quite interested in how many companies have actually sat up and smelt the coffee and addressed this issue? This problem is something that DBA&amp;rsquo;s quite readily acknowledge is a potential area of concern, but we usually have to rely on our SAN and Server administrators being one step ahead of the game in actively addressing the situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Database Mirroring modes of operation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/11/22/back-to-front-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 14:13:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/11/22/back-to-front-mirror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SQL Server database mirroring was obviously a great feature first introduced in SQL 2005 and will improve even further in the next big release (Denali) but quite surprising to me is how drastically the order in which the transactions are committed differ between both modes of operation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To recap, there are two types of mirroring (High Performance and High Safety) so lets look at exactly how these two types work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NxtGenUG Guerrilla tactics presentation review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/10/27/nxtgenug-guerrilla-tactics-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 12:11:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/10/27/nxtgenug-guerrilla-tactics-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night I attended the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nxtgenug.net/Default.aspx&#34;&gt;NxtGenUG&lt;/a&gt; meeting in Cambridge for my first time to see Peter Marriott blog|twitter give his presentation &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nxtgenug.net/ViewEvent.aspx?EventID=348&#34;&gt;Guerrilla tactics – Performance Testing MS SQL Server Applications&lt;/a&gt; and I very much enjoyed myself. I also expected to bump into Guy Smith Ferrier &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.guysmithferrier.com&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/GuySmithFerrier&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; but sadly he could not make it and was called at short notice to present in Birmingham. Both presenters I had previously met during my recent visit to Microsoft in Reading and was very much looking forward to this event.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protect your failover cluster names</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/10/22/use-protection-to-stay-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2010 12:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/10/22/use-protection-to-stay-available/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest worries for us grumpy DBAs are the risks which are posed to us due to our reliance on other teams, specialists and technologies in order to maintain a working and efficient SQL Server infrastructure. This was one of the key concepts when I put together my Thinking outside the Box talk for &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlbits.com&#34;&gt;SQLBits&lt;/a&gt; 7, and insist that we need to understand, get involved and help communicate best practices to our colleagues and fellow IT professionals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More cluster disk corruption</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/10/21/chk-your-dsk-ironing-out-those-abnormalities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 13:59:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/10/21/chk-your-dsk-ironing-out-those-abnormalities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ironically not more than a week or so after I emphasised the importance for DBAs to check file system integrity in my recent post &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/10/08/cluster-aint-misbehavin/&#34;&gt;Recovering from corruption in SQL Failover Cluster&lt;/a&gt;, another incident raises it&amp;rsquo;s ugly head. The post highlighted that file system corruption can cause unusual behaviour with your SQL instance, so when the other day the following errors in the event log were passed to me, I knew exactly what to look at.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to generate failover cluster logs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/10/11/generate-your-cluster-logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2010 11:58:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/10/11/generate-your-cluster-logs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Windows and SQL Clustering can be a tricky business, but fortunately most of the administration and troubleshooting can be performed through the GUI. Obviously the same argument can apply that the simplicity of any GUI can be it&amp;rsquo;s downfall in the sense that it opens up something complicated to the inexperienced. This can be a recipe for disaster on Clusters but as mentioned in previous posts is really down to your IT structures to restrict access to them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recovering from corruption in SQL Failover Cluster</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/10/08/cluster-aint-misbehavin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2010 11:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/10/08/cluster-aint-misbehavin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the great things about SQL Clustered Instances is that they generally give a much greater possibility for High Availability which is obviously the whole point of them. However one of the more commonly overlooked considerations is the fact that by their very design you are introducing extra complexity to your environment and this can be counter-productive and work against what you are trying to achieve in the first place. For instance if you allow unqualified and inexperienced people to access and even administrate your SQL Clusters then you could be in for a world of pain. I have seen it time and time again and yet those kind of classic mistakes seem to keep being allowed to happen. In order to highlight this point further, imagine your sysadmins, operators and DBA&amp;rsquo;s going about their everyday management of systems oblivious to the fact that what they are working on is actually a clustered node. They could be creating a Network Share, stopping a Service or even installing software without realizing what they are doing and the potential risk they are taking. It is for this very reason that I believe that Windows Clusters in particular require a specialized team in order to support them because we want to maintain the High Availability don&amp;rsquo;t we folks?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When the Cloud approach goes wrong</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/09/23/when-cloud-goes-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2010 09:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/09/23/when-cloud-goes-wrong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Around 2 or 3 years ago I made a conscious effort to try to detach myself a little from any one Operating System for my personal Documents, Favorites, RSS feeds and those sorts of things and therefore attempted to start using Cloud based technologies to achieve this goal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well the other day I went into my Bloglines account and was greeted with the following message:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2010/bloglines.png&#34; alt=&#34;Bloglines&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What particularly annoys me about this is the fact that they are just shutting down the service. No handing over to the community, no attempt at selling it on, not even a suggestion or arrangement of where you should move your feeds to. Their reasons for the shutdown are pretty lame too, but essentially boil down to the fact that they are focusing on their &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;commercial&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; activities. Certain functionality and settings will now be lost forever and should I have not seen this shutdown message (perhaps I was on holiday for 1 month) then it begs the question of what would happen to my feeds then.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A week at Oracle University</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/09/21/a-week-at-oracle-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 18:25:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/09/21/a-week-at-oracle-university/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About a month ago I went into the Big Smoke to spend the week at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oracle.com/global/uk/education/maps/london_oracle.html&#34;&gt;Oracle University&lt;/a&gt; premises at 1 South Place. I was attending the &lt;a href=&#34;https://education.oracle.com/pls/web_prod-plq-dad/db_pages.getCourseDesc?dc=D50311GC10&amp;amp;p_org_id=28&amp;amp;lang=US&#34;&gt;11g R1 Oracle RAC course&lt;/a&gt; and since I am very knowledgeable about high availability solutions, I was especially looking forward to filling in the one last piece of the jigsaw. I had already been on &lt;a href=&#34;https://education.oracle.com/pls/web_prod-plq-dad/db_pages.getCourseDesc?dc=D17316GC20&amp;amp;p_org_id=1001&amp;amp;lang=US&#34;&gt;Oracle&amp;rsquo;s 10g Data Guard course&lt;/a&gt; – which for the benefit of you SQL boffins is the equivalent of SQL Server mirroring. RAC of course is an acronym for Real Application Clusters and you can think of it as being similar to SQL Clustering but differs greatly in the sense that an Oracle instance is (or can be) effectively scaled out with the addition of extra nodes and due to the potential processing and memory available can theoretically be scaled up.&#xA;Rumor has it that something similar is being worked on for the next major release of SQL Server, but I am really not too sure whether this is fact or fiction. One thing I really liked about RAC is that when it works you can imagine it being really special, however like all of the other Oracle exposure I have had I was again left with a sense of bemusement due to all of the warnings we received such as don&amp;rsquo;t click this or don&amp;rsquo;t type that otherwise catastrophe will strike. The classic example of this in the notes was the warning about when you uninstall a node from the cluster to ensure that you do not miss the last part of the command. I think the following was the offending command:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLBits Speaker Training Day</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/09/19/speaker-training-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2010 18:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/09/19/speaker-training-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago, I (like many others) rolled into Reading to attend the Speaker Training day held at Microsoft HQ in the UK. This event was organized to help people prepare for speaking at SQLBits 7 (if your submission was successful) or to prepare for a future successful submission (if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t). Upon arriving at Microsoft it was quite funny because the receptionist seemed to recognize me, but since I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been to that building for around 3 years I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how she could have done &amp;hellip;still it&amp;rsquo;s always nice to be &amp;ldquo;recognized&amp;rdquo; 🙂&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An approach to dealing with database corruptoin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/09/16/corrupt-behaviour/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2010 15:58:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/09/16/corrupt-behaviour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After attending Paul and Kimberly&amp;rsquo;s excellent Masterclass in London a few months ago, I made a scribble in my notepad to play around a little more with self induced corrupted DBs (yes you read that right!). Part of Paul&amp;rsquo;s demonstration showed various recovery techniques and gotchas when you are unfortunate enough to be hit with corruption problems. Having been exposed to quite a few situations in live environments, I am not exactly a stranger to DBCC CHECKDB and fixing corruption issues, but the session was definitely enlightening and taught me some useful things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloning your VirtualBox virtual disks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/09/07/cloning-your-virtual-disks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 14:23:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/09/07/cloning-your-virtual-disks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The cloning of disk images (especially Windows) can present a few problems from the OS perspective which I shall expand upon shortly, however depending upon the Virtualization solution that you are using there can be a few problems to overcome unique to that solution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;get-a-new-guid&#34;&gt;Get a new GUID&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;VirtualBox uses a GUIDs in several places to uniquely identify various things. I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure I like this, and haven&amp;rsquo;t really thought about why it is required, but it could have something to do with the multi-platform support of VirtualBox and its VMs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VirtualBox virtual disk corruption when using ext4 host partitions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/09/06/virtualb-disk-corruption-on-ext4-file-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 16:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/09/06/virtualb-disk-corruption-on-ext4-file-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it is not always a great idea to be running the latest and greatest, and it seems that there is a small problem when VirtualBox virtual machines have their virtual disks housed on ext4 filesystems. I am sure that this will be corrected at some point, but in the meantime luckily there is a simple workaround.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the virtual machine is first started up, and if the error condition is satisfied, you are prompt with the warning message.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microsofts new GUI-less server OS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/09/02/what-a-real-server-should-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 19:38:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/09/02/what-a-real-server-should-be/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I stumbled on this the other day and I really like this idea.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyone who remembers the days of Novell NetWare being King of the LANs would likely agree that you don&amp;rsquo;t need a fancy GUI to have a server. Something which is still relevant to UX&amp;rsquo;s today and thankfully Microsoft are starting to take notice. One thing I really like about Microsoft is that they do listen and are not too arrogant to think that only their opinion is the only one that matters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to query your database relationships</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/08/22/its-all-in-a-relationship-finding-your-constraints/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2010 09:26:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/08/22/its-all-in-a-relationship-finding-your-constraints/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I wrote about how to manage your table constraints in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/07/22/checking-your-constraints-to-check-your-integrity&#34;&gt;Check your constraints to check your integrity&lt;/a&gt; but one thing that is missing from this post is how do you determine what relationships exist between tables in order for you to temporarily disable them. This can be particularly tiresome on relationship heavy schemas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Luckily there are two quite useful stored procedures that you can use to show you them and they are &lt;a href=&#34;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms189813.aspx&#34;&gt;sp_pkeys&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms175090(v=SQL.105).aspx&#34;&gt;sp_fkeys&lt;/a&gt;. The first stored procedure will display a primary key for a given table and the second can display a list of all tables with a defined foreign key relationship to the specified primary table.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to create CD ISO image In Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/08/10/how-to-create-a-cd-image-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 11:21:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/08/10/how-to-create-a-cd-image-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You may recall me mentioning the dd command from a previous post many moons ago in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/11/09/cloning-and-expanding-virtualbox-disks-its-not-that-hard&#34;&gt;Cloning and Expanding VirtualBox Disks&lt;/a&gt; and saw for yourself how incredibly easy Linux and useful can be at times. Well lets put dd to a similar use -and a common necessity for all of us from time to time, especially in relation to building virtual machines quickly. I am of course talking about creating ISO cd/dvd images from physical media.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Big Fat Greek Desktop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/08/03/my-big-fat-greek-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 22:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/08/03/my-big-fat-greek-desktop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;Although this post may look at first to be about Linux and whilst many of you visiting this post will be either Windows or SQL centric you might think this is not for you. &lt;em&gt;Actually you are exactly the right people to be reading it because I want you to understand that you have options out there open to you&lt;/em&gt;. Your desktop can be a blank piece of paper and you can draw what you want. You are not constrained by software boundaries if you do not want to be. My desktop is all about flexibility, speed and usability. I can do anything I want whether it be Linux, Windows, SQL, Oracle whatever on my beloved desktop.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Query Editor save highlighting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/07/30/greens-are-good-ssms-script-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2010 14:56:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/07/30/greens-are-good-ssms-script-feedback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the little things in life that please me, and there have been a few things of late I have noticed or directed to which have left that warm fuzzy feeling.&#xA;The latest is a nice little feature that appears to have been present for a very long time. Why I have not noticed (or paid attention) to it so far is beyond me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After writing a script in SSMS if you wish to reuse it, then it is probably a very good idea to save it now. However, before you do, have a look to the side of the script and you will notice a yellowish colour by the side of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make your query tabs more readable in SSMS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/07/28/make-your-tabs-more-readable-in-ssms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2010 14:24:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/07/28/make-your-tabs-more-readable-in-ssms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just the other day I came across a post by Simon Sabin that highlighted some useful status bar and tab settings that have been introduced in SQL Server 2008.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For me this is fantastic, since it removes one of my few pet hates introduced by SSMS.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2010/pre_tab_change.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pre tab change&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From SSMS, select &lt;em&gt;Tools/ Options&lt;/em&gt; and under the &lt;em&gt;Text Editor&lt;/em&gt; node remove all the connection settings you don&amp;rsquo;t want in the tab.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using STUBs for object promotions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/07/19/stub-out-your-bad-practices-when-deploying-object-promotions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2010 12:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/07/19/stub-out-your-bad-practices-when-deploying-object-promotions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When a script is deployed in your production environment, how is it deployed? Are the scripts written to account for the object already existing and if so what actions are taken? But what if the object doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist, what then? All too often in these scenarios the usual style of deployment scripts I see being provided to database teams first detect the existence of said object and then drop it (should it exist). This then leaves the way clear for the script to perform its create statement. is there really anything wrong with this approach? Well yes, actually there is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Prometric problems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/07/09/just-cant-get-no-sit-isfaction-70-451/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2010 12:42:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/07/09/just-cant-get-no-sit-isfaction-70-451/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What on earth is going on? I sometimes think the world is going mad and that I&amp;rsquo;m the last person alive who is sane. But then, come to think of it, isn&amp;rsquo;t that the first sign of madness?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not all that long ago I had a right fiasco with my SQL 2005 upgrade exam as blogged about previously in &lt;a href=&#34;http://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2010/04/21/prometric-madness-nightmare-on-examination-street/&#34;&gt;Prometric madness - Computer Says: No&lt;/a&gt;. Well, what I haven&amp;rsquo;t said since then is that a month later, I went straight on to upgrading to my SQL 2008 MCITP. The exam itself went smoothly enough (although I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find my passport in the morning) but once completed, the test centre started having all sorts of problems with the certificate printer and started to talk about turning things off and on again (such as the PC that I sat the test on). After about 20 minutes of them panicking the printer suddenly whirred into action and all was good with the world again and my stress levels dropped back to normal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to set and manage your SQL Server default paths</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/07/08/how-to-set-and-manage-your-sql-server-default-paths/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 23:59:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/07/08/how-to-set-and-manage-your-sql-server-default-paths/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good practice in any SQL installation is to ensure that all builds have commonality. This ensures that administrating more than one server becomes much easier to perform since, as an administrator you should never have any nasty surprises (such as finding the TEMPDB installed on the System partition).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One such default that should always be set for every SQL instance installed is the default file paths for the &lt;code&gt;DATA&lt;/code&gt; file (&lt;code&gt;mdf&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;ndf&lt;/code&gt;) drive, the &lt;code&gt;LOG&lt;/code&gt; file (&lt;code&gt;ldf&lt;/code&gt;) drive and the &lt;code&gt;BACKUP&lt;/code&gt; file drive. SQL Server will use and default to values that have been specified on installation, but sometimes it is not always convenient, desirable or possible to set these to your final destinations at this point. In fact in my automated build, I am only really interested in the drive in which the system databases will be located. This removes the dependency upon many multiple drives at the time of installation, and post installation reconfiguration can take place when all drive arrays have been made ready.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Develop query tool to return multi-query results</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/05/30/make-your-life-easier-write-an-app-make-rad-work-for-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2010 16:41:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/05/30/make-your-life-easier-write-an-app-make-rad-work-for-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quite often I come across scenarios where you know what you need to do, you know how to do them, but know the way to do it will be very repetitive in SSMS. In these instances the best way to overcome them is to create a few queries and join them up into a little applet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One such example I had recently was that we wanted a way to very quickly check several servers for privileged database and server role membership.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSMS query pane bug in Windows 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/05/20/ssms-query-pane-bug-in-windows-7-its-bugging-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2010 14:05:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/05/20/ssms-query-pane-bug-in-windows-7-its-bugging-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you familiar with this menu?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2010/right0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Menu&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are you sure?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do you use it a lot?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yep me too&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of you will already know how to get this menu within SSMS, and one such way (the way I always use) is to right click the white space within a Query window. One of the reasons you might wish to do this could be because you are copying text. Well in Windows 7 this does not seem to work any more. I initially noticed the problem when using my spanking new SQL 2008 R2 client installation. After several installations on a couple of platforms it appears that the issue is not specific to SQL 2008 R2 but is actually related to running on Windows 7. The following all display this behaviour :&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First view on installing Windows 7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/05/13/windows-7-install-sit-back-and-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2010 20:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/05/13/windows-7-install-sit-back-and-watch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well I&amp;rsquo;m not really going to go into any detail right now about my experiences so far with Windows 7, but I just wanted to show just what the installer looks like. I&amp;rsquo;ve heard all sorts of things about it being quicker and less painful in Windows 7 and I guess if I am being honest that might be largely true.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2010/windows001.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Loading&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One thing for sure is that the interface does look nice and polished. However first booting up from your media you are presented with this unappealing boot sequence. Shame they didn&amp;rsquo;t give a nice custard yellow colour to the bar, it would have looked very much like the NT 4 loader.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing the Citrix client on Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/05/12/installing-citrix-client-on-linuxcertify-your-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 20:53:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/05/12/installing-citrix-client-on-linuxcertify-your-client/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first step of installing Citrix client on your Linux machine is to first obtain the package. From Citrix&amp;rsquo;s website download the tarball of the Citrix Receiver.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2010/citrix1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Citrix clients&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Extract the tarball&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2010/citrix2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Extract&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;and run the setupwfc executable. Select the first menu item to start the installer, and keep defaults. Once the installer has completed, exit the installer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2010/citrix3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Run setup&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once complete you should try launching a published Citrix Application. At this stage you will probably encounter a client error message &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;You have not chosen to trust &amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo;, the issuer of the server&amp;rsquo;s security certificate (SSL error 61).&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webcam troubleshooting on Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/05/10/skype-on-helena-can-you-see-me-yes-we-can/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 08:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/05/10/skype-on-helena-can-you-see-me-yes-we-can/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The other day, due to a long distance friendship, I really thought it was time to try and get Skype up and running on one of my Linux machines (currently running the Helena release of Mint).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Upon plugging in the USB cam (a nice little Logitech Quickcam Communicate STX), all initially looked promising with a little blue light briefly coming on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Downloading and installation of Skype occurred without incident, and I then proceeded to set-up my account. Unfortunately when I can to set-up my video device, even though Skype looked like it could see one, clicking the test button just had no effect and the screen was black.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to load CHM files from external media in Windows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/04/24/loading-chm-files-from-external-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2010 22:43:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/04/24/loading-chm-files-from-external-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another very quick but useful tip that I had to do several years back (and most recently a few days ago) was to have to tell Windows to ignore the usual security constraints and allow other data sources. Otherwise when you attempt to load e-books from these data sources, otherwise you will be blocked.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To work around this you simply need to add the following registry file to your registry. Note that in my case the J: drive is a mapped network drive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prometric madness - Computer Says: No</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/04/21/prometric-madness-nightmare-on-examination-street/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2010 21:25:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/04/21/prometric-madness-nightmare-on-examination-street/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I spent a very entertaining 4 hours or so, finally taking (after 4 years of getting around to it) the SQL 2005 upgrade exam and had a bit of a &amp;lsquo;mare. My first problem with this exam was that it started off with 7 or 8 mini-exams and these were essentially very large case studies that each had 5-8 questions attached. Now my first problem was that I must have spent the first 8 minutes of my allocated 15 for this one case study trying to figure out where the first question was! The number was displaying 1/8, however clicking the &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Question&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; button simply didn&amp;rsquo;t change anything and I was left with the explanation of how to do these mini exams. Finally after coming across some text somewhere I realised that question 1 was in fact not a question but an introduction!!!! Was it beyond the wit of man to not start the question numbering post introduction?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to search Active Directory membership</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/04/20/searching-active-directory-membership-when-a-gui-just-aint-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2010 13:14:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/04/20/searching-active-directory-membership-when-a-gui-just-aint-enough/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bit of a quickie here but a goody. Nothing really new either but since I&amp;rsquo;ve just spent the last 10 minutes piecing the command together (the last time around 6 years ago) I might as well make a record of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So the problem is that you have a very long list of users and groups within an Active Directory group and screen shots don&amp;rsquo;t cut the mustard any more. The solution is to use the dsquery command line tool.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Good practices for manual SQL script promotion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/02/25/promoting-tsql-scripts-keeping-control-of-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2010 14:36:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/02/25/promoting-tsql-scripts-keeping-control-of-changes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An often overlooked part of promoting DML scripts is knowing what the intention is going to be before one is run. For instance if you work in an environment with a high throughput of DML script promotions then there is a good chance that those scripts will be ran via change control and then the results fed back. However what happens when the result counts end up being incorrect (i.e different to what was anticipated)? A rollback occurs and we are then talking about possible availability issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disabling and Enabling Oracle Scheduled Jobs in sqlplus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/01/19/disabling-and-enabling-oracle-scheduled-jobs-in-sqlplus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 14:23:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/01/19/disabling-and-enabling-oracle-scheduled-jobs-in-sqlplus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first thing you need to know is what jobs are scheduled and enabled. To do this we simply query the &lt;code&gt;dba_scheduler_jobs&lt;/code&gt; view as follows:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sql&#34; data-lang=&#34;sql&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;SELECT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;owner&lt;/span&gt;, job_name, enabled &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;FROM&lt;/span&gt; dba_scheduler_jobs;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2010/configschedjobs.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Query scheduled jobs&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now we know what jobs are present and enabled/ disabled we can use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/cd/B28359_01/appdev.111/b28419/d_sched.htm&#34;&gt;DBMS_SCHEDULER&lt;/a&gt; to change their status. The &lt;code&gt;DBMS_SCHEDULER&lt;/code&gt; is a package which provides a collection of scheduling functions and procedures and in our case since we wish to either disable or enable a job, we simply call its Disable or Enable procedure as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Restoring Mozilla Thunderbird email</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/01/02/restoring-mozilla-thunderbird-email-changing-your-outlook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 01:29:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2010/01/02/restoring-mozilla-thunderbird-email-changing-your-outlook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thunderbird is quiet a nice little app, just about all you want from a mail client and no more. The no more part is good because it keeps it fast. MS Outlook, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;killer app&amp;rdquo; is a very decent client too and I for one am currently tied into it due to years of reliance, but that I sense is changing due to my more flexible attitude of late. The main problem with Outlook as with any of the MS products is the sense that you are firstly &amp;ldquo;tied in&amp;rdquo; and secondly that over time they start to look and behave like bloat-ware. This is not necessarily Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s fault, but probably down to the age of the products and endless drive to add new commercial features.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Permanently changing xterm size defaults</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/12/29/changing-xterm-size-defaults-for-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2009 15:52:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/12/29/changing-xterm-size-defaults-for-good/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a good tip from a fellow blogger which for all those people (like me) who have lots of tweeks and customisations here and there might just get fed up of constantly resizing their xterm settings. Works an absolute treat.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codealpha.net/36/how-to-change-the-gnome-terminal-default-size-ubuntu/&#34;&gt;http://www.codealpha.net/36/how-to-change-the-gnome-terminal-default-size-ubuntu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2009/xtermdefaults.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;change xterm defaults&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Its just a shame that it is currently not possible to do this through the xterm profile settings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rejoining split files in Windows and Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/12/21/joining-split-files-through-the-os-a-classic-command-example-of-command-line-flexibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2009 14:06:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/12/21/joining-split-files-through-the-os-a-classic-command-example-of-command-line-flexibility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you frequently download large files in many parts then you are probably not a stranger to HJSplit. This application can be used to connect these parts back together and is quite frankly completely unnecessary since your operating system likely already has a way! So how do you do it?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lets say you have just downloaded the following files:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;big_file_part.iso.001&#xA;big_file_part.iso.002&#xA;big_file_part.iso.003&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To join these into one big file:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Windows&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A quick ramble about Linux Mint 8</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/12/15/mint-8-ramblings-eee-its-rather-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2009 22:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/12/15/mint-8-ramblings-eee-its-rather-good/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I&amp;rsquo;m just typing this from my new (extra) desktop setup at home installed to Linux Mint 8.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got to say that it just keeps getting better. Unlike my recent disappointment with the latest Windows offerings (excepting Windows 7 because it is too early for me to fairly judge), I have been very pleased with the latest Mint offering. Not only does it retain it&amp;rsquo;s familiar interface (which I have to say is why linux may imo one day trump Windows), but it appears crisper, more user friendly and accessible than ever.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remember your database files when dropping OFFLINE databases</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/12/13/dropping-offline-databases-dont-forget-your-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2009 23:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/12/13/dropping-offline-databases-dont-forget-your-files/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If I asked you the question, &amp;ldquo;what happens to the physical data files if you drop an offline database?&amp;rdquo; would would probably have to have a bit of a think about it.&#xA;There are really only three potential outcomes here:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The DROP fails&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The DROP succeeds and removes the data files&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The DROP succeeds and leaves the data files&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now if you think about the nature of the offline database the answer becomes a little more obvious. The &lt;code&gt;OFFLINE&lt;/code&gt; database is simply meta data in the system catalog, there are no associations to files apart from that which exists within this meta. Therefore on this basis, if you remove an offline database, you are essentially removing the meta data. So on this basis you can deduce that the physical data files would remain – and this is exactly what happens (option 3).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some observations to SQL 2008 clustering installation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/11/19/observations-with-sql-2008-clustering-simplifying-the-installer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 13:23:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/11/19/observations-with-sql-2008-clustering-simplifying-the-installer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well these last few days I&amp;rsquo;ve been really in the thick of it trying to sort out clustering on two new UAT servers running Windows 2008 and get SQL 2008 setup in an active/ active configuration. It&amp;rsquo;s been a real struggle for several reasons. The first is that I was only given a couple of days to learn, implement and configure due to significant overruns from the Technical Support team and the second is due to the fact of how much has changed in this latest release of clustering.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloning and Expanding VirtualBox disks in Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/11/09/cloning-and-expanding-virtualbox-disks-its-not-that-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 13:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/11/09/cloning-and-expanding-virtualbox-disks-its-not-that-hard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You always know when someone is very knowledgeable about a subject by the way in which they answer a question. A simple question is always answered with a simple solution, and this is what happened to me recently when I wanted to expand or migrate a virtualbox virtual disk attached to a real physical disk partition so that I could double my capacity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem was that I had built a virtual machine with a 16GB disk and realised pretty quickly that it was not going to be enough, so I posed a question to the Linux gurus &amp;ldquo;how do I clone a disk in Linux?&amp;rdquo;. Sure enough the reply came &amp;ldquo;&lt;code&gt;dd if=source of=destination bb=512&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL 2005 Performance troubleshooting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/11/02/sql-2005-performance-troubleshooting-article-quite-useful-really/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 23:07:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/11/02/sql-2005-performance-troubleshooting-article-quite-useful-really/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is just a quick post pointing to what appears to be a really useful technet article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/cc966540.aspx&#34;&gt;Troubleshooting Performance Problems in SQL Server 2005&lt;/a&gt; with some custom scripts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to connect to SMB targets in Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/10/13/mounting-unc-paths-on-linux-dont-forget-your-smb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2009 21:32:15 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/10/13/mounting-unc-paths-on-linux-dont-forget-your-smb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After much scrabbling around for days I have finally found it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me explain. After a recent rebuild of my Linux Mint laptop I could not for the life of me remember how to connect back to a UNC. Although I obviously had the command syntax:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;sudo mount -t cifs //hostname/share /media/unc -o user&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;username&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It just would not work and kept throwing up the following error:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mount: cannot mount block device&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;All I remembered doing from previously getting it to work was that (I thought) I needed to apt-get a package. Thankfully after much trawling around and another poster, I came across the package and hey presto all is working again:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Auto generate database GRANTs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/09/16/generating-grant-statements-because-its-quicker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2009 12:20:15 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/09/16/generating-grant-statements-because-its-quicker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a very quick post here, but sometimes when you wish to grant execute right for multiple stored procedures to a particular database user it is easier to simply run the following script in the respective database in order to generate this assignment script. This is far easier than using the 2005 and 2008 GUI interface (and even 2000/ 7) especially if there are a lot of procedures.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sql&#34; data-lang=&#34;sql&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;USE&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;SELECT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;GRANT EXEC ON .&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; name &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39; TO [user]&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;FROM&lt;/span&gt; sysobjects &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;WHERE&lt;/span&gt; xtype &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;P&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;AND&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update (18th January 2026):&lt;/strong&gt; Upon migrating posts to my new site I notice that this script appears incomplete. Todo: Will seek to update it with a working script when I get the chance (despite its age).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check your constraints to check your integrity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/07/22/checking-your-constraints-to-check-your-integrity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 11:33:15 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/07/22/checking-your-constraints-to-check-your-integrity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Something that you probably don&amp;rsquo;t need to do every day is to change the data in the foreign key field. Generally, depending upon how your application is designed these would be relatively irrelevant and are simply just a mechanism to constrain the data on the key and logically join it together. In a situation where the primary and foreign key data actually describes a physical entity, it is feasible that when the physical entity changes name it makes perfect sense that the foreign and primary key data ought to change to reflect that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Started using Linux Mint</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/07/19/choosing-the-right-distro-at-last-it-has-been-found/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2009 21:48:15 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/07/19/choosing-the-right-distro-at-last-it-has-been-found/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a very long time now (over 10 years) I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying very hard to &amp;ldquo;get into&amp;rdquo; Linux and there has always been a major obstacle hit along the way to make me put the OS back on the shelf for another day. Over this last year I have been seriously looking into a few distributions and I am very impressed. Whilst everything is not perfect, I have been very surprised how polished everything is begining to look and if I was Microsoft I would be really starting to look over my shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to perform an emergency database restore when blocked by corrupt database</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/07/22/recovering-suspect-databases-but-what-if-you-cant-remove-the-old-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2009 12:18:15 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/07/22/recovering-suspect-databases-but-what-if-you-cant-remove-the-old-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The other day a fellow dba was having a problem with removing a corrupt database from a SQL Server and was failing to remember that the physical architecture of SQL Server is actually quite simple. Every time he tried to drop the database or to fix the database allowing for data loss or even take the database offline, the server would complain that the database was in single user mode (even though it wasn&amp;rsquo;t). Anything he tried on this database was complained about, and he was at a loss on how to remove it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Issues when moving your SQL data and log files</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/07/13/more-moving-files-careful-when-you-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 20:53:15 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/07/13/more-moving-files-careful-when-you-point/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You might recall that I recently touched upon how to go about moving your &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/03/05/moving-sql-server-data-and-log-files-dont-detach&#34;&gt;SQL data and log files correctly&lt;/a&gt;. In this post I will quickly walk through one common scenario.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ok so your in a hurry and you&amp;rsquo;ve stopped your SQL Service. All relevant datafiles have been moved to a new location and you are ready to roll. SQL Service has been started back up and unfortunately (but you expected this) none of the user databases whose files you moved have come back up. Well thats alright you say, because you are going to repoint them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Name resolution for SQL Server instances</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/07/07/name-resolution-for-sql-server-instances-it-just-might-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 02:10:15 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/07/07/name-resolution-for-sql-server-instances-it-just-might-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SQL Server instances are great for allowing multiple instances on a single windows host, but unlike with Oracle instances this does cause a very big headache when configuring applications that consume these servers, instances and its databases. In the Oracle world there are many different mechanisms for name resolution and one of the most common is the use of the &lt;code&gt;TNSNAMES&lt;/code&gt; file which effectively maps the database (think SQL instance) to the host. The Oracle database name is a unique identifier and does not have an &amp;ldquo;instance&amp;rdquo; postfix name like SQL server, so this lends itself very easily to application/ database name separation. In addition the Oracle instance is not tied to a particular hostname and therefore can be moved onto another physical host with very little reconfiguration required in order for applications to communicate to this new host location. To be more specific, when using &lt;code&gt;TNSNAMES&lt;/code&gt; resolution, all that would be necessary from the application perspective to reconfigure them to reflect a new database host would be to edit this file on all the application servers ensuring that this hostname is changed to reflect its new name for this specific database.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preserve backup chain with COPY ONLY backups</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/06/09/copy-only-backups-another-great-addition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2009 02:09:41 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/06/09/copy-only-backups-another-great-addition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A welcome addition to SQL 2005 and above is the inclusion of the &lt;code&gt;COPY_ONLY&lt;/code&gt; clause to the BACKUP statement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This overcomes the long time problem of breaking the backup chain for your automated backup jobs when taking adhoc backups. For instance, imagine that another dba has taken a full backup in preparation for a change request and then later that day an incident occurs (such as drive failure) which requires a point in time recovery of the database and its logs. Unfortunately your colleague has not informed anyone about their full backup and has gone home for the evening. You will be left in a situation where you can successfully restore your scheduled backups, a differential and possibly some transaction logs but only up to the point before the last full was taken. In order to recover the database properly you need to restore that last full and any subsequent logs, but unfortunately you cannot locate this last full backup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recursive killing of SPIDs in a database for admin operations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/05/27/simplifying-killing-spids-because-you-really-ought-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 02:11:18 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/05/27/simplifying-killing-spids-because-you-really-ought-to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One problem that I have found particulary annoying of late when performing any database operation that requires connections to it to be disconnected, such as setting it offline or a restoring over the top of itself is getting rid of these connections. Obviously this can be achieved by listing the current spids connected to the database and performing a kill for each spid. This can be quite laborious and obvious does not address any spids coming live whilst you are busy killing the existing ones, so you can end up going around in circles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Login failure user is not associated with a trusted SQL Server connection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/03/31/login-failures-for-windows-based-authentication-what-does-that-error-mean/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 02:10:10 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/03/31/login-failures-for-windows-based-authentication-what-does-that-error-mean/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever come across the following login failure within the SQL Server error logs? &amp;ldquo;Login failed for user &amp;ldquo;. (Note the empty user name). This is all a bit unusual if you think about it. Since the user attempting the authentication should theoretically have already been authenticated to the windows domain, you would have expected that this user-name would be displayed here in the authentication failure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/2009/untrusted.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Login failed for user&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Auto generate RESTORE scripts from a live database</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/03/19/auto-generating-statements-every-dba-should-try-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2009 02:13:49 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/03/19/auto-generating-statements-every-dba-should-try-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever performed a scripted restore or some of similar operation and then got entirely frustrated at the laborious and error prone nature of this exercise especially when the database consists of many datafiles and transaction log files?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course the SQL Server 2005 GUI is very good at making the restore process much easier but it&amp;rsquo;s biggest failing is that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t preserve filenames (especially when the restored database name is changed). This is a very big problem when you have a large number of data files and causes a big headache.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to move your SQL Data and Log files correctly!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/03/05/moving-sql-server-data-and-log-files-dont-detach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2009 02:13:46 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2009/03/05/moving-sql-server-data-and-log-files-dont-detach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I came across the &lt;code&gt;ALTER FILE&lt;/code&gt; part of the &lt;code&gt;ALTER DATABASE&lt;/code&gt; command and started thinking about its use when moving physical datafiles.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I must admit that this particular part of the &lt;code&gt;ALTER DATABASE&lt;/code&gt; command has largely gone unused. Whilst the &lt;code&gt;REMOVE FILE&lt;/code&gt; part is infrequently used and the &lt;code&gt;ADD FILE&lt;/code&gt; part is possibly more so, the intuitive nature of the SQL 2005 and above GUI (and even SQL 7 and 2000 to some extent) has meant that resorting to various statements is largely unnecessary. In fact, the only times that I can really recall having resorted to the &lt;code&gt;MODIFY&lt;/code&gt; operator is when I have been renaming logical file names.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
