<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community on tenbulls blog</title>
    <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community on tenbulls blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © {year} Mark Broadbent</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 19:12:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>4 Days of Dockercon – Day 4</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/10/19/4-days-of-dockercon-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 19:12:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/10/19/4-days-of-dockercon-day-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2017/entsummit.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Enterprise Summit&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After doing some more work in the evening for Microsoft and watching my Football match, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to sleep until midnight, so I woke with my usual conference groggy feeling. At my age, I really need more hours in bed! Thankfully I had done most of my packing the night before so didn&amp;rsquo;t have an awful lot to do. However given the fact that I had skipped dinner/ supper the night before I was determined to grab a big breakfast. I&amp;rsquo;d skipped my evening meal since I really couldn&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to wander down to the Shopping Mall and waste 40 minutes on a round trip in doing so, nor did I fancy a meal in the hotel restaurant wasting 2 hours of messing around.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Days of Dockercon – Day 3</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/10/19/4-days-of-dockercon-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 08:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/10/19/4-days-of-dockercon-day-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2017/handsonlabs.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hands on labs&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The second and final day of general sessions arrives and I manage to leave my room with a little more time to spare than yesterday. Again, I grab a bite to eat in the exhibitor room and then find myself a good seat for the keynote day 2. This time it was lead by Scott Johnson (COO of Docker) and focused again on Docker Enterprise Edition but with a strong focus on the MTA program and migrating legacy apps to Docker. The atmosphere was slightly more subdued today -probably because people were nursing hangovers from last nights party, but I was intrigued by a few things. For instance, when they talked about migrating a legacy .NET app and modernizing it to Docker, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t really clear to me whether doing so was also irradicating dependencies on older .NET frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Days of Dockercon – Day 2</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/10/17/4-days-of-dockercon-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 22:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/10/17/4-days-of-dockercon-day-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2017/keynote.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Keynote&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why is it that at every conference I always seem to be rushing around in the morning trying to get to the keynote sessions in time. No matter how early I wake, I always seem to run out of time. Today was the first main day of sessions and I was determined to grab a bite to eat before heading to the keynote, so I headed across to the sponsor hall and grabbed my required bacon supplement for the day and managed to have a very interesting chat with a Docker insider (who is apparently contributing to the keynote the next day – I&amp;rsquo;ll insert name if that is correct). We discussed the future of containers in a potentially Serverless world and it was really interesting (and reassuring) to note that Docker has their eyes and ears firmly planted in all the right places (can&amp;rsquo;t say any more right now!).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Days of Dockercon – Day 1</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/10/17/4-days-of-dockercon-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 06:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/10/17/4-days-of-dockercon-day-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2017/dockercon.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dockercon&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s those little things in life that you come to be grateful for when you are staying in a different country and significantly helps make your trip more relaxing and enjoyable. A quick visit to Starbucks in the morning or being able to grab a half decent lunch in a nearby restaurant during the conference or simply popping into a nearby newsagent to grab a newspaper to read in your room in the evening just make the days away from home a little more bearable&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Days of Dockercon – Day 0</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/10/15/4-days-of-dockercon-day-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 19:37:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/10/15/4-days-of-dockercon-day-0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2017/food.webp&#34; alt=&#34;BASALT&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s around this time of year that I&amp;rsquo;d usually begin blogging my traditional 5,6 or 7 days of PASS (another conference about another technology) and I have been doing this for at least 3-4 years (primarily as a speaker). This year, due to a multitude of reasons, I decided to pull my sessions just prior to selection after deciding that it really was time for me to do something different. Those people who know me quite well will know that I have harbored a very strong interest in Microservices and container technologies (long before they started getting &amp;ldquo;hip&amp;rdquo; in the world of Microsoft) and have had a bucket list desire to attend Dockercon since it&amp;rsquo;s inception.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at SQLSaturday Parma 2017</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/09/20/speaking-at-sqlsaturday-parma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 09:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/09/20/speaking-at-sqlsaturday-parma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anyone who knows me well will know that I like to fly my colors close to my chest and am a proud Chelsea fan. I have supported them since they fell to and rose back from the English old Second Division as Champions under the then manager Bobby Campbell, and have seen highs and lows (mostly lows) for the next seven years. That is until Dutch legend Ruud Gullit became the manager in &amp;lsquo;96 and bought perhaps the greatest player ever to grace the blue shirt of Chelsea FC.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at SQLSaturday New York 2017</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/04/21/back-in-the-big-apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 17:52:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/04/21/back-in-the-big-apple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2017/go-mets.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Go Mets!!!&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to announce that I&amp;rsquo;ll once again be speaking at &lt;a href=&#34;https://http://www.sqlsaturday.com/588/eventhome.aspx&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday New York&lt;/a&gt; on the 20th May and this is my Third time speaking at this event and my FOURTH time speaking at the Microsoft offices in New York, after last year speaking at &lt;a href=&#34;https://href.li/?http://www.spsevents.org/city/NYC/nyc2016&#34;&gt;SharePoint Saturday New York&lt;/a&gt; (since the SQLSaturday didn&amp;rsquo;t run that year).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of the event and obviously, it is a mammoth task for the organizers to put on given the location and size of the audience, but I have always had great fun and (unexpectedly) refreshingly good feedback speaking there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 7</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/10/30/7-days-of-pass-day-7-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 01:16:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/10/30/7-days-of-pass-day-7-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2016/karla.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Karla&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After a very heavy night (my only one of the trip) I wake to a pounding head and dry mouth. Having consumed at least one bottle of soda during the night I start on another and then move onto Coffee. There is no keynote today and therefore no rush, so I leisurely get my stuff together and contemplate breakfast. No rush that is until I look to my phone and notice a tweet telling me that the UK community is in the Community Zone at 8am, but given that the time is currently 7:30am I realize that it will be impossible for me to make it in time. I&amp;rsquo;ve represented this area many times before and am no longer the UK RM, so I excuse myself and let others step up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 6</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/10/29/7-days-of-pass-day-6-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 17:24:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/10/29/7-days-of-pass-day-6-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2016/drdewitt.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dr DeWitt&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today is the big day of my presentation, and it is Thursday 3am and I have slept since 10pm, having managed to achieve a few extra hours of prep on my session the night before until jetlag smashed me across my head. My session is the last one of the day which means I have just under 14hours to go before completing what I actually came here to do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 5</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/10/27/7-days-of-pass-day-5-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 13:06:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/10/27/7-days-of-pass-day-5-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;7 Days of PASS – Day 5&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s 3.30am and I have been sleeping off a really bad pain in my stomach (from what I think is a Mango allergy). Having achieved practically nothing the night before, it is important that I manage to put in some serious hours into my session prep. The whole thing is going badly and I&amp;rsquo;m not happy, but I&amp;rsquo;ll keep plugging away up until the end. By 6.30am I have progressed a little further, but now it is time I start getting ready for the PASS Keynote in which I am on the Blogger table again. I&amp;rsquo;m out of my hotel by around 7.30am, so I quickly head to (yes you&amp;rsquo;ve guessed it) Starbucks at 600 Pine Street and grab a muffin for breakfast as I walk across to the Conference Center.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 4</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/10/26/7-days-of-pass-day-4-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 13:43:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/10/26/7-days-of-pass-day-4-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I started the day pretty much as I ended the previous night, I woke up and immediately started working on my session again! By around 9am I decided that I really ought to head out to breakfast, and went over to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sheratonseattle.com/seattle-daily-grill&#34;&gt;Sheraton Bar and Grill&lt;/a&gt; and proceeded to eat the largest amount of Bacon and Salmon that has ever been consumed in one sitting. The buffet cost me 20 Bucks, but I suspect my Salmon alone cost that much wholesale! Combined with two huge Orange juices and several hogs worth of Bacon, I was not only very happy but very full!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 3</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/10/25/7-days-of-pass-day-3-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 14:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/10/25/7-days-of-pass-day-3-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2016/room.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Room&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Comfy, but spending too much time here!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today is the first day of the Summit pre-cons, and I wake up at 5am knowing that I won&amp;rsquo;t be attending. Instead, I will have a day of session preparation ahead of me because I am still behind and seriously need to get this train back on the tracks. I know the day is going to be a fairly solitary event, and so it proves, but I at least struggle to get myself to breakfast at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dragonfishcafe.com/&#34;&gt;Dragonfish Cafe&lt;/a&gt; and have probably the most amazing tasting and crunchy fried potatoes ever -washed down with some eggs and American crispy bacon. One thing I have learnt about the Americans is that they LOVE potatoes and LOVE crispy bacon. But I&amp;rsquo;m not complaining!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 2</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/10/24/7-days-of-pass-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 14:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/10/24/7-days-of-pass-day-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2016/sounder2016.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sounders&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After arriving the day before, the threat of jetlag was always going to be there, but I thankfully managed to sleep until 4am and snoozed for a further hour. I started the day looking forward to the return of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jos%C3%A9_Mourinho&#34;&gt;Mourinho&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stamford_Bridge_(stadium)&#34;&gt;Stamford Bridge&lt;/a&gt;, but this time he was leading a different team (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.manutd.com/&#34;&gt;Manchester United&lt;/a&gt;). I was of course hoping for a &lt;a href=&#34;https://https://www.chelseafc.com/&#34;&gt;Chelsea&lt;/a&gt; win, but my biggest challenge was trying to find somewhere to watch the match. My problem was that the game would kick off at 9am (Seattle time), so a sports bar wasn&amp;rsquo;t possible, so in the end, I found a dodgy streaming site which kind-of did the job. Four-Nil to Chelsea and I was a happy man!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 1</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/10/23/7-days-of-pass-day-1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 12:52:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/10/23/7-days-of-pass-day-1-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2016/curry.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Curry&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having had the luxury of booking a slightly later flight than normal (9.45am to Seattle), I took the liberty of an overnight stay closer to the airport, but unfortunately for me I had decided upon a Curry for tea the night before and now at 6am I am feeling a little rough and cannot manage my traditional pre-flight bacon sandwich. Not good, but at least my cup of tea is slightly more appealing, and I start to get ready for my trip. I have a 30-minute drive ahead of me to the airport, so I start getting ready and head off.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye Karla!</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/07/12/big-up-to-karla/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 11:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/07/12/big-up-to-karla/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2016/sad_puppy_small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sad Puppy&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well the day I&amp;rsquo;ve been dreading for the last few weeks has finally arrived, and it is with great sadness and joy to read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/Community/PASSBlog/tabid/1476/entryid/805/A-Look-Back-Five-Incredible-Years.aspx&#34;&gt;Karla&amp;rsquo;s announcement&lt;/a&gt; that she will be leaving her current role in the PASS family. Sadness because Karla has not only become a great friend and ally over the years (and I will deeply miss her in doing what she does), but joyous because I know that she is moving on to the next successful phase of her life story -one in which she can rightly reap the rewards of her brilliance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anouncing Hybrid Virtual Chapter</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/01/22/goodbye-oraclevc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 14:59:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/01/22/goodbye-oraclevc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is with a tinge of sadness that we announce the Oracle Virtual Chapter is no more, but do not despair, all is not lost!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Around 14 months ago the leadership of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://oracle.sqlpass.org/Home.aspx&#34;&gt;Oracle Virtual Chapter&lt;/a&gt; changed hands after it had laid dormant for approximately the same length of time as from then to now. Back then &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/&#34;&gt;PASS&lt;/a&gt; were not entirely convinced that there was an audience or market for this Chapter, but we discussed our vision for it&amp;rsquo;s future and for a time the VC had a stay of execution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing SQLNexus</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/01/07/sql-nexus-is-alive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 11:13:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2016/01/07/sql-nexus-is-alive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2016/sqlnexus.webp&#34; alt=&#34;SQLNexus&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have not already heard, SQL Nexus (a next generation SQL Server focused event) will be held on May 2nd – 4th 2016 in Copenhagen, Denmark.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;idea&amp;rdquo; for SQL Nexus (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlnexus.com/&#34;&gt;w&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sqlnexus&#34;&gt;t&lt;/a&gt;) was first conceived in 2012 more as a future pipe dream than anything else and it was something that I had in mind when we delivered the second &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlsaturday.com/228/eventhome.aspx&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Cambridge in 2012&lt;/a&gt; in which we included a dedicated SharePoint track.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dear #sqlfamily</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/12/16/dear-sqlfamily/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 15:32:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/12/16/dear-sqlfamily/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2015/rare_smile1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rare smile&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;This was the first time Lucy (and her brother smiled) after the first few days of treatment (in which she was constantly vomiting). A charity had come into the hospital to let the kids play with their video editing software. It was the first time that Mummy and Daddy felt hopefull&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would first like to apologise for the time it has taken for me to write this open letter to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/sqlfamily&#34;&gt;#sqlfamily&lt;/a&gt; in response to the rather incredible and slightly bewildering response to Steve Jones&amp;rsquo;s first &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/sqlwish&#34;&gt;#sqlwish&lt;/a&gt; initiative.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 7</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/11/04/7-days-of-pass-day-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 15:28:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/11/04/7-days-of-pass-day-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2015/conf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Conference Center&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wake at 3 a.m. to find my plan of preparing my sessions into the late evening in tatters having completely crashed and burned after the huge meal the night before. My main session is scheduled to be delivered at 8 a.m so that means I have approximately &lt;em&gt;four hours&lt;/em&gt; to try and nail it. First I get showered at dressed, and then start running through my slide deck and correct error after error. Once I am happy with the deck, I read through my notes and study each slide until I am happy that I &lt;em&gt;understand&lt;/em&gt; each one. I run through the demos and complete main session preparation before returning back to the lightning talk. After working four solid hours I head to the Convention Centre so that I can grab a quick bite to eat and setup in my room with enough lead time before the session starts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 6</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/11/03/7-days-of-pass-day-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 16:14:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/11/03/7-days-of-pass-day-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2015/nikocrazy.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Crazy Niko&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s my 2nd and final day on the Blogger Table and also the 2nd day of the Summit proper. This time I am seated at the opposite end of the table to the day before and soon after sitting down I am greeted by Chris Yates (&lt;a href=&#34;https://chrisyatessql.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/yatessql&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;) who turns out to be a really nice guy and a pleasure to sit with. This time the keynote focuses more on the logistics of PASS growth and their finances more than anything else. After an all too long discussion on those points we finally get to the ever brilliant Dr David DeWitt and Dr Rimma Nehme who talk about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_of_Things&#34;&gt;IoT&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest and say that I didn&amp;rsquo;t find much (personal) value in this discussion but that is probably because I am more interested in technical nitty gritty rather than more generalised discussion, but there is no doubting those two are not only brilliant individuals but are an incredible team together. Sad then that the real stand out announcement of the entire Summit Keynote sessions for me was their shock news that they would not be working together after this Summit due to David retiring and Rimma moving onto other things. The result was a couple of tears in my eyes and a standing ovation from all those present. I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching these guys present (especially David) since my very first Summit, and this feels like an end of an era to all concerned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 5</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/10/29/7-days-of-pass-day-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 23:58:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/10/29/7-days-of-pass-day-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2015/meandrob.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mark Broadbent and Rob Farley on Blogger table&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today is the first day proper of the Summit and I am scheduled to be on the Blogger table again which means an early start for me. I need some breakfast but am running out of time so for the first time ever (out of 6 years of Summit) I decide to drop by the Conference Center and check-out the breakfast offerings. The only thing that I really care about is Bacon and I am pleased to report that the dining hall has a bountiful supply! I grab some Egg, fruit and (of course) Bacon and wonder why I have never done this before??? Could have saved myself hundreds of Bucks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 4</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/10/28/7-days-of-pass-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/10/28/7-days-of-pass-day-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2015/pike.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pike&amp;rsquo;s Place&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another day, another dawn, but somebody forgot to tell my body that what has gone has gone. I feel pretty bad from yesterday&amp;rsquo;s alcoholic Molotov concoctions and have been up since 2.30 a.m. unable to sleep with jet-lag and over exuberance. By the morning I have become an expert on Seattle Weather reports and American News but I&amp;rsquo;m feeling a little better and am grateful for those few bottles of water in my room. I decide to get in-touch with last nights partners in crime and we arrange to meetup at &lt;a href=&#34;https://eatatlowells.com/&#34;&gt;Lowells&lt;/a&gt; to have some breakfast. This is good for me because I have wanted to try breakfast at Lowells for a long time having only ever eaten there for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 3</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/10/28/7-days-of-pass-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/10/28/7-days-of-pass-day-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2015/ill.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ill&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is unbelievable to think that it is already Monday although it feels like I&amp;rsquo;ve now been in Seattle for a week. Today is the first day of SQLPASS pre-conference sessions although this year is the first time ever in 6 years that I will not be attending them. Instead I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to leave the days open to do other things and hopefully catch up on some work, so this is what I try to do for the next few hours until my hunger cannot take it any more. I head over to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dailygrill.com/locations/daily-grill-seattle-washington/&#34;&gt;Daily Grill&lt;/a&gt; again for a quick breakfast and coffee and then head across the road to register at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wscc.com/&#34;&gt;Convention Center&lt;/a&gt; to pick up the standard fare and obligatory conference bag.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 2</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/10/28/7-days-of-pass-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/10/28/7-days-of-pass-day-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2015/soccer.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sounders&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is Sunday 8 a.m. and I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to sleep well after yesterday&amp;rsquo;s exuberance. My body aches, but I&amp;rsquo;m soaking my bones in a nice hot bath and starting to feel ready for the day. As I glance outside I can see that the darkened streets are glistening from the light rain that is gently falling. The Sun is not completely up and it is cloudy to boot. Welcome to Seattle weather.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Days of PASS – Day 1</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/10/25/7-days-of-pass-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 11:27:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/10/25/7-days-of-pass-day-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2015/carnival.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Carnival of Souls&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having decided to avoid missing yet another day of work, rather than travel on my more traditional Friday slot, instead I managed to catch the early morning Saturday flight to Seattle from London Heathrow. Knowing that I had lots of work to do on the plane, I decided that an upgrade to Business Class was in order so upon boarding settled back for that more pampered experience. The flight itself was fairly uneventful and despite spending a couple of hours trying to go through presentation content, I could not resist the lure of the in-flight film system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bring-A-Boss to SQLSaturday Training day promotion</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/08/20/announcing-our-sqlsaturday-cambridge-bring-a-boss-training-day-promotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 14:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/08/20/announcing-our-sqlsaturday-cambridge-bring-a-boss-training-day-promotion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2015/david_brent_111.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;David Brent&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft are delivering a dedicated full day pre-conference training day session at &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlcambs.org.uk/&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Cambridge&lt;/a&gt; aimed towards Data Professional Leaders and Executives, delivered by industry leading technology movers and shakers. &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlcambs.org.uk/precon7/&#34;&gt;Building a Data Driven Strategy&lt;/a&gt; will help your boss understand how they invest in Data Driven Data Analytics and how they can implement them. They will learn all about Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s future data vision and understand what theirs should be. It is something they will not want to miss.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So you havent been selected for the PASS Summit?</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/06/26/not-accepted-for-the-pass-summit-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 19:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/06/26/not-accepted-for-the-pass-summit-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I guess it could be easy to become complacent about being selected to speak at conferences and you could certainly argue that I have been tremendously lucky with the selection process since I first broke into the speaking circuit in 2010. In 2011 I delivered my first lightning talk at the Summit and this was already off the back of me being the only European speaker (AFAIK) at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/sqlrally/2011/orlando/Home.aspx&#34;&gt;SQLRally Orlando&lt;/a&gt;. Every year since then I have been fortunate enough to be selected to deliver one (or more) full session abstracts at the Summit and when combined with a nice collection of speaking gigs at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlsaturday.com/&#34;&gt;SQLSaturdays&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/Events/24HoursofPASS.aspx&#34;&gt;24HOP&lt;/a&gt; and other events you could be forgiven for thinking that I must have the &lt;em&gt;magic touch&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing SharePoint Saturday Cambridge 2015</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/06/25/twotribes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 10:43:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/06/25/twotribes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2013, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlsaturday.com/228/eventhome.aspx&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Cambridge&lt;/a&gt; became the first ever SQLSaturday in the World to host a dedicated SharePoint track and the event was a great success. It struck me at the time how well we managed to get a SharePoint audience at an event that was largely about SQL Server so with the support of our dedicated SharePoint sponsors (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.combined-knowledge.com/&#34;&gt;Combined Knowledge&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.k2.com/&#34;&gt;K2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.axioworks.com/&#34;&gt;AxioWorks&lt;/a&gt;), a fantastic addition of SharePoint speakers and with the expert help from the SharePoint community through Peter Baddeley (&lt;a href=&#34;https:https://about.me/baddaz&#34;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/baddaz&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;) I think we managed to light the touch paper for my future plans for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlsaturday.com/411/EventHome.aspx&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Cambridge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at SharePoint Saturday London 2015</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/06/05/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturday-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 10:43:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/06/05/speaking-at-sharepoint-saturday-london/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2015/evoconf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Evoconf&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think it is any great secret that I have had my eyes on the SharePoint Community for quite some time. With the introduction of a dedicated SharePoint track (and precon) in 2013 at &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlcambs.org.uk/category/sqlsaturday/&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Cambridge&lt;/a&gt; (a World 1st, I believe) and most recently my attendance of the three day annual &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sharepointevolutionconference.com/&#34;&gt;SharePoint Evolution Conference&lt;/a&gt; in London, it has been clear to me for years that the SQL and SharePoint Communities and technologies are more closely related and integrated than I think most professionals would realize. They are simply just different perspectives on what is essentially the end goal of presenting data to the end-user.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choose your own agenda - from SQLSaturday to the PASS Summit</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/05/26/progcomm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 11:44:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/05/26/progcomm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2015/buck-needs-you.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Buck needs you!&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;OK so sadly Buck can&amp;rsquo;t be with us this year, but if he could, he would tell you to join our Programme Committee!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This year, SQLSaturday Cambridge is pioneering the first ever Global Programme Committee for a SQLSaturday and we want you to be part of it!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After being personally involved in the PASS Programme Committee for many many years and playing a small part in reviewing abstracts, speakers and anything else that needs an opinion, it might be natural that I would want to take my experiences of this process and attempt to improve things -or at very least try a different approach.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at SQLSaturday New York 2015</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/04/09/speaking-at-sqlsaturday-380-new-york/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 15:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/04/09/speaking-at-sqlsaturday-380-new-york/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in August 2012 I had the honour of speaking at the last (but one) SQLSaturday to be held in New York City which marked a particular milestone in my SQL Server journey. While I had (by then) already spoken at the two American SQLRally events (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/sqlrally/2011/orlando/Home.aspx&#34;&gt;Orlando&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/sqlrally/2012/dallas/Home.aspx&#34;&gt;Dallas&lt;/a&gt;) and delivered a lightning talk at the 2011 PASS Summit, SQLSaturday New York was my first ever SQLSaturday in the U.S.A and because of that it was already special before I had even arrived.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at SQLBits XIV (after all!)</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/02/20/speaking-at-sqlbits-xiv-after-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 13:36:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/02/20/speaking-at-sqlbits-xiv-after-all/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think it is a particularly big secret that I am a fan of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlbits.com/&#34;&gt;SQLBits&lt;/a&gt; (more posts about SQLBits can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/sqlbits/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). I remember being at the PASS Summit in 2010 and enthusiastically talking about the SQLBits conference to those that cared to listen and was rather taken aback by the lack of awareness outside of Europe during my time there, so I like to think that my enthusiastic ramblings over the years have contributed in some very small way to promoting the conference to a wider global audience. SQLBits gave me my first speaking break, which allowed me soon after to speak at SQLRally in Orlando, so I am always grateful to them for offering me that opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speaking at SQLSaturday Lisbon 2015</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/02/17/speaking-at-sqlsaturday-lisbon-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 09:14:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/02/17/speaking-at-sqlsaturday-lisbon-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2015/sqlportremington2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Remington&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;I liked the event so much, I bought the community&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you ever asked an experienced speaker what is the best formula to follow when starting out on your road to presenting, they would most likely tell you to start &lt;em&gt;small&lt;/em&gt; and work your way up to bigger events. First present to your work colleagues, next move onto User-Groups, then onto bigger events such as SQLSaturdays and then finally (when you are ready) talk at the biggest events in the World such as the PASS Summit (in the U.S.A) or SQLBits (in the U.K).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Days of PASSDay - 5</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/11/08/5-days-of-pass-day-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 14:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/11/08/5-days-of-pass-day-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2014/enterthedragon.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Enter the Dragon&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wake up to the faint sound of early morning traffic starting to roll slowly through the empty streets of Downtown Seattle as the occasional bark from a dog can be heard from somewhere in the distance. Nearby, just a few blocks away, the now empty Convention Center stands as a shell compared to the hive of activity that it was over the last week.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The last day of the Summit has been and gone and I feel just a hint of sadness that my time here in Seattle and the U.S.A is almost over but can at least start to think about the end of 2014 and look forward to good things in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Days of PASSDay - 4</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/11/07/5-days-of-pass-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 14:56:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/11/07/5-days-of-pass-day-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2014/beingbuck.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Being Buck Woody&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I write, the penultimate day of the PASS Summit has been and gone. It was again an overloaded rollercoster of a ride filled with appointments, chance meetings of old friends and most significantly the day I gave my Community Session called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/summit/2014/Sessions.aspx#sid7377&#34;&gt;Being Buck Woody&lt;/a&gt; alongside the ever fabulous Buck Woody. I spent the early hours of the morning in deep concentration preparing for this session and even while eating breakfast I had my head down gathering thoughts and listening to some recorded notes. Later on, myself and Buck got together in the speaker room and did a final run through of the deck and both of us were fairly happy with the content and flow of the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Days of PASS - Day 3</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/11/06/5-days-of-pass-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2014 00:38:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/11/06/5-days-of-pass-day-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well just when you thought things could not get any busier, along comes Day 3 of the PASS Summit. I started the day on the PASS Blogger Table for the opening Keynote speech of the Summit introduced by Thomas LaRock (the current PASS president). There was a distinct shortage of Australian representatives on the table, which was soon rectified by the arrival of the one an only Rob Farley (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rob_farley&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlblog.com/blogs/rob_farley/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;), who is always amusing to listen to. To my left was one of my favourite German SQL Server experts, the ever happy Oliver Engels who was furiously typing away and in front of me Brent Ozar appeared to be switching backwards and forwards across different media platforms and applications and was no doubt constructing some interesting posts for our consumption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 days of PASS - Blogger table</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/11/05/blogger-table-day-1-thomas-larock/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 16:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/11/05/blogger-table-day-1-thomas-larock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The key note has just begun and the number of first timers standing up is quite incredible and very large. Thomas LaRock has begun the keynote speech and runs through the board of Directors and then makes a plea for people to stop by the Community Zone and connect.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some of the numbers quoted regarding the number of Chapters, SQLSaturdays and Virtual Chapters is quite staggering and demonstrates the growth of PASS today. The discussion moves to looking back at how our personal careers have grown in the last 5 years, which is interesting  because 5 years ago just pre-dates my first ever Summit, how things have changed for me back then in that time frame.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Days of PASS – Day 2</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/11/05/5-days-of-pass-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 13:42:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/11/05/5-days-of-pass-day-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome folks to the second enthralling instalment of 5 days of PASS! As I am sure is about to become very clear, I type with the knowledge that I have a very busy day ahead with various pieces of preparation to complete. The biggest thing that bothers me is that by the time my PASS related workload ends, so will most of the conference. This is perhaps the biggest downside to being involved in events as something more than just an attendee, since you don&amp;rsquo;t quite get to relax and do as much with your time that you would normally do and your time doesn&amp;rsquo;t really feel like your own, however if I didn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy contributing I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t do it right?!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Days of PASS – Day 1</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/11/04/5-days-of-pass-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 15:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/11/04/5-days-of-pass-day-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2014/taphouse_beer.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Taphouse Beer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is now the morning after the night before, having completed the official first day of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlpass.org/summit/2014/Home.aspx&#34;&gt;PASS Summit 2014&lt;/a&gt;. It is nice to be back in Seattle and America after not being able to travel last year so it has been particularly great to catch up with a couple of old friends and ex-colleagues. I actually arrived in the States on Saturday evening (two days ago) where I met up with my good friend &lt;a href=&#34;https://theblobfarm.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Régis Baccaro&lt;/a&gt; at the Airport, and then later we had a nice meal and drinks with the most excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.solidq.com/rpertusa/home.aspx&#34;&gt;Ruben Pertusa Lopez&lt;/a&gt; and a bunch of other &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.solidq.com/&#34;&gt;SolidQ&lt;/a&gt; guys (at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://http://www.taphousegrill.com/&#34;&gt;Taphouse&lt;/a&gt; -of course).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who is watching the Watchmen?</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/06/03/who-is-watching-the-watchmen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 17:06:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/06/03/who-is-watching-the-watchmen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2014/smiley.png&#34; alt=&#34;Watchmen&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is funny, but when I first decided to put myself forward for the Nominations Committee this year, I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize that the whole process would turn into a Campaign for Election. It really goes against much of what I stand for and is not really what I believe the Community is truly about. My involvement with community efforts, whether they be PASS related or not, are done so because I believe that my input (if required) would be beneficial to the cause that  I am offering to invest my time, efforts and possibly finances into. I am not seeking publicity, nor am I interested in promoting any personal ventures, Companies or other self-serving interests into those efforts. What I &lt;strong&gt;am&lt;/strong&gt; interested in, is that this &amp;rsquo;thing&amp;rsquo; we all are part of benefits from my investment, whatever that may be. That is surely the whole purpose of being a volunteer? I volunteer my time and effort to you, so that you can benefit -not me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PASS NomCom is announced</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/05/28/your-country-needs-you-pass-nomcom-is-announced/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 21:06:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/05/28/your-country-needs-you-pass-nomcom-is-announced/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Please also check out my latest post on the NomCom election found &lt;a href=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/06/03/who-is-watching-the-watchmen&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already heard, the official slate for the 2014  NomCom committee has been finalized and published by the Professional Association for SQL Server (that&amp;rsquo;s PASS to you and me) and can be found on their website via this &lt;a href=&#34;https://bit.ly/SfTpBD&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;. You can check out the list of 11 candidates (and how to vote) in which I am very pleased to announce I am one of them having decided to put myself forward this year for reasons that will become clearer in future posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside SQLSaturday: Lisbon</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/04/07/inside-sqlsaturday-niko-neugebauer-sqlsaturday-lisbon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 13:32:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/04/07/inside-sqlsaturday-niko-neugebauer-sqlsaturday-lisbon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2014/sintra.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Sintra&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;The beautiful Sintra&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Inside SQLSaturday, and today I am joined by Portugal&amp;rsquo;s very own Niko Neugebauer (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nikoport.com/&#34;&gt;web&lt;/a&gt;|&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/NikoNeugebauer&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Niko is the event lead to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlsaturday.com/267/eventhome.aspx&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Lisbon&lt;/a&gt; which holds the honour of being the first SQLSaturday &lt;strong&gt;ever&lt;/strong&gt; to be held outside of the United States and the launch pad for so many other great events to follow around the world. Along with his team, they run a selection of Community events and innovative initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLBits 12 Announced!</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/03/04/twelve-is-a-magic-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 09:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/03/04/twelve-is-a-magic-number/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2014/coltsfoot_rock_small.png&#34; alt=&#34;Coltsfoot Rock&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A massive congratulations to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlbits.com/&#34;&gt;SQLBits&lt;/a&gt; team for announcing what will become the 12th iteration of the UKs finest and largest SQL Server conference. Putting on events at this scale by such a small core team demands huge respect and I sincerely thank them for doing so. I have personally learnt a ton of information and grown as a person and as a SQL Professional because of their efforts and I know many others in the industry feel the same way too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLSaturday Cambridge raises £££ for charity!</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2013/09/29/sqlsaturday-cambridge-raises-for-charity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 20:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2013/09/29/sqlsaturday-cambridge-raises-for-charity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are very pleased to announce that the final figures of the SQLSaturday Cambridge fundraising has been counted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some of you will know that we were collecting for Children&amp;rsquo;s Cancer Charity &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.younglivesvscancer.org.uk/&#34;&gt;CLIC Sargent&lt;/a&gt; and the reasons why we were doing this can be understood by reading my previous post &lt;a href=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2013/09/25/change-your-event-and-make-a-difference&#34;&gt;Change (your event) and make a difference!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The amount collected at the event through various different means amounts to &lt;strong&gt;£490.03&lt;/strong&gt;!!!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SQLSaturday Cambridge are therefore honoring our commitment to match this figure, which means that &lt;mark&gt;we are therfore donating a grand total of £980.06 to charity&lt;/mark&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to write a bit more about this further in due course.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Change (your event) and make a difference!</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2013/09/25/change-your-event-and-make-a-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 22:52:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2013/09/25/change-your-event-and-make-a-difference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Regular readers may remember a post I wrote many moons ago in which I described just how exactly &lt;a href=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2012/05/04/change-and-make-a-difference&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Cambridge started&lt;/a&gt; and hopefully gave a lesson in why we should all attempt to grow as much as possible as individuals and embrace (unforeseen) opportunities, as and when they appear. These days I suppose you could describe me as a seasoned presenter (note: seasoning doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily equal good 🙂) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlsaturday.com/228/eventhome.aspx&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Cambridge&lt;/a&gt; is soon to celebrate its second birthday and outing this coming Friday and Saturday. I know I have only just scratched the surface of what I could become and what I would like to be and that I only have myself and genetic limitations to get in the way of my &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;enlightenment&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Countdown to SQLSaturday Edinburgh</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2013/06/06/countdown-to-sqlsaturday-edinburgh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 10:25:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2013/06/06/countdown-to-sqlsaturday-edinburgh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2013/xeventjonathan2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jonathan Kehayias&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;A pre-conference good enough for Super heros&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In exactly 2 days time the United Kingdom&amp;rsquo;s 3rd SQLSaturday will be in full swing, showcasing a group of SQL Server MVPs, MCMs and Community experts. This will be the very first time that SQLSaturday has happened in Scotland and it is going to be fantastic to bolster the PASS membership and exposure in that area which can only good news for all concerned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My recent achievements</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2012/12/23/santa-comes-early/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2012 09:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2012/12/23/santa-comes-early/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2012/kumar_christmas_smaller.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kumar Christmas&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With days to go before Santa boards his sleigh and pulls back on the reigns tethering his trusty magical flying reindeer to perform what is probably the most incredible feat of logistical planning and execution the world has ever seen, I can look back on the last few months with surprise, satisfaction and appreciation and thank those people who have helped to make my run up to Christmas an extremely rewarding and happy affair.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
