<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community on tenbulls blog</title>
    <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community on tenbulls blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © {year} Mark Broadbent</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 09:02:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SQLBits 12 Announced!</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/02/11/03/04/twelve-is-a-magic-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 09:02:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2014/02/11/03/04/twelve-is-a-magic-number/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2014/coltsfoot_rock_small.png&#34; alt=&#34;Coltsfoot Rock&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A massive congratulations to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlbits.com/&#34;&gt;SQLBits&lt;/a&gt; team for announcing what will become the 12th iteration of the UKs finest and largest SQL Server conference. Putting on events at this scale by such a small core team demands huge respect and I sincerely thank them for doing so. I have personally learnt a ton of information and grown as a person and as a SQL Professional because of their efforts and I know many others in the industry feel the same way too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLSaturday Cambridge raises £££ for charity!</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2013/09/29/sqlsaturday-cambridge-raises-for-charity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 20:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2013/09/29/sqlsaturday-cambridge-raises-for-charity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are very pleased to announce that the final figures of the SQLSaturday Cambridge fundraising has been counted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some of you will know that we were collecting for Children’s Cancer Charity &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.younglivesvscancer.org.uk/&#34;&gt;CLIC Sargent&lt;/a&gt; and the reasons why we were doing this can be understood by reading my previous post &lt;a href=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2013/09/25/change-your-event-and-make-a-difference&#34;&gt;Change (your event) and make a difference!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The amount collected at the event through various different means amounts to &lt;strong&gt;£490.03&lt;/strong&gt;!!!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SQLSaturday Cambridge are therefore honoring our commitment to match this figure, which means that &lt;mark&gt;we are therfore donating a grand total of £980.06 to charity&lt;/mark&gt;. I’m hoping to write a bit more about this further in due course.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Change (your event) and make a difference!</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2013/09/25/change-your-event-and-make-a-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 22:52:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2013/09/25/change-your-event-and-make-a-difference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Regular readers may remember a post I wrote many moons ago in which I described just how exactly &lt;a href=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2012/05/04/change-and-make-a-difference&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Cambridge started&lt;/a&gt; and hopefully gave a lesson in why we should all attempt to grow as much as possible as individuals and embrace (unforeseen) opportunities, as and when they appear. These days I suppose you could describe me as a seasoned presenter (note: seasoning doesn’t necessarily equal good 🙂) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlsaturday.com/228/eventhome.aspx&#34;&gt;SQLSaturday Cambridge&lt;/a&gt; is soon to celebrate its second birthday and outing this coming Friday and Saturday. I know I have only just scratched the surface of what I could become and what I would like to be and that I only have myself and genetic limitations to get in the way of my &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;enlightenment&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Countdown to SQLSaturday Edinburgh</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2013/06/06/countdown-to-sqlsaturday-edinburgh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 10:25:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2013/06/06/countdown-to-sqlsaturday-edinburgh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2013/xeventjonathan2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jonathan Kehayias&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;A pre-conference good enough for Super heros&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In exactly 2 days time the United Kingdom’s 3rd SQLSaturday will be in full swing, showcasing a group of SQL Server MVPs, MCMs and Community experts. This will be the very first time that SQLSaturday has happened in Scotland and it is going to be fantastic to bolster the PASS membership and exposure in that area which can only good news for all concerned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My recent achievements</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2012/12/23/santa-comes-early/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2012 09:31:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2012/12/23/santa-comes-early/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2012/kumar_christmas_smaller.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kumar Christmas&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With days to go before Santa boards his sleigh and pulls back on the reigns tethering his trusty magical flying reindeer to perform what is probably the most incredible feat of logistical planning and execution the world has ever seen, I can look back on the last few months with surprise, satisfaction and appreciation and thank those people who have helped to make my run up to Christmas an extremely rewarding and happy affair.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
