<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Installation on tenbulls blog</title>
    <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/installation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Installation on tenbulls blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © {year} Mark Broadbent</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 14:33:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/installation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Flash in Chrome/ Chromium on Linux</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/01/06/flash-not-working-in-chrome-chromium/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 14:33:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2015/01/06/flash-not-working-in-chrome-chromium/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2015/parliament_not_working.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Flash not working&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Linux works it works well, and when it doesn’t it can be a real pain in the backside. Usually though, the failings are not necessarily the fault of the OS, but more the fault of the way in which packages, snap-ins, extensions and other third party code is deployed. Granted, it doesn’t really help that there are numerous methods and &lt;em&gt;Package Managers&lt;/em&gt; available to install applications, codecs and their ilk, but often the fault lies partially with the Third-party vendors for not making the process as easy and transparent as possible (especially for the less technical savvy amongst us).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using the SQL Server Installation Wizard on Server Core!</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2012/09/19/using-the-sql-server-installation-wizard-on-server-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 18:47:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2012/09/19/using-the-sql-server-installation-wizard-on-server-core/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever heard the phrase &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;just because you can, doesn’t mean you should?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. Yep me too -many times, and what I am about to say comes with that caveat in mind although as I shall explain, I see absolutely no reason why you shouldn’t -certainly not in a development environment OR using this technique to produce a configuration installation file. But I’m getting ahead of myself, first let me describe our scenario.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
