<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scalability on tenbulls blog</title>
    <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/scalability/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scalability on tenbulls blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © {year} Mark Broadbent</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 23:24:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/scalability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using SQL Server Scalable Shared Database</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2011/05/25/sqlrally-scalable-shared-database-demo-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 23:24:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2011/05/25/sqlrally-scalable-shared-database-demo-redux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2011/orders.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Presentation slide&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several weeks ago now I had the honour of presenting at the very first ever SQLRally event in Orlando Florida and I gave a presentation around the very large (no pun intended) subject of scaling out your SQL Server data. At the end of one of my demos it unfortunately crashed and burned and the annoying thing was, that up to then it had worked flawlessly!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem that I hit in the demo was (I believe) related to a virtual machine crash that had happened the previous evening and I don’t think I allowed the database to run through recovery the following day. I am presuming that my iSCSI targets were not connected to my SQL Server on startup which meant that the database in question which was located on my shared drive still needed to run through recovery and couldn’t because I had (as part of the demo) changed the attribute of the drive to read-only in order to prepare it for the next stage. The error was suggesting that there was a version compatibility problem between the two instances and I had several members of the audience suggesting that this was the problem when I knew the versions were identical. Disappointingly, we were so short of time that I needed to move on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
