<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PowerShell on tenbulls blog</title>
    <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/powershell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PowerShell on tenbulls blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © {year} Mark Broadbent</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 17:40:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/powershell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Azure Cloud Shell</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2019/04/25/introduction-to-azure-cloud-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 17:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2019/04/25/introduction-to-azure-cloud-shell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2019/cloudshell.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;On the beach&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my last couple of posts, I have described the remote management of Azure through the command line from what was essentially a fat (or thick) client. This gives you an awful lot of scripting and automation control over the platform by using either the Azure CLI or PowerShell through the PowerShell Az Module. This is perfect for most cases, but what if you are using an unsupported Operating System or you only have access to the browser (perhaps via a thin client)?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AzureRM, Azure CLI and the PowerShell Az Module</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2019/02/01/azurerm-azure-cli-and-the-powershell-az-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 13:18:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2019/02/01/azurerm-azure-cli-and-the-powershell-az-module/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2019/azurecli.png&#34; alt=&#34;Azure CLI&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is now a variety of Microsoft provided command line tools available to connect to (and manage) Azure Resources and the situation is quite confusing to new-comers or those individuals who have not kept up to date with new developments. This post is designed to rectify this situation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is probably also worth me mentioning that I am focusing on the usage and deployment of these tools with Linux in mind, however, the following explanation is also applicable to Windows and macOS environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing Azure CLI on Linux Mint</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2018/12/01/installing-azure-cli-on-linux-mint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 21:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2018/12/01/installing-azure-cli-on-linux-mint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Azure CLI (or Azure Command Line Interface) allows provides an easy way to create and manage your Azure resources on macOS, Linux, and Windows. If you (like me) are using Linux and wish to use and control &lt;a href=&#34;https://portal.azure.com&#34;&gt;Microsoft Azure&lt;/a&gt; easily through the command line, then it is probably something you should have.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wanted to write a very quick post in order to explain the very simple steps you must follow to get the Azure CLI working for you if are using an &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category:Ubuntu_derivatives&#34;&gt;Ubuntu derivative distribution&lt;/a&gt; such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://linuxmint.com/&#34;&gt;Linux Mint&lt;/a&gt;. Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s basic installation guide &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/cli/azure/install-azure-cli-apt?view=azure-cli-latest&#34;&gt;Install Azure CLI with apt&lt;/a&gt; has one specific problem for those distros, so let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the Ubuntu section of that guide:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Custom Job scheduling, Remote queries, and avoiding false negatives using PowerShell and SQL Agent</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2018/10/01/custom-schedule-exceptions-for-sql-jobs-using-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 17:07:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2018/10/01/custom-schedule-exceptions-for-sql-jobs-using-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Say what you want about the SQL Server Agent, it is the lifeblood of SQL Server for scheduling maintenance routines, data loading, and other such ongoing operations. It has been around since the dawn of time and has grown into a rich (but simple) job execution scheduler, yet at the same time, still lacks certain capabilities that mildly annoy me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;scheduling-exclusions&#34;&gt;Scheduling exclusions&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One such annoyance is the inability to create intelligent exclusions for job schedules. In other words the &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t run this job if&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; scenarios that you might commonly run into at retailers, education or health sectors, financial institutions and other environments that may have time-sensitive or complex execution logic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating SQL Agent Jobs through PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2018/08/02/manipulating-sql-agent-jobs-through-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 12:14:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2018/08/02/manipulating-sql-agent-jobs-through-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In our last post titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2018/08/01/loading-and-using-sql-server-management-objects-in-powershell&#34;&gt;Loading and using SQL Server Management Objects in PowerShell&lt;/a&gt;, we demonstrated how to load and consume SQL Server Management Objects in PowerShell, which then allows us to access your SQL instance through an SMO instance object. Please make sure you read that post before continuing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this specific post, we will demonstrate and walk through how to use PSH and SMO to view and change SQL Agent jobs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loading and using SQL Server Management Objects in PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2018/08/01/loading-and-using-sql-server-management-objects-in-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 17:37:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2018/08/01/loading-and-using-sql-server-management-objects-in-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently came across a snippet of code I had written for a client several years ago – one of those &amp;ldquo;by the way, how would you do this&amp;rdquo; type of requests. On the face of it, the task at hand seemed fairly simple to deliver since they wanted to query SQL Server Agent jobs through PowerShell. But because they also wanted to be able to change the SQL Server Agent jobs using PowerShell, I decided that the simplest way would be to programmatically access these jobs as Objects thereby providing &lt;em&gt;Methods&lt;/em&gt; to call and &lt;em&gt;Properties&lt;/em&gt; that can be easily returned or changed through their &lt;em&gt;get&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;set&lt;/em&gt; accessors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading very BIG text files using PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2018/03/14/reading-big-text-files-using-ps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2018/03/14/reading-big-text-files-using-ps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2018/big.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Big&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I frequently have to troubleshoot a variety of data feeds (populated from very very large files) which are regularly ingested into SQL Server for reporting and data validation purposes. From time to time, these feeds break due to malformed or invalid data provided by the third parties, and often due to the size of the files and limitations of third-party text file applications, loading them into a text file viewer is not possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resolving Windows Cluster creation problems in Powershell</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/04/03/problems-creating-windows-cluster-through-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 16:09:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2017/04/03/problems-creating-windows-cluster-through-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating a Windows Cluster is surprisingly easy, but every now and again you run into small problems which irritate and are not really helped by the error messages – a problem which is exacerbated by the do all in one go power of PowerShell.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One such problem is when you use the New-Cluster command to add all your nodes in one go.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34; data-lang=&#34;powershell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;New-Cluster -Name magrathea -node server5,server6,server7&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;-staticaddress &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;192.168&lt;/span&gt;.1.70&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simple right? Well no. In this instance I ran into the following error:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
