<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on tenbulls blog</title>
    <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on tenbulls blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © {year} Mark Broadbent</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 18:51:32 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Restart of blog</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2025/04/06/blog-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 18:51:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2025/04/06/blog-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2025/restart-plane-ai-600.png&#34; alt=&#34;Restarting&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve finally made the shift to my new statically generated blog and am slowly migrating the content over. This operation is probably going to take me quite some time since I will need to go all the way back to 2009 and decide what posts and content I want to come across. There is possibly over a hundred posts (or more) to bring across! I&amp;rsquo;ll also be quite keen on bringing over some of my more useful resources (although they may need a huge revamp/ update) such as my Ultimate Resources Training Page and others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Future Changes</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2025/02/01/future-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 20:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2025/02/01/future-changes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a quick note to give an update on the future changes for this blog. Many long time readers out there might realise that what you are reading today no longer exists under its original domain and currently lives under its default WordPress domain namespace. Given that this blog has existed since 2009 and been linked to from a variety of popular sources and published materials, this is a big shift.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automating Pause of Synapse Dedicated Pool Part I</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2023/06/18/automating-pause-of-synapse-dedicated-pool-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 20:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2023/06/18/automating-pause-of-synapse-dedicated-pool-part-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Synapse Analytics is an enterprise analytics engine that offers multiple (compute) Pool types that you can use for varying data processing and analytics requirements. Each Pool type has a slightly different cost model based upon its architecture, capabilities, and consumption patterns, but if we over simplify things, we can break these cost considerations down to compute costs and (in some cases) storage costs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest benefits with modern data lakehouse architectures is that with the separation of compute and storage comes the ability to reduce costs when compute is not needed, and most importantly, not running.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Is My Azure Solution Running Slow</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2023/01/31/why-is-my-azure-solution-running-slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 15:36:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2023/01/31/why-is-my-azure-solution-running-slow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an Azure data professional, one of the most common questions you are most likely to hear from users is “why do cloud solutions often appear to have performance issues post-deployment“. This perception is particularly common for Azure migration projects moving on-premises into the cloud, but do these observations really match reality or are they misguided?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this introductory article, we will take a look into some of the reasons why Azure cloud-based solutions are often seen to be problematic, or in some cases, are problematic, and provide some ideas to avoid these negative perceptions in your cloud environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encouraging Diversity in Leadership Roles</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2022/09/01/encouraging-diversity-in-leadership-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 21:19:27 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2022/09/01/encouraging-diversity-in-leadership-roles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over 33 years ago I started my journey working in Information Technology (I.T.), and it is probably fair to say that I have worked my way slowly up from the absolute bottom of the pile to the modest heights of today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-problem-with-it&#34;&gt;The problem with I.T.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I look back over the years I cannot help but feel a sense of disappointment that during my long and arduous journey to the “top” I never really found someone of seniority (or power) who went out of their way to selflessly help me climb the greasy ladder of success in any of the organisations I worked at. I don’t think my experiences are particularly unique either.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Introduction to Azure Purview</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2022/07/29/a-quick-introduction-to-azure-purview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 07:15:27 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2022/07/29/a-quick-introduction-to-azure-purview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2022/catalogue-of-data-ai-600.png&#34; alt=&#34;Data Catalog&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Azure Purview is Microsoft’s next-generation data catalog service in Azure which is a direct replacement for the first-generation service known as Azure Data Catalog. While some people refer to Purview as Azure Data Catalog v2, It is important to note that Purview is more of a re-write of Azure Data Catalog rather than an upgrade, and as such, no migration path between both services currently exists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Azure Purview can be used to inventory, classify, map, and govern your on-premises, multi-cloud, and SaaS data estate, providing a holistic up-to-date map of your data with automatic data discovery, data classification, and end-to-end data lineage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSIS Data Flow Performance Tuning</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2020/08/11/ssis-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 15:18:01 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2020/08/11/ssis-performance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yes before you say it, I know SQL Server Integration Services is “old technology” but a lot of people are still using it, and in many cases are either still developing against it, or are looking to integrate/ migrate with other burgeoning technologies such as Azure Data Factory. In other words, if you are not currently using SSIS then this post is probably not for you -otherwise read on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are still one of the lucky ones to still be using SSIS, I thought it would be worth publishing these comprehensive notes taken from a session titled “SSIS Data Flow Performance Tuning” delivered at SQLBits 8 (Brighton) by the then “SSIS guru” Jamie Thomson. Notes have timings (in mins and seconds) against them, which correlate directly with the presentation times. The video is still available and can be downloaded from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sqlbits.com/Sessions/Event8/SSIS_Dataflow_Performance_tuning&#34;&gt;SQLBits website&lt;/a&gt; so you can watch it (if required) and use the timings to follow along.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Querying Azure Vm State With Powershell</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2020/05/12/querying-azure-vm-state-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 15:16:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2020/05/12/querying-azure-vm-state-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently given the task of identifying the state of an Azure VM so that an automation script using the &lt;code&gt;az vm run-command invoke&lt;/code&gt; would not fail if the VM was down or under a reboot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I initially thought the task would be really easy and a simple query of the VM state using &lt;code&gt;Get-AzVM&lt;/code&gt; would provide us with a running state property of the VM, but as it happens the state is a little abstracted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Removing and Maintaining Azure Resource Group Deployments Based Upon Deployment Count</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2020/05/06/removing-and-maintaining-azure-resource-group-deployments-based-upon-deployment-count/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 11:37:47 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2020/05/06/removing-and-maintaining-azure-resource-group-deployments-based-upon-deployment-count/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whenever you create or update an Azure resource, a new &lt;em&gt;deployment&lt;/em&gt; is created under the resources’ configured resource group. This deployment history is retained ad-infinitum until you eventually hit the hard limit of &lt;em&gt;800 deployments (per resource group)&lt;/em&gt;. You may think this figure is more than enough to accommodate all the possible resource changes that could ever be made in a resource group, but if you are running CICD pipelines to push out your Infrastructure as Code (IaC) (or create lots of resources per resource group) then it is very likely you will exhaust this figure very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inconsistent result sets and another case against pessimistic isolation</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2020/04/27/inconsistent-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 12:05:21 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2020/04/27/inconsistent-results/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a big fan of demonstrating when transaction processing goes bad in Database Management Systems because it is a reminder to us all to ensure that we know exactly what we are doing when we write our code. Not only should you test and execute your code multiple times in serial (for instance running in sequence in isolation), but you should also execute in parallel with itself or other potentially dependent transactions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Restore Azure Devops Repository</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2020/04/14/restore-azure-devops-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 12:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2020/04/14/restore-azure-devops-repository/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are using &lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com/en-gb/services/devops/&#34;&gt;Azure DevOps&lt;/a&gt;, you might be comforted that your &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; repo is “in the Cloud” and automatically has availability and disaster guarantees. However you (or someone else) still have the ability to accidentally (or maliciously) delete repos from Azure DevOps Repos. Surprisingly, at the time of writing, there is no GUI based option to restore your repo. This might initially instill a sense of panic as you frantically search for the latest local clone to replace your remote – but there is a better way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cannot delete old build definitions in Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2020/03/25/delete-old-build-definitions-in-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 19:34:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2020/03/25/delete-old-build-definitions-in-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been experiencing a problem for quite a while now in my current environment, in that some of our old builds cannot be deleted. When you attempt to do so it results in the following error:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2020/cannotdel.webp&#34; alt=&#34;build error&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One or more builds associated with the requested pipeline(s) are retained by a release. The pipeline(s) and builds will not be deleted.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many of our pipelines have undergone a lot of change over time to the degree it is not even obvious anymore why (or indeed where) these builds are being prevented from being dropped. The only thing that is clear is that until they can be, the old build definitions will remain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Querying Azure Devops Rest Api With Powershell</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2020/03/11/querying-azure-devops-rest-api-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 13:13:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2020/03/11/querying-azure-devops-rest-api-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2020/saddog.png&#34; alt=&#34;sad dog&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In previous posts we have talked about trying to use and consume Azure DevOps using PowerShell and utilizing the Azure CLI. In particular, my post titled Use &lt;a href=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2020/02/17/use-powershell-to-consume-your-azure-cli-devops-result-set.md&#34;&gt;PowerShell to consume your Azure CLI DevOps result&lt;/a&gt; set painted a rather frustrating picture when trying to manipulate the tabular dataset from the Azure CLI. Furthermore, our functionality is restricted to only those commands implemented by the Azure CLI Azure DevOps add-in -as will become increasingly obvious, this is limited to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
