<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Funny on tenbulls blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/funny/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Funny on tenbulls blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © {year} Mark Broadbent</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 12:44:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/funny/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to run SQL Server 2012 on the Kindle Fire HD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013/04/01/how-to-run-sql-server-2012-on-the-kindle-fire-hd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 12:44:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2013/04/01/how-to-run-sql-server-2012-on-the-kindle-fire-hd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;Warning! Please do not attempt to perform any of the following steps on production systems. This information is provided purely for reference and any attempt to replicate these actions on your own hardware will be purely at your own risk!&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest benefits to the latest release of SQL Server (and reasons to upgrade) is that Windows Server Core is now a supported option. For those of you who are not yet familiar with Server Core, it could be best described as a reduced GUI version of Microsoft Windows. In other words, if you like the command line then you are in for a very big treat! Regular visitors to these pages will most likely be very aware of my passion for Windows Server Core and more to the point running SQL Server on it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to run SQL Server on Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/01/how-to-run-sql-server-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 14:51:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/01/how-to-run-sql-server-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE 2011-04-10: PLEASE NOTE THIS WAS AN APRILS FOOL JOKE 🙂&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well I have finally cracked it, after years of trying (and a little help from the R2 release) to get SQL Server to install and run happily on the Linux Platform. I could hardly believe it when it all came together, but I&amp;rsquo;m very pleased that it has. What is even more exciting is that the performance of the SQL Engine is going through the roof.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
