<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Public Speaking on tenbulls blog</title>
    <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/public-speaking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Public Speaking on tenbulls blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © {year} Mark Broadbent</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 18:43:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tenbulls.co.uk/tags/public-speaking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The real value of attending SQLRally</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2011/05/18/the-real-value-of-attending-sqlrally/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 18:43:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2011/05/18/the-real-value-of-attending-sqlrally/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(This post was written primarily whilst travelling back from SQLRally and subsequently edited, amended and added to where necessary before publishing)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m currently sat here at Orlando Airport and I am able to reflect a little bit whilst waiting to board my plane back to the U.K. after having spent the last 5 days of preparation, learning and socialising at SQLRally and I need to ask myself &lt;em&gt;was it worth the expense?&lt;/em&gt;. I’m not too sure how many attendees or indeed speakers were from Europe but I am pretty sure I was one of a very small number and therefore the cost to myself was indeed far more than it would have cost for the majority of the attendees. It is therefore important that I look at the return on investment of not just my attending the event, but also of me speaking. One key thing to remember about going to conferences, is that the knowledge &lt;em&gt;retained&lt;/em&gt; is usually very little of what you have actually heard but hopefully with the efforts of the presenters, the materials provided will help to reinforce the important parts of this knowledge. It is true that I went to some excellent presentations but was sadly unable to attend many of them due to the amount of work I felt I needed to do on the preparation of my own session since I was really not quite happy where I was at. This particular point is a key take home for me, and I &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; now ensure that I am far more prepared going forward. Unfortunately due to working commitments, family and other events it is sometimes easier said than done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQLBits 8 - a presenters review</title>
      <link>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2011/04/20/sqlbits-8-finis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 15:42:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tenbulls.co.uk/posts/2011/04/20/sqlbits-8-finis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly two weeks has passed after another SQLBits and what another fabulous event. After an incredibly early morning train journey down to Brighton for the excellent Thursday training session with Thomas Kejser and an enjoyable time presenting my &lt;em&gt;SQL Server Clustering for Dummies&lt;/em&gt; session I am well and truly back down to earth with a thump.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Personal highs for me were :-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally getting to meet Allan Hirt and not only that but I had a Geo-Cluster debate with him in the speaker room.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meeting a few of the new first time SQLBits speakers -in particular Atul Thakor (blog|twitter) who I had a very long chat with in the speaker room and on the morning before his presentation. He had run into lots of problems with his laptop and demos prior to his session -which can strike the best of us, but managed to keep his wits about him an plow onto success when he finally came to present. What a top guy, and look forward to meeting him again in a User Group or another conference.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Recognizing some audience members in my Clustering for Dummies session from my SQLBits 7 session. I ran into a couple of them later on and said a big thanks for the support, gave them my personal email and very much hope they do drop me a mail sometime to say hello.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bumping into some old faces…people I’ve met in Seattle, previous UK conferences and User Groups and old colleagues. A special big-up to Judith Kinsella who made the effort to come to my presentation (which threw me when I saw her in the audience), although she keeps telling me that I remind her of John Peel and just can’t take me seriously 🙂🙂🙂&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Being able to enjoy the experience a little more, due to familiarity of proceedings. Anyone who presents at a major conference for the first time will tell you that it is all a bit of a daze, stressful and is a big unknown what you have let yourself in for. This time I knew what to expect, what I was doing and what I needed to do.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Seeing some great presentations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Excellent weather!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tenbulls.co.uk/images/2011/introduction.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mark Broadbent Introduction&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;In full flow!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
